A lot of people are looking for passive
很多人都在寻找被动收入
income from side hustles. Yeah, it's the
副业收入。是的，就是那个
financial ompic and it's more accessible
金融视野开阔，而且更容易获取
than ever. Like 90% of the ideas I talk
比以往任何时候都更甚。就像我谈论的90%的想法一样
about can be launched with $500 or less.
大约只需 500 美元或更少即可启动。
And there's [music] enough time in the
而且音乐部分也有足够的时间
day to do these on the nights and
白天在晚上做这些事，
weekends. So in these three suitcases in
周末。所以，在这三个行李箱里……
front of me, I have three different
我面前有三种不同的
amounts of money. And during this
金额。在此期间
conversation, I'm going to pass you a
谈话中，我将把一个
box at random. And your job is to tell
随机选择一个盒子。而你的工作就是告诉
me what kind of business you would start
你会创办什么样的企业？
with that amount of money. Sounds good.
有了那笔钱。听起来不错。
Let's do this. Known as the king of side
我们开始吧。被称为边路之王
hustles, Chris Kerner has launched over
克里斯·克纳已经发起了一系列活动。
80 businesses, earning millions in the
80家企业，盈利数百万美元
process. [music]
过程。 [音乐]
And now, the serial entrepreneur is
而现在，这位连续创业者是
going to teach us how to adopt a
将会教我们如何收养
business mindset
商业思维
&gt;&gt; and launch simple, overlooked, but
启动简单，容易被忽视，但却
profitable ventures with little money.
用少量资金实现盈利的投资项目。
&gt;&gt; Many of us struggle financially and they
我们许多人都面临经济困难，而且
see a side hustle as a solution to that.
把兼职看作是解决这个问题的办法。
Like for me, growing up kind of poor,
比如我，从小家境比较贫寒，
business allowed me to take hold of my
商业让我能够掌控自己的命运
life and make it what I wanted it to be.
生活，并把它变成我想要的样子。
And it started when I was 9 years old
这一切始于我9岁那年。
and wanting a Red Schwin bicycle. My
想要一辆红色的施文牌自行车。我的
friends had a bicycle. My neighbors had
朋友们有一辆自行车。我的邻居们曾
a bicycle and my parents didn't have
一辆自行车，而我的父母没有。
money for it. But I lived across the
花钱买它。但我住在对面
street from a golf course and these golf
一条通往高尔夫球场的街道，以及这些高尔夫球场
balls would fly in my yard and I would
球会飞进我的院子里，我会
go to my neighbor's yard and go across
去邻居家的院子，然后穿过
the street, dig through the ditches and
沿着街道，挖开沟渠，
I'd pull out all these golf balls and I
我会把这些高尔夫球都拿出来，然后我
started selling them. That was my first
开始出售它们。那是我的第一次
business. That taught me that business
商业。那件事教会了我商业之道。
is approachable and we all have ideas,
平易近人，我们每个人都有自己的想法，
but we usually don't do anything about
但我们通常不会采取任何行动。
it. Why? I think number one, they're
它。为什么？我认为第一点是，他们是
afraid of what people think. Number two
害怕别人怎么想。第二
is they don't have the tools or they're
要么他们没有工具，要么他们是
not connecting the tools with the ideas.
没有将工具与想法联系起来。
If we can get over those, the world is
如果我们能克服这些困难，世界将会……
our oyster at that point. I have $1,000.
那时我们就像牡蛎一样。我有1000美元。
What side hustle would you start?
你会选择做什么副业？
&gt;&gt; The first thing that comes to mind is my
我首先想到的是我的
favorite business idea of all right now.
目前我最喜欢的商业想法。
This is a zero employee business. It's
这是一家零员工企业。它是
highly profitable and that would be so
利润丰厚，而且会非常有利可图。
how important is it for you to love the
对你来说，热爱有多重要？
thing to be successful at it? Ignore
要想成功，需要具备哪些条件？忽略
passion. [music]
热情。 [音乐]
Follow the profit until you can afford
追逐利润，直到你有能力为止。
to follow your passion. Do they need a
追随你的热情。他们需要什么？
business partner? No. If you look at the
商业伙伴？不。如果你看一下……
stats on business failure rates with
关于企业倒闭率的统计数据
companies that have co-founders, it's
拥有联合创始人的公司，就是这样。
significantly higher than companies that
远高于那些公司
have solo founders. And how does someone
由单人创始人创立。一个人怎么会……
validate a business idea? If I had to
验证商业想法是否可行？如果我必须这样做的话
pick one tool, it's one that one in four
选一种工具，四分之一的人会用到它。
humans use every day.
人类每天都在使用。
That's everything you need right there.
这就是你需要的所有东西了。
I see messages all the time in the
我经常在……中看到消息
comments section that some of you didn't
评论区里有些人没看到。
realize you didn't subscribe. So, if you
意识到你没有订阅。所以，如果你
could do me a favor and double check if
能不能帮我个忙，再确认一下？
you're a subscriber to this channel,
您是本频道的订阅者，
that would be tremendously appreciated.
非常感谢。
It's the simple, it's the free thing
它很简单，而且是免费的。
that anybody that watches this show
任何观看这档节目的人
frequently can do to help us here to
通常情况下，他们可以在这里帮助我们。
keep everything going in this show in
让这个节目继续下去
the trajectory it's on. So, please do
它所处的轨迹。所以，请务必这样做。
double check if you've subscribed and uh
请再次确认您是否已订阅，呃……
thank you so much because in a strange
非常感谢，因为在一个奇怪的
way you are you're part of our history
你就是历史的一部分
and you're on this journey with us and I
你和我们一起踏上这段旅程，我
appreciate you for that. So, yeah, thank
谢谢你。是的，谢谢
you. [music]
你。 [音乐]
[music]
[音乐]
Chris,
克里斯，
&gt;&gt; who are you and what is the mission that
你是谁？你的使命是什么？
you're [clears throat] on?
你准备好了吗？（清嗓子）
&gt;&gt; I am a father. I am a husband and I'm a
我是一位父亲。我是一位丈夫，我是一个
serial entrepreneur and I love talking
连续创业者，我喜欢聊天
about business and starting businesses
关于商业和创业
and inspiring other people to do the
并激励其他人这样做
same.
相同的。
&gt;&gt; Why business has given me everything.
为什么商业给了我一切。
Um, growing up kind of poor, it was my
嗯，我从小家境比较穷，那是我的
outlet. It was my way of just kind of
出路。那是我表达方式的一种方式。
taking hold of my life and making it
掌控我的人生并让它成为现实
what I wanted it to be. And I have
正是我想要的样子。而且我还有
immense gratitude for that. Um, and I
对此我万分感激。嗯，还有我
love I just love talking about it. I
我就是喜欢谈论爱情。我
it's the only thing I know you I can't
这是我唯一知道你不能做的事
talk to you about history or nutrition
跟你聊聊历史或营养
or anything, but when it comes to
或者其他任何事情，但说到
business, I just love it and I want
我热爱商业，我渴望从事它。
other people to love it as well. How
其他人也会喜欢它。如何
have you made your name in the world of
你是否在世界上闯出了名堂？
business? Because I've heard your name a
商业？因为我听过你的名字
lot recently. People call you the king
最近很多。人们称你为国王
of side hustles.
副业。
Where has this come from? I think I just
这是从哪里来的？我觉得我只是
published my life on the internet now.
现在我把自己的生活公开到网上了。
Um, I I'm always testing and launching
嗯，我一直在测试和发布。
and starting businesses, but only over
以及创办企业，但仅限于……
the last couple years have I started
过去几年我开始
publishing that. And
发布该内容。和
I didn't try to be like the king of side
我并没有试图成为边路之王。
hustles. That's not something that I've
忙碌。这不是我曾经做过的事。
ever like intentionally tried to brand
曾经有意尝试打造品牌
myself as, but I think people see what I
我自己是这样的人，但我认为人们看到的是我
do as a side hustle and they call it
把它当作副业来做，他们称之为
that. But I think that anything is
那。但我认为任何事都是
scalable. Any side hustle could could be
可扩展的。任何副业都可能……
a multi-million dollar business. Um, I
一家价值数百万美元的企业。嗯，我
mean, we we live on a planet with eight
也就是说，我们生活在一个拥有八个……的星球上。
billion people and we're all connected
数十亿人口，我们彼此相连。
and anything can be scaled.
任何事物都可以规模化。
&gt;&gt; And you make a lot of content now, so
而且你现在制作了很多内容，所以
you've probably had a bit of a feedback
你可能已经收到了一些反馈
loop in terms of understanding what it
循环，就理解它而言
is that you say and do and create that's
就是你说的、做的、创造的。
resonant with people and also why it's
它能引起人们的共鸣，以及它为何如此受欢迎。
resonant like what is the crux of what
共鸣就像……的关键是什么？
people like my audiences are are looking
像我的观众这样的人正在寻找
for. As humans, we all want a silver
为了。作为人类，我们都想要一枚银牌
bullet. We want a solution to our
子弹。我们想要一个解决方案来解决这个问题
problems and many of us struggle
问题，我们许多人都在努力应对。
financially um and they see a side
在经济方面，他们看到了这一点。
hustle as as an outlet to that or as a
努力奋斗，既是摆脱困境的途径，也是……
solution to that. I think everyone has
解决办法。我认为每个人都有
ideas. um most people are very hesitant
想法。嗯，大多数人都很犹豫。
to execute on those ideas. And so when
将这些想法付诸实践。所以当
they see someone like me freely
他们看到像我这样的人会自由自在地出现。
executing on all the ideas, it hopefully
如果能将所有想法付诸实践，希望一切顺利。
it opens their mind and helps them look
这能开拓他们的视野，帮助他们看待事物。
at their ideas in a different way or a
以不同的方式或某种方式表达他们的想法
more approachable way and maybe gives
更平易近人的方式，或许还能带来
them confidence to do the same. In the
他们也因此获得了同样的信心。在
boxes in front of me here, I have three
我面前的这些箱子里，有三个
different amounts of money. $500, I
不同金额的钱。 500美元，我
think I have $1,000, and $5,000. And
我想我手头有1000美元和5000美元。和
during this conversation, I'm going to
在这次谈话中，我将……
pass you a box at random. And your job
随机递给你一个盒子。以及你的工作
is to tell me what kind of business you
就是告诉我你经营的是什么类型的企业。
would start with that amount of money
会从那笔钱开始。
because I know my audience, you know,
因为我了解我的听众，你知道的。
they're many of them are interested in
他们中的许多人对……感兴趣
starting their own business one day. And
有朝一日，他们会创办自己的企业。和
I use specifically sort of low amounts
我特意使用少量。
of money just to make it as accessible
投入资金只是为了让它更容易获得。
to them as possible. So, we will do that
尽可能地帮助他们。所以，我们会这么做。
at some point. I'll pass you the boxes.
在某个时候。我把箱子递给你。
You give me three business ideas. You'll
你给我三个商业点子。你会
start with $500, $1,000, and $5,000. Um,
先从 500 美元、1000 美元和 5000 美元开始。嗯，
but I want to get a view on on you and
但我很想了解你，
the businesses that you've started and
你创办的企业和
the sort of the variety of success
成功类型及种类
you've had. So, can you give me an
你已经有了。所以，你能给我一个
overview?
概述？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, I was 9 years old living in
是的。所以，我9岁那年住在……
Utah and I lived across the street from
我和犹他州住在街对面
a golf course and these golf balls would
一个高尔夫球场和这些高尔夫球
fly in my yard and I don't know what
一只苍蝇飞进了我的院子，我不知道它是什么。
gave me the idea, but I started selling
他给了我这个想法，但我开始卖东西。
them. Um, I just wanted money for a
他们。嗯，我只是想要点钱。
bike. I wanted this Schwin bicycle and
自行车。我想要这辆施文牌自行车，
it was red and my friends had a bicycle,
它是红色的，我的朋友们有一辆自行车。
my neighbors had a bicycle and my
我的邻居有一辆自行车，而我的
parents didn't have money for it. And so
父母没钱买。所以
for whatever reason, I connected that
不知何故，我把那件事联系起来了。
white golf ball in my grass with money.
草地上有一个白色高尔夫球，里面有钱。
And I would go to my neighbor's yards,
我会去邻居家的院子里逛逛，
I'd go across the street, I'd dig
我会走到街对面，我会挖
through the ditches, and I'd pull out
穿过沟渠，然后我会把它拉出来
all these golf balls. I'd wash them. And
所有这些高尔夫球。我会把它们洗干净。和
then I put up this huge piece of plywood
然后我竖起了这块巨大的胶合板
in front of my house that said golf
我家门前写着“高尔夫”
balls three for a dollar. And that was
三个球一美元。事情就是这样。
my first business. And at the time, it
我的第一家公司。当时，它
was just normal. It was natural. Uh I
一切都很正常。这是自然而然的。呃，我
didn't know any different. And now I
我以前根本不知道还有其他选择。现在我
have a 9-year-old, and I was nine when I
我有一个9岁的孩子，而我9岁的时候……
did that. And we live on a busy road
做到了。我们住在一条繁忙的道路上
today. I lived on a busy road then. And
今天。我当时住在一条繁忙的道路旁。和
the thought of him like negotiating,
想到他喜欢谈判，
haggling with grown-ups wearing polo
与穿着polo衫的成年人讨价还价
shirts on our doorstep is unfathomable.
家门口就摆着衬衫，这简直难以置信。
But that's what I was doing. And that
但我当时就是这么做的。而那
planted the seed that kind of taught me
在我心中种下了这颗种子，它教会了我很多东西。
that business is approachable. Um,
这家公司很容易沟通。嗯，
preferably it's approachable.
最好是平易近人的。
Approachable and scalable can be the
易于上手且可扩展
same thing. They don't have to be at
同一件事。他们不必在场
odds with one another. So, and how many
彼此赔率相反。那么，有多少个？
businesses have you started since then?
从那以后你创办了哪些企业？
&gt;&gt; I lose count. I have a spreadsheet. Um,
我都数不清了。我有一个电子表格。嗯，
but it's at least 80.
但至少有 80。
And what's the what have the outcomes
那么结果又是什么呢？
been? How much money have you made? What
到过？你赚了多少钱？什么
kind of how has that changed your life?
这究竟如何改变了你的生活？
What freedom has that given you?
那给你带来了哪些自由？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, cumulatively uh all of the
是的。所以，总的来说，所有这些
businesses have generated low hundreds
企业已创造了数百美元的低收入。
of millions of revenue. Um low tens of
数百万美元的收入。嗯，几十个低
millions of profit. Um but on a real
数百万的利润。嗯，但实际上
number basis,
数字基础，
the majority of them have been abandoned
其中大部分已被废弃。
or fizzled out or failed or there was
或者不了了之，或者失败了，或者存在
too much opportunity cost so I pivoted
机会成本太高，所以我改变了策略。
to something else. Um, it's just a
变成别的东西。嗯，这只是一个
numbers game.
数字游戏。
&gt;&gt; And how has that changed your life? What
这给你的生活带来了哪些改变？什么
does your lifestyle look like?
你的生活方式是怎样的？
&gt;&gt; My life is awesome. Um, we built our
我的生活太棒了。嗯，我们建立了我们的
dream house in our 20s. Uh, we had all
二十多岁时的梦想之家。呃，我们都有
four of our kids in our 20s. We travel a
我们四个孩子都二十多岁了。我们旅行
lot. Uh, we're I've been married for 17
很多。呃，我结婚17年了。
years. We're a very close family. We
年。我们一家人关系非常亲密。我们
take a lot of trips. Um, we live in a
多出去旅行。嗯，我们生活在一个
good school district, but my kids go to
学区不错，但我的孩子上……
public school and, um, we have
公立学校，嗯，我们有
everything we need and more, and we're
我们所需的一切，甚至更多，我们
very grateful for that.
非常感谢。
What is the overt sort of underpinning
显性的潜在支撑是什么？
mentality that's required for someone to
一个人必须具备的心态
be successful at starting businesses in
在创业方面取得成功
the way that you started them? Starting
你当初开始做这些事的方式？开始
these side hustles at volume and seeing
这些副业的规模和表现都令人瞩目。
success. Is there like a foundational
成功。是否存在某种基础性的
mentality or personality or character
心态、性格或气质
trait required before we get into the
进入正题之前需要具备的特质
tactics? Yeah, the
策略？是的，
I should say that the the pain of your
我应该说，你的痛苦
problem needs to be greater than how
问题需要比“如何”更大。
much you care about what people think
你有多在意别人的看法？
about you. It needs to get to that point
关于你。它需要达到那个阶段。
because by far that is the biggest
因为那是迄今为止最大的。
roadblock to success is people caring
成功路上的障碍是人们的关心。
too much about what people think about
太在意别人怎么想了
them. And so they don't want to do the
他们。所以他们不想做这件事
thing or they don't want to talk about
或者他们不想谈论这件事。
doing the thing because some random
做这件事是因为一些随机因素
person from high school follows them on
高中时有人关注了他们
Facebook and might comment something,
Facebook，可能会发表一些评论，
right? Which is really silly, but I I've
正确的？这真的很傻，但我
been there. I get it. Right? If we can
去过。我得到它。正确的？如果我们能
get over that, if we can just flip the
克服这一点，如果我们能扭转局面……
switch in our brain that says people are
我们大脑中有一个开关，它告诉我们人们是
thinking about me, people are caring
有人在想我，他们很关心我
about me and just switch that to off.
关于我，把它关掉就行了。
Right? Because the world is our oyster
正确的？因为世界是我们的舞台。
at that point. And in terms of where we
那时。至于我们身处何地
sit at this moment of time with
此时此刻，请与……一起静坐
technology, with AI, with in fast
技术，结合人工智能，快速发展
internet, with mobile phones, do you
互联网，加上手机，你……
think this is the best time for people
我认为这是人们最好的时机。
to start something to to start a side
开始做某事，开始一个方面
hustle or to try? Every day that goes
努力奋斗还是尝试一下？每一天都是如此
by, the timing gets better for people,
到那时，人们的时机就更好了。
right? Things are getting more
正确的？事情变得越来越
competitive, but there are more tools
很有竞争力，但工具更多。
than ever. Um, 10 years ago, if I wanted
比以往任何时候都更甚。嗯，十年前，如果我想要
to start a business, and this is like
创业，这就好比……
the internet's in full swing, social
互联网正蓬勃发展，社交
media is in full swing, I probably had
媒体报道铺天盖地，我可能也参与其中了。
to spend a lot of money or move to San
花很多钱或者搬到圣安东尼奥
Francisco or raise venture capital.
旧金山或筹集风险投资。
That's like I I would love for you to
就像我希望你那样
try to convince me. Try to give me an
试着说服我。试着给我一个
idea where you have to raise money or
你需要筹集资金的想法
where you have to go allin or where you
你必须全力以赴的地方，或者你
you have to quit your job. It doesn't
你必须辞职。它不
exist. With all these AI tools, software
存在。有了所有这些人工智能工具，软件
tools, you can make a website with one
工具，你可以用其中一个工具创建一个网站。
prompt. You can make an app with one
迅速的。你可以用一个来制作应用程序。
prompt. You could post to Facebook
迅速的。你可以发帖到 Facebook
Marketplace and have hundreds of
市场，拥有数百个
inquiries within an hour. You could post
一小时内回复查询。你可以发帖
Facebook ads. You could go to
Facebook广告。你可以去
Craigslist. Like, you could put a sign
Craigslist。比如，你可以放个牌子
up in front of your house. You could go
就在你家门前。你可以去
launch a survey to people. Like, there
发起一项针对民众的调查。比如，那里
are so many tools for testing and
有很多测试工具和
validating and experimenting with these
验证和试验这些
concepts that it is more accessible than
比起其他概念，它更容易理解。
ever. Why don't people?
曾经。为什么人们不这样做？
I think number one is they're afraid of
我认为第一点是他们害怕……
what people think. Number two is they
人们的想法。第二点是他们
don't have the tools or at least they're
没有工具，或者至少他们没有
not connecting the tools with the ideas,
没有将工具与想法联系起来，
right? They'll use Facebook Marketplace
正确的？他们会使用 Facebook Marketplace
to sell a sectional, but then they won't
想卖掉一套组合沙发，但他们却不卖。
think to use it when validating their
在验证他们的信息时，可以考虑使用它。
woodworking idea, right? They're just
这是个木工创意，对吧？他们只是
not connecting the dots. There's too
没能把这些点联系起来。太多了
many tools in a sense, so we don't know
从某种意义上说，有很多工具，所以我们并不清楚。
how to tie them all together. Um,
如何将它们联系起来。嗯，
they also probably don't know
他们可能也不知道
like how much the law of abundance is a
比如丰盛法则究竟有多重要
real thing, right? People think business
是真的，对吧？人们思考商业
is a zero sum game. What does that mean?
这是一个零和博弈。这意味着什么？
&gt;&gt; Well, they think that things are
他们认为事情是
oversaturated. They'll have an idea for
饱和度过高。他们会有一个想法
a product or a service and then they'll
提供产品或服务，然后他们就会
get really excited and then they'll go
他们会非常兴奋，然后就会走
Google it and then we'll see it exists
谷歌一下，你就会发现它确实存在。
and they'll move on. And when I do that
他们会继续前进。当我这样做的时候
and I see it exists, I'm like, "Yes,
当我看到它存在时，我就想，“是的，
this is it. Someone someone went to the
就是这样。有人去了
front lines of the battlefield and
战场前线和
validated this for me." And then I'll go
这对我来说是证实了这一点。”然后我就走了
to the web archive. I'll go to who is
上传至网络存档。我要去见谁
and I'll go look at what their website
我去看看他们的网站。
has looked like over the last decade.
过去十年间，情况一直如此。
See where they started. Maybe their
看看他们从哪里起步。或许他们的
product was $99. Now it's like 49 every
该产品售价99美元。现在大概是每49人
2 months. Interesting. Okay. I'll look
2个月。有趣的。好的。我看看
at the the copy of their headline. I'll
在他们的标题副本上。患病的
look at like how many tabs they have on
看看他们有多少标签页
their website. Do they post their
他们的网站。他们会发布他们的
Instagram feed on? I'll look at all
Instagram 信息流已开启？我会查看所有
these things and see how it's evolved
看看这些东西是如何演变的
over time and think awesome. I'm going
随着时间的推移，你会觉得很棒。我要去
to start where he's at today. like this
从他现在所处的位置开始说起。像这样
guy already proved it out for me. He
他已经向我证明了这一点。他
took all the risk. This is amazing. This
承担了所有风险。这太棒了。这
exists. I don't need to like do it
存在。我不需要那样做
better. I don't need to do it
更好的。我不需要这样做。
differently. I just need to do the same
不一样。我也需要这样做。
thing. Um and the market is big enough,
事物。嗯，而且市场足够大。
the world is big enough to where I can
世界如此之大，以至于我可以
win as well.
也赢了。
&gt;&gt; You said um web archive. What role does
你说的是网络存档。它扮演什么角色？
web archive play? What is that for
网络存档播放？那是什么？
anyone that isn't familiar? And how do
还有谁不熟悉吗？以及如何……
you use that?
你用那个吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's just a tool that shows
是的，它只是一个显示工具。
snapshots uh over time of what a website
随着时间的推移，网站的快照
looks like, right? So, it's a great way
看起来是这样，对吧？所以，这真是一个好方法
of kind of reverse engineering what
某种逆向工程
businesses have done to be successful.
企业为了成功所采取的措施。
And then there's another tool called
然后还有另一个工具叫做
Similar Web where you can see what their
类似网站，您可以在那里看到他们的
traffic has been over time. And you can
交通状况一直很紧张。而且你可以
kind of overlay the two and you can say,
将两者叠加起来，就可以说：
"Oh, interesting. When they when they
“哦，有意思。当他们当他们
redesigned their website to be more
他们重新设计了网站，使其更加
mobile friendly, their traffic went from
移动友好型，他们的流量从
3,000 a month to 4500 a month.
每月 3000 至 4500。
Interesting. I'm just going to make it
有趣的。我一定要做到。
mobile friendly from day one." Right? So
从第一天起就支持移动设备。”对吧？
we are at a great advantage when we
当我们……时，我们就拥有巨大的优势。
start where our competitors or our
从我们的竞争对手或我们开始
future competitors already are instead
未来的竞争对手现在就已经存在了。
of starting where we think we need to be
从我们认为应该去的地方开始
starting like trying to be different or
一开始就像试图与众不同一样
innovative or unique. In my experience,
创新或独特。以我的经验来看，
that's more of like a signal of our
这更像是我们发出的一个信号。
pride or our ego. We feel kind of like
骄傲或自负。我们感觉有点像
weird or odd or even dirty or unethical
怪异的、奇特的，甚至是肮脏的或不道德的
if we're just like copying and pasting a
如果我们只是简单地复制粘贴一个
business. Even if we had the original
商业。即使我们拥有原版
idea ourselves when really there's
我们自己想象着，但实际上却并非如此。
nothing to be ashamed of. We don't want
没什么好羞愧的。我们不想
to steal their intellectual property or
窃取他们的知识产权或
their logo or anything, but copy what's
他们的标志或其他任何东西，但要复制原有的内容。
already working.
已经开始运行了。
&gt;&gt; People think, you know, people don't
人们认为，你知道，人们不这么认为
think that that's a thing because they
认为这是真的，因为他们
think if I copy a business that's
想想如果我复制一家企业……
already working, then I'm not going to
如果我已经开始工作了，那我就不去了。
get any customers because that this
因为这样就无法获得任何客户
existing business has all the customers.
现有企业拥有所有客户。
&gt;&gt; But it's interesting. I had someone on
但这很有意思。我当时有个朋友
the show where they talked about how
在那个节目里，他们谈到了……
some of the greatest entrepreneurs in
一些最伟大的企业家
the world basically just copy 95% of the
世界基本上只模仿了95%的……
blueprint. I think it was Walmart. I
蓝图。我想应该是沃尔玛。我
think he was talking about Walmart, but
我想他指的是沃尔玛，但是
yeah, they copied other like regional
是的，他们抄袭了其他地区的类似做法。
grocery chains. Mhm. [clears throat]
连锁超市。嗯。 [清嗓子]
Copying as a strategy.
将模仿作为一种策略。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
Have you done that?
你做过这件事吗？
&gt;&gt; Oh, absolutely.
当然。
&gt;&gt; Give me an example.
请举个例子。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Well, I I had a phone repair
好的。嗯，我修过手机。
business in when I was in college, 2010,
2010年我还在上大学的时候就开始做生意了，
and I got a call one day from someone
有一天，我接到一个电话。
that said, "Hey, Chris, I want to buy
也就是说，“嘿，克里斯，我想买
all of your broken iPhone screens." Do
你所有摔坏的iPhone屏幕。”
you have any broken iPhone screens?
你的iPhone屏幕碎了吗？
Sure. We don't throw them away cuz we
当然。我们不把它们扔掉，因为我们
think it's bad for the environment. We
我认为这对环境有害。我们
just have a box of them. How much will
就买一盒吧。多少钱？
you pay me? three bucks a piece. Why?
你付钱给我？每件三美元。为什么？
Why? Why will you pay me $3? It's just
为什么？你为什么要付我3美元？只是
broken glass. And they said, "Well,
碎玻璃。他们说：“好吧，
there's actually a way of
实际上有一种方法
remanufacturing these. We can send them
对这些产品进行再制造。我们可以把它们寄给他们。
to China. We can remove the broken
到中国。我们可以移除破损的部件。
glass, put new glass on them, and then
把玻璃换成新的，然后
we can resell them as a remanufactured
我们可以将它们作为翻新产品转售。
unit." And that was just like a light
“单位。”那就像一道光
bulb, right? So, most people, I think,
是灯泡，对吧？所以，我想大多数人
at this point, would say, "Yeah, like,
此时，他会说：“是啊，就像，
yeah, where do I ship these?" You know,
“是啊，这些东西我该寄到哪里去？”你知道，
but I was like, "Oh, I need to be in
但我当时想，“哦，我需要参与其中。”
that business. I want to copy that guy
那家公司。我想模仿那个人
who called me." right now. I don't know
现在是谁给我打的电话？我不知道。
what his website was. I don't know. I
他的网站是什么？我不知道。我
don't know what the name of his business
不知道他公司叫什么名字
was. There was no web archive at the
曾是。当时没有网络存档。
time to look at. I just wanted to copy
是时候看看了。我只是想复制
the business model cuz I thought this is
我之所以认为这是商业模式，是因为我认为这是
going to be a thing. I'm in the
将会成为一种现象。我在
industry. I know the industry. I'm going
行业。我了解这个行业。我要去
to do this as well. We did 2 million the
这样做也是可以的。我们做了200万
first year, then five, and then nine,
第一年，然后是第五年，然后是第九年，
and then we exited a few years after
几年后我们就退出了。
that.
那。
&gt;&gt; It's interesting, but you know, you
这很有意思，但是你知道，你
often don't think that
他们通常不会这么想。
everyone's in search of a new idea.
每个人都在寻找新的想法。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And it's tough to find new ideas. Yeah,
找到新点子并不容易。是的，
like I think was it Einstein that said
我想好像是爱因斯坦说过的话吧。
there's no such thing as a new idea?
难道就没有新想法吗？
Sounds right. But you have an
听起来没错。但你有一个
orientation just to look at existing
方向只是为了观察现有情况
models and to replicate them. Do you put
模型并对其进行复制。你放
a spin on it at all? I'll develop my own
有没有其他解读方式？我会开发自己的
spins over time. Right. Because we're
随着时间的推移而旋转。正确的。因为我们是
all a product of our environment. And so
这一切都是环境的产物。所以
in in the case of this business, I
就这家公司而言，我
started copying. Exactly. Right. Um I
开始复制。确切地。正确的。嗯，我
went and found people in China. I just
去了中国，找到了一些人。我只是
went to Alibaba. I messaged a ton of
去了阿里巴巴。我发了很多信息
people that sold iPhone screens and I
那些卖iPhone屏幕的人和我
said, "Do you recycle? Do you recycle?
他说：“你们回收利用吗？你们回收利用吗？”
did you recycle? And like five or 10% of
你回收利用了吗？还有大约百分之五到百分之十的
them said yes. So then I shipped them
他们答应了。于是我就把它们寄出去了。
samples and then they shipped me some
样品，然后他们给我寄了一些。
back and and then over time I started
回去之后，随着时间的推移，我开始
like taking some marketing principles
例如，可以借鉴一些营销原则。
principles from previous businesses like
借鉴以往业务的原则，例如
Facebook ads, cold calling and I started
Facebook广告、电话推销，然后我开始了
applying them just cuz I didn't know how
我之所以应用它们，只是因为我不知道怎么做。
this other competitor was finding
另一位竞争对手发现
success. I knew he was cold calling and
成功。我知道他是在进行陌生拜访。
that was working. That's all I knew.
那样做是行得通的。我当时只知道这些。
Remember I didn't even know the name of
记得我当时甚至不知道他的名字
his business. And so over time, you
他的生意。所以随着时间的推移，你
start using your previous experiences to
开始运用你过去的经验
apply these tweaks to the business and
将这些调整应用于业务中，
to make it your own. But if you do that
让它成为你自己的风格。但如果你那样做的话
right at the outset, right? Like if I
一开始就是这样，对吧？比如如果我
got a call and he said, "I want to buy
接到一个电话，他说：“我想买。”
your broken iPhone screens." And I said,
你那碎掉的iPhone屏幕。”我说，
"Okay, I'm going to do that, but I don't
“好的，我会这么做，但我不会……”
want to just sell iPhone screens. That's
只想卖iPhone屏幕。那是
lame. I'm going to do Samsung." Right?
瘸。我打算用三星的。对吧？
Pretty good chance there's not even a
很有可能根本没有
market for that or there's not even a
要么有这样的市场，要么根本就没有。
method for that. And because of my my
方法。因为我的
ego, my pride, my unwillingness to just
自负、骄傲、以及我不愿就此罢休的性格
copy what's already working, I wouldn't
照搬已经奏效的方案，我不会这么做。
that I wouldn't have that successful
那样我就不会那么成功了。
business in my back pocket. Right?
生意就在我的后口袋里。正确的？
[clears throat]
[清嗓子]
&gt;&gt; So, if you do twists in the beginning,
所以，如果你一开始就做扭转动作，
it's kind of like your um I'm kind of
有点像你的……嗯，我有点……
thinking of an analogy like if you're on
想一个类似的例子，比如你正在……
a long road trip and you start taking
长途自驾游，你开始……
detours early on or if a flight is on a
提前绕道，或者如果航班在……
flight path and he starts like getting
飞行路线，他开始像……一样。
off track just a little bit at the
稍微偏离轨道了一点
beginning, he's going to end off he's
开始，他将结束，他是
going to end up hundreds of miles away
最终会到达数百英里之外的地方
from his destination. But if he starts
从他的目的地出发。但如果他开始
making tweaks along the way, then he'll
他会在此过程中不断进行调整，然后他会
be much closer to where he would have
会离他原本应该在的地方更近一些
been anyway.
反正一直都是这样。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. And you [clears throat] might reach
嗯。而你（清了清嗓子）可能会达到
a better destination with some of those
更好的目的地，其中一些
&gt;&gt; tweaks because you're blending it with
因为你要把它和……混合，所以需要做一些调整。
your your experience, what you know
你的经验，你的知识
better than the person that you're
比你现在的这个人要好
copying.
复制。
&gt;&gt; And so it's important to to copy the
因此，复制以下内容很重要：
model exactly at the beginning because
模型一开始就完全一样，因为
you're also going to learn what it is
你还会了解到它是什么。
about that existing model that works.
关于目前行之有效的模式。
Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And therefore what you can iterate on,
因此，你可以迭代改进的地方是：
change, expand. If you if you didn't,
改变，扩展。如果你没有，
then you might miss something. Exactly.
那样你可能会错过一些东西。确切地。
Cuz so often I made the mistake of
因为我经常犯这样的错误
looking at another business and saying,
看着另一家企业，然后说：
"Oh man, why are they doing that? Why
“哦，天哪，他们为什么要这样做？为什么？”
are they charging like that? Why? Like
他们真的这样收费吗？为什么？喜欢
they're charging all these different
他们收取的费用各不相同。
things. That's so confusing." I made
事物。这太令人困惑了。”我做了
this mistake. I had a an e-commerce
这个错误。我曾经营一家电子商务公司。
fulfillment business where brands would
品牌会参与的履约业务
send us all their products. We had this
请把他们的所有产品都寄给我们。我们曾有过这个
big warehouse and we would ship all all
我们拥有大型仓库，所有商品都会发货。
of their stuff out, right? And I was
他们把东西都拿出来了，对吧？而我当时
like, "Why do they have storage fees,
例如，“为什么他们会收取仓储费？”
pick pack, and ship fees? They they
拣货、包装和运费？他们
charge fees for tracking their
收取追踪费用
expiration dates. They charge extra fees
有效期。他们会收取额外费用
if there's five items in a box versus
如果一个盒子里有五件物品，
four. Like there's so much friction
四、感觉摩擦力太大了。
there. That's so messy. Like we're going
那里。真是太乱了。就像我们要去的地方
to make this simple. We're going to just
简单来说。我们打算就这么做。
one flat fee, no storage fee, and that's
一次性收取固定费用，不收取仓储费，就是这样。
going to be our differentiator, right?
这将是我们的差异化优势，对吧？
And then over time, over the course of
然后随着时间的推移，在……的过程中
months and years, we learned, oh,
几个月几年后，我们才明白，哦，
storage fees. It's because sometimes
仓储费。这是因为有时
your customers go out of business and
你的客户倒闭了，
then you're left holding the bill and
然后你就得自己承担账单了。
like your storage costs are actually
比如你的仓储成本实际上是
very high but there's nothing to pass
高得离谱，但没什么可及的。
on. Oh, pick back and ship fees because
在。哦，还有退货和运费，因为
you learn all these things and you're
你学会了所有这些东西，然后你
like, "Okay, I wasn't like this genius
就像，“好吧，我以前可不是这种天才。”
that had an MBA. I was just like trying
拥有工商管理硕士学位。我当时只是想试试而已。
to put my own spin on it cuz I thought I
我想加入我自己的想法，因为我觉得
was smarter than that business owner."
比那位企业主聪明多了。
Turns out someone that's been doing this
原来一直有人在做这件事
for 15 years versus 15 days knows a lot
15 年和 15 天相比，懂得很多。
more about the industry than me. And I'm
他更了解这个行业，而不是我。而我是
much better off just copying his
最好还是直接模仿他的做法。
pricing, copying the layout of his
定价，复制他的布局
website, copying the size of the
网站，复制其大小
warehouse he has, copying the same niche
他拥有一个仓库，复制了同样的细分市场。
that he's going after, cuz that's
他要去追寻的就是这个，因为那是
clearly working for him. So, I don't
显然是为他工作的。所以，我不
make that mistake anymore. I don't I
别再犯同样的错误了。我不
don't assume that other competitors are
不要假设其他竞争对手
idiots, right? Yeah.
真是白痴，对吧？是的。
&gt;&gt; I've been proven wrong too many times. I
我被证明犯错的次数太多了。我
assume that they're doing that because
假设他们这样做是因为
they've learned the hard way. Yeah.
他们付出了惨痛的代价才吸取了教训。是的。
&gt;&gt; And if I copy them, then I won't have to
如果我复制它们，我就不必……
learn the hard way.
吃一堑长一智。
&gt;&gt; I had um several of our executives over
我邀请了几位高管过来。
at my house over the last couple of days
过去几天我一直待在我家。
and we were looking at different models
我们当时在研究不同的模型。
of so basically we're looking at other
所以基本上我们是在看其他方面。
companies that do similar things to us
与我们做类似事情的公司
that have been around for a long time.
已经存在很长时间了。
And the question that I ended up asking
最后我问的问题是
at one moment when I was had the exact
在某个时刻，我正好
same epiphany. I was like why do they do
同样的顿悟。我当时就想，他们为什么要这样做？
it that way? Isn't that shitty?
那样吗？那岂不是很糟糕吗？
&gt;&gt; And there was a second where I think we
还有一次，我觉得我们
were tempted to try and reinvent the
他们曾试图重新发明……
wheel. But the question I ask myself now
车轮。但我现在问自己的问题是……
with the wisdom of like many years of
凭借多年积累的智慧
business is like why did it end up that
商业就像是，为什么最终会变成那样？
way?
方式？
&gt;&gt; Which is why did our competitor who's
这就是为什么我们的竞争对手……
been doing this for 50 years end up
做了50年，最后
there?
那里？
&gt;&gt; Because that as you said there's clearly
因为正如你所说，这一点显然是存在的。
a set of things that have happened that
一系列已经发生的事情
have made them conclude whether it's at
让他们得出结论，它是否在
scale or some other factor that's made
规模或其他一些因素造成的
them conclude that this is the best way
他们得出结论，这是最好的方法
of doing it. And just like you I've been
去做这件事。就像你一样，我也曾是
wrong so many times where I've thought
我错了很多次，我以为
they're just idiots. That's why they
他们简直就是一群白痴。这就是他们的原因
they they can't see this obvious thing.
他们竟然看不到这显而易见的事实。
But actually their model is stress
但实际上他们的模型是压力模型。
tested in the market much more than mine
市场上经过检验的产品比我的多得多。
is. So maybe I should
是。所以也许我应该
&gt;&gt; I should put my ego aside and at least
我应该放下自尊，至少
start how they start as you said which I
就像你说的，他们就是这样开始的，我
think is really important advice.
我认为这确实是一条非常重要的建议。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, there are times when a
是的。嗯，有时候……
company just keeps doing something
公司一直在做某件事
because it works.
因为它有效。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And so they don't take the time to test
所以他们不花时间去测试
something that works better,
更好的方法，
&gt;&gt; right?
正确的？
&gt;&gt; But it's almost impossible to guess what
但几乎不可能猜到是什么
that is, right? Like if a if a clothing
没错吧？比如，如果一件衣服
brand is growing their business entirely
该品牌正在全面拓展业务。
through Facebook ads um and they've just
通过 Facebook 广告，嗯，他们刚刚
never tried Google ads, maybe Google ads
从未尝试过谷歌广告，也许是谷歌广告
could convert twice as better. Twice
转化率可以提高一倍。两次
twice better, right? But I don't want to
效果好两倍，对吧？但我不想
guess that. I just want to start with
我猜对了。我只想从……开始
Facebook ads and then I'll still take 5%
Facebook广告，我还能再拿5%的佣金。
of my budget and start testing other
在我的预算范围内，开始测试其他产品
concepts. But nine times out of 10, I
概念。但十次里有九次，我
ended up just coming right back to
结果还是回到了原点
Facebook ads. It got me thinking about
Facebook广告。这让我开始思考……
how in business basically everything,
在商业中，基本上一切都是如此。
again speaking broadly here, can be put
再次概括地说，可以这样说
into one of two categories. either like
分为两类之一。要么喜欢
old problems where thousands of people
数千人面临的老问题
have come before you and the same
在你之前，也同样如此。
solutions and same thinking is still
解决方案和同样的思路依然存在
relevant and then new problems you know
相关问题以及你已知的新问题
things like AI have created a set of new
人工智能等技术创造了一系列新的事物。
problems new opportunities as well and
问题也带来了新的机遇。
what I tend to find is that like 95% of
我发现的情况是，大约95%的
the things in business are like old
商业中的事物就像旧事物一样
problems like hiring cash flow how
诸如招聘现金流等问题如何解决
finance is done legal all those kinds of
金融活动都是合法进行的，诸如此类。
things
事物
&gt;&gt; and the and when when you're dealing
以及当你处理的时候
with a new an old problem expertise is
拥有解决新旧问题的专业知识
usually the answer which is like find
通常答案就像是“找到”。
someone who knows hire someone or mentor
懂得如何招聘或指导的人
or whatever and then you have these new
或者其他什么，然后你就有了这些新的
problems where
问题所在
&gt;&gt; there is no blueprint in our industry.
我们这个行业没有现成的模式。
It's a new new challenge. So
这是一个全新的挑战。所以
experimentation is the answer. Does that
实验是解决之道。是吗？
like broadly hold in your in your mind?
就像你脑海中大致存在的那样？
&gt;&gt; Oh 100%. Yeah. I I like to say test
哦，百分之百。是的。我喜欢说测试
everything except drugs.
除了毒品以外，其他一切。
&gt;&gt; Like we're always testing. Um it's the
就像我们一直在测试一样。嗯，是……
basis to everything we do.
这是我们一切行动的基础。
&gt;&gt; But do you test when it's an old
但是，如果是旧款，你会进行测试吗？
problem?
问题？
&gt;&gt; Can you give me an example? So
你能举个例子吗？所以
like things like cash flow management um
比如现金流管理之类的事情
&gt;&gt; hiring principles around like probation
招聘原则，例如试用期
and uh notice periods
以及通知期
um a lot of legal structuring and deals
嗯，很多法律结构和交易。
things with like a wellestablished
类似成熟的事物
president
总统
&gt;&gt; well established presidents where like
像那些根基稳固的总统们
nothing has fundamentally changed in the
本质上，一切都没有改变。
world that makes that invalid. Yeah, I
这个世界使得这种说法无效。是的，我
think if it's an old problem, I look to
想想如果这是个老问题，我会看看
an example of someone within the last
过去某个时期的一个例子
decade that's solved it in an
十年内解决了这个问题
interesting way and I'm more likely to
有趣的方式，我更倾向于
copy that. Like in hiring, traditionally
收到。就像传统招聘一样
companies will they'll spend hours and
公司会花几个小时，
weeks or days hiring, going from round
招聘周期从几周或几天开始。
to round to round, person. And if you
绕圈，人。如果你
look at Y Combinator, arguably the
看看 Y Combinator，可以说是
greatest, you know, startup incubator in
最棒的创业孵化器，你知道的。
the world, they have seven-minute
全世界，他们有七分钟
interviews. Um, and they said they would
面试。嗯，他们说他们会
make it five minutes, but it just felt
五分钟就够了，但感觉就是这么短。
rude, right? and in their interviews,
很没礼貌，对吧？在他们的采访中，
they really know in the first three
他们确实在前三个阶段就明白了。
minutes if it's a fit or not, and then
几分钟后，看看是否合适，然后……
the interview's done. Like, they're
面试结束了。比如，他们是
either in or they're not. I I approach
要么在，要么不在。我的方法
hiring the same way. Um, I would much
招聘方式相同。嗯，我非常
rather um take a like a a law of large
更确切地说，就像大定律一样。
numbers approach to it and give five
采用数字方法，并给出五个
people 30 days to show what their skills
人们有 30 天的时间来展示他们的技能
are as opposed to spending 30 days going
与花30天时间相比，
all in on one person. Because in my
全部的希望都寄托在一个人身上。因为在我的
experience, that one person that I spent
经历，那个我曾与之相处的人
30 days on is not any more likely to
30天后，可能性并不会更大
succeed than those those other five
比其他五人更成功
people that I might be testing.
我可能会测试的人。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
And your example of that storage company
还有你举的那个仓储公司的例子
you started.
你开始了。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; It sounds like you hit an old problem.
听起来你遇到了一个老问题。
&gt;&gt; Yes, very much so.
是的，确实如此。
&gt;&gt; And you tried to innovate and
你尝试过创新，
experiment, but this was an old problem
实验，但这其实是个老问题了。
where the laws of human beings and how
人类的法律在哪里以及如何
they behave and businesses going bust
他们的行为以及企业倒闭的情况
was still pertinent.
仍然具有现实意义。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And at the end of our our 2-year
是的。在我们两年的最后……
experiment, like we look just like all
实验，就像我们看起来和所有人一样
of our competitors, right? So, if we
我们的竞争对手，对吧？所以，如果我们
would have started there, we could have
我们本可以从那里开始，我们本来可以
saved two years.
节省了两年时间。
&gt;&gt; And this is what I find is founders
这就是我发现的创始人
waste years trying to experiment where
浪费数年时间试图进行各种实验
old problems are still um strong and
老问题依然根深蒂固，而且
still hold.
仍然有效。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And this is what I the mistake several
这就是我犯的几个错误。
of the mistakes I made in my company was
我在公司犯的错误是
I should have spent all of my time
我应该把所有时间都花在……
experimenting on the new problems.
尝试解决新问题。
&gt;&gt; Uhhuh. and should have hired people to
嗯哼。应该雇人来
tell me um how to navigate the old
告诉我如何使用旧系统
problems.
问题。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; What what was your um I think one of the
你的……嗯……我想其中一个
videos that made you go pretty viral was
让你爆红的视频是
your story of
你的故事
&gt;&gt; BIES. We don't know what BIES is around
比斯。我们不知道BIES是什么。
the world. I think it's a US brand.
世界。我认为这是一个美国品牌。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; But this shows I think how you've always
但这表明，我认为这是你一直以来的风格。
had an orientation to think slightly
略微倾向于思考
differently or in innovatively.
以不同的方式或创新的方式。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; What happened with BIES?
BIES到底发生了什么？
&gt;&gt; So this was during the time when I was
所以，那是在我……的那段时间。
running that business shipping products
经营这家公司，运送产品
for other companies. Right. Bies is a
为其他公司。正确的。比斯是一个
gas station brand uh with only 50
加油站品牌，呃，只有50
locations. And from those 50 locations,
地点。而在这50个地点中，
they do billions of dollars of revenue.
他们创造了数十亿美元的收入。
I say gas station, they're between
我说的是加油站，它们在……之间
40,000 and 80,000 square feet. Wow.
40,000 和 80,000 平方英尺。哇。
&gt;&gt; They're massive. They have an amazing
它们体型巨大。他们拥有惊人的天赋。
brand, an amazing logo, and they just
品牌，一个很棒的标志，他们就……
have a lot of trust from their
他们非常信任他们。
customers. But these gas stations are
顾客。但这些加油站是
like they're on the way out to these
就像他们正要离开这里一样
road trip destinations. They're out in
自驾游目的地。他们出去了
the middle of nowhere. And so if you're
荒郊野外。所以，如果你是
if you live in Dallas and you're driving
如果你住在达拉斯，并且正在开车
down to the beach, you're going to stop
走到海滩边，你就会停下来
by Bies on the way there and on the way
途中和去程途中都经过比斯
back, and you're probably going to spend
回来，你可能要花……
hundreds of dollars, right? You're going
几百美元，对吧？你要走了
to fill up the tank, then you're going
加满油箱，然后你就可以出发了。
to buy shirts and snacks and all that
去买衬衫、零食等等
stuff. So, at the time we were running
东西。所以，当时我们正在运行
this e-commerce fulfillment business, we
我们这家电子商务物流公司
went to Buckies. I brought my cousin, my
去了巴基斯。我带了我的表弟，我的
business partner, um, just to kind of
商业伙伴，嗯，只是想……
show him the experience. And we were
让他亲身体验一下。我们当时
just having a conversation. I remember
只是闲聊而已。我记得
exactly where I was. I was like under
我当时就在那儿。我当时就像在……之下
this underpass, this huge under pass in
这个地下通道，这个巨大的地下通道
DFW. We were driving home and I said,
达拉斯-沃斯堡。我们开车回家的路上，我说：
"Man, these guys must kill it online.
“伙计，这些人肯定在网上很火。”
They must sell so much stuff." Um,
他们一定卖出了很多东西。”嗯，
&gt;&gt; why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; Because I knew that Disney sells like
因为我知道迪士尼的销量很好。
billions of dollars of t-shirts on their
他们花了数十亿美元购买T恤。
website, right? I read a stat recently.
网站，对吧？我最近读到一篇统计数据。
So, I kind of just took that data point,
所以，我就直接采用了这个数据点。
connected it to Bies, and said, "All
它与比斯联系在一起，并说道：“所有
right, Bies is a fraction of the size of
没错，比斯的规模只是……的一小部分
Disney, but they have the same amount of
迪士尼，但它们的数量相同
brand loyalty. People love their shirts.
品牌忠诚度。人们很喜欢他们的衬衫。
You'll see their shirts all over the
你会在各处看到他们的衬衫
world, even though they only have 50
世界，即使他们只有50
locations like in the Southeast, right?"
像东南部那样的地方，对吧？”
And so we went to their website and
于是我们访问了他们的网站，
there was no shop button. There was no
没有“购买”按钮。没有
place to buy their stuff and I was just
我当时就在买他们东西的地方。
like like all the light bulbs were going
就像所有的灯泡都亮了一样
off at once, right? It was like, "Oh my
立即关闭，对吧？当时的感觉就像是，“哦，我的天哪”
gosh, okay, we need to reach out to
哦，好吧，我们需要联系
them. Like we need to bring them
他们。就像我们需要带他们来一样
online." I just had all these ideas and
“在网上。”我当时有很多想法，
my cousin is is much more balanced than
我的表弟比我表妹要沉稳得多。
I am. He's like the the operator and I'm
我是。他就像操作员，而我
like the ADHD crazy guy, right? So his
就像那个患有注意力缺陷多动症的疯子一样，对吧？所以他的
role is to like calm me down and he's
他的角色是安抚我的情绪，而他
very good at that. But I just couldn't
非常擅长这个。但我就是做不到
be calmed down from this. I'm like, "No,
冷静下来。我心想，“不，
no, no. We got to do something here.
不，不。我们必须做点什么了。
We're going to buy one of everything.
我们打算每样东西都买一份。
We're going to hire a photographer to
我们将聘请一位摄影师
take pictures of it. We're going to
给它拍照。我们将要
launch our own BIES online store, and
推出我们自己的BIES在线商店，
we're going to try to go viral." Like,
我们打算尝试让它爆红。就像这样，
it's viral or bust, right? If we don't
要么爆红，要么就失败，对吧？如果我们不
go viral, then I'll just be eating these
如果火了，我就吃这些。
unhealthy snacks for the next 3 years of
接下来三年，我都会吃不健康的零食。
my life. And so, we did. We bought one
我的人生。于是，我们就这么做了。我们买了一个
of everything. Uh, it cost thousands of
一切。呃，花费了数千美元
dollars. I brought all four of my kids.
美元。我带了我的四个孩子一起来。
And, uh, we brought it back to our
然后，呃，我们把它带回了我们的
warehouse. We took pictures of it. We
仓库。我们拍了照片。我们
launched a website. Um, and I emailed
上线了一个网站。嗯，我发了邮件
all the reporters I could find. Uh, and
我能找到的所有记者。呃，还有
one of them just loved the idea. He ran
其中一人非常喜欢这个主意。他跑了
with it. And so he reached out to BIES
和它一起。于是他联系了BIES。
for comment cuz they wouldn't respond to
因为他们不回应，所以无法评论。
my cold emails. I wanted to launch this
我的陌生开发邮件。我想推出这个
like with them in tandem, but who am I?
就像和他们一起并肩作战一样，但我又是谁呢？
They didn't care about me. And I don't
他们根本不在乎我。我没有
blame them. And so he wrote this big
都怪他们。于是他写下了这篇长文。
article about me. Millions of people
一篇关于我的文章。数百万人
read it. All these other news outlets uh
读一下。其他所有新闻媒体呃
wrote about it. And we did hundreds of
我写过相关文章。我们做了数百次。
thousands of of dollars in our first 30
在最初的30年里，我们赚了数千美元。
days organically from that.
从那以后，几天内自然而然地发生了。
How did Bies feel about that?
比斯对此有何感想？
&gt;&gt; They wanted us to make some key changes
他们希望我们做出一些关键改变。
to the website. They wanted us to like
进入网站。他们想让我们喜欢
basically put disclaimers everywhere
基本上到处都要加上免责声明。
that said we are not Bies. We're not
也就是说，我们不是Bies。我们不是
affiliated with Bies. They wanted us to
与比斯有关联。他们希望我们
change the name. It had the word beaver
更改名称。上面有“海狸”这个词。
in the name. That's their mascot. They
以名称为名。那是他们的吉祥物。他们
just they didn't want it to be confusing
只是他们不想让人感到困惑。
at all. So, we made all those changes
完全没有。所以，我们做了所有这些改变。
and then we got like the unofficial
然后我们就得到了类似非官方的
thumbs up from them. They said, "We're
他们都竖起了大拇指。他们说：“我们是
not going to sign anything, but like you
我不会签任何东西，但是就像你一样。
have our blessing. Um, have fun." And
请接受我们的祝福。嗯，玩得开心。”
did that website make you a lot of
那个网站让你赚了很多钱吗？
money?
钱？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it still is. It's been 5 years. We
是的，现在依然如此。已经五年了。我们
still own it, 100% of it, and it's going
我仍然拥有它，100%的所有权，而且它还在继续
great.
伟大的。
&gt;&gt; And it's made you millions.
它让你赚了数百万美元。
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
&gt;&gt; What can someone listening take from
听众能从中获得什么？
that in terms of applying that to their
就将其应用于他们而言
own life, finding opportunities like
过自己的生活，寻找机会，例如
that out in the world, or is that just a
在外面的世界里，或者那只是……
oneandone? Is there only one opportunity
一对一？只有一次机会吗？
like that? Okay. So, specific, I get
像这样吗？好的。所以，具体来说，我明白了。
asked that question a lot. How could
我问过很多人这个问题。怎么可能
someone do that with another brand?
有人用其他品牌做过类似的事情吗？
I don't know. If if there was another
我不知道。如果还有另一个
brand out there like that, I would be
如果能有这样一个品牌，我会……
doing it, right? Trader Joe's is
正在做，对吧？ Trader Joe's是
similar, but they're very ligious. Um I
相似，但他们非常虔诚。嗯，我
think that was kind of lightning in a
我觉得那就像一道闪电。
bottle for that particular experiment as
用于该特定实验的瓶子
in launching an online brand for an
在为一家公司推出在线品牌
in-person business. Okay. But people
面对面业务。好的。但人们
should not be disheartened hearing that
听到这些话不应该灰心丧气
because on a macro level like people
因为从宏观层面来看，就像人们一样
should take their curious ideas very
应该非常重视他们那些奇特的想法。
seriously. [snorts] They need to shorten
严重地。 [嗤笑] 他们需要缩短
the amount of time spent between having
两次经历之间的时间间隔
the idea and doing something about that
这个想法以及如何实现它。
idea
主意
&gt;&gt; because that will strengthen their bias
因为那样会加深他们的偏见。
for action muscle, right? We all have
是为了活动肌肉，对吧？我们都有
ideas, some of them good, some of them
想法，有些不错，有些
bad on a regular basis. We usually don't
经常表现不佳。我们通常不会
do anything about it. It's just a
你对此无能为力吗？它只是一个
passing thought, right? Whether it's a
只是一闪而过的想法，对吧？无论是
business idea or a hard conversation I
商业想法或艰难的谈话
need to have with something, any idea,
需要和某样东西有关，有什么想法吗？
right? But the the the more we shrink
正确的？但我们越是缩小
the amount of time between doing
两次做某事之间的时间间隔
something about that idea and having the
关于这个想法以及拥有
idea that that idea, the more often
认为这种想法，越是经常
we'll do that. And it becomes this
我们会这么做。它就变成了这样
self-perpetuating snowball that just
就像滚雪球一样，自我延续，永无止境。
compounds. And then before we know it,
化合物。然后，在我们还没反应过来之前，
we'll get more ideas. We'll do more
我们会想到更多办法。我们会做得更多
about those ideas. We'll be testing
关于这些想法。我们将进行测试
things. We'll be learning tools. We'll
事物。我们将学习使用各种工具。出色地
be experimenting. And we'll have a whole
尝试各种方法。我们将拥有一个完整的
portfolio of businesses. Is there
企业组合。有没有
something in your mentality or
你心态上的某些东西，或者
perspective though where you walk into a
但从你走进的地方的角度来看
Buckies and you even think about how you
巴基斯，你甚至会想你如何
could do something whereas most people
可以做某事，而大多数人
walk into a Bies and buy their stuff and
走进一家Bies商店，买他们的东西
leave? Like is there something
离开？好像有什么事吗？
foundational in the way that you're
从根本上来说，你是
looking at the world? Yeah. But I don't
在观察这个世界吗？是的。但我没有
think I'm any different. I think um I
你觉得我有什么不同吗？我想嗯……
think a lot of people have ideas like
我认为很多人都有这样的想法。
that. Like you walk into a BIES and you
那。就像你走进一家BIES，然后你
see something about something that could
看到一些关于某件事的信息，这可能
be improved and people have these
可以改进，人们拥有这些
passing thoughts and they move on. I
思绪飘忽不定，然后继续前行。我
think that you become an expert at doing
认为你会成为这方面的专家
something about those ideas. When you do
关于这些想法的一些内容。当你这样做的时候
something about those ideas, you just
关于那些想法，你就是……
you get better at at what you do, at
你会越来越擅长你所做的事情。
what you test,
你测试的内容，
&gt;&gt; cuz you've built up some kind of muscle,
因为你练出了一些肌肉，
which means that you don't really care
这意味着你根本不在乎
about it seems failure as much as the
就这一点而言，它似乎和失败一样令人失望。
average person. And also in that
普通人。而且在那方面也是如此
particular case,
具体情况
&gt;&gt; the average person might think, well,
普通人可能会想，嗯，
I've got no experience in doing that.
我在这方面没有任何经验。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. No, no one has any experience in
嗯。不，没有人有这方面的经验。
anything until they do it, right? Like
在他们付诸行动之前，什么都行，对吧？喜欢
every every expert started out as a
每一位专家最初都是从零开始的。
beginner, right?
新手，对吧？
Sometimes though, people try this and
但有时，人们会尝试这样做
they learn h doesn't give them energy.
他们发现 h 并不能给他们提供能量。
It's not for them. That's okay. Now,
这不适合他们。没关系。现在，
when they have ideas, they can know, all
当他们有了想法，他们就能知道一切。
right, box checked. That's not really
好的，已勾选。那其实不是真的
for me. That entrepreneurship thinks
为我。那种企业家精神
someone else needs to do that. And
这件事得由别人来做。和
great, good. All the power to them. I
很好，不错。祝他们好运。我
just want people to answer that question
只是想让大家回答这个问题
for themselves. I hate seeing regret in
为了他们自己。我讨厌看到别人后悔。
people's faces. Like I have friends that
人们的脸。比如我有一些朋友
want to start a business. They've always
想创业。他们一直
talked about it and I know they would be
我们谈过这件事，我知道他们会……
good at it and I know it just eats them
我很擅长这个，我知道它会把它们吃掉。
up and they have really really good
他们真的非常好
ideas objectively and I I just hate
客观地看待这些想法，我就是讨厌它们。
seeing them have that question for the
看到他们有这样的疑问，真是令人欣慰。
rest of their lives. I just want them to
余生。我只是希望他们
to taste entrepreneurship.
体验创业的乐趣。
Is it for everybody though? You know,
但它适合所有人吗？你知道，
you can think think of all your friends.
你可以想想你的所有朋友。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; You can probably put them in groups of
你大概可以把它们分成几组。
this person should, this person
这个人应该，这个人
shouldn't. Mhm. And what defines who
不应该。嗯。那么，究竟是什么定义了“谁”呢？
goes in which group?
属于哪个组？
&gt;&gt; To me, it's how far they go in doing
对我来说，关键在于他们做得有多远。
something about that idea because I will
关于这个想法，我会……
have friends that will text me ideas or
找些朋友，他们会给我发短信，给我一些想法或建议。
talk to me about ideas and then I never
跟我谈谈想法，然后我就再也不……
hear from them again about that thing. I
再次听到他们提起那件事。我
don't worry about them. Right? I I feel
别担心他们。正确的？我感觉
like there's a selection bias at play.
感觉像是存在选择性偏差。
Like if they really wanted to do
就好像他们真的想这么做一样
something about it, they would get a
他们对此有所了解，就会得到
little further down the line. They'd
再往后一点。他们会
follow up with me. that's, hey, I did
请与我联系。没错，我做到了。
this thing. Cuz I'll always give them
这个东西。因为我总会给他们
tips and feedback. You should do this.
建议和反馈。你应该这样做。
You should try this. And they'll follow
你应该试试这个。他们会跟随
up. And then, you know, at some point
向上。然后，你知道，在某个时候
along the line, it'll die, right? But if
它迟早会死掉，对吧？但是如果
they don't get any further than just
他们就此止步，再无其他进展。
telling me their idea, then
然后他们告诉我他们的想法
I don't I don't lose sleep over them.
我不会，我不会为这些事失眠。
&gt;&gt; So, it's kind of surviv. It's kind of
所以，这有点像是在求生。这有点像
sort of self- selecting itself anyway.
某种程度上来说，这算是自我筛选的结果。
&gt;&gt; It is entrepreneurship.
这就是创业精神。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Absolutely. But then I have other
是的。绝对地。但我还有其他情况。
friends that are like they'll follow up,
像那样的朋友会跟进，
they'll follow up, they'll follow up,
他们会跟进，他们会跟进。
and then and then it dies, which is
然后，然后它就死了，这就是
okay. A lot of my ideas die, too. And to
好的。我的很多想法也都夭折了。以及
me, that's a signal that it was supposed
对我来说，那是一个信号，表明它本该如此。
to die, right? I'll just move on to the
去死吧？我这就继续往下看。
next thing. Um, so it's those people
接下来。嗯，就是那些人。
that maybe I'm just biased and they look
也许我只是有偏见，他们看起来
more like me, you know? Um, maybe that's
更像我，你知道吗？嗯，也许那是……
not an accurate signal or not, but if
无论信号是否准确，但如果
they look more like me, then that's a
如果她们长得更像我，那就好了。
signal that they they should get further
发出信号，表明他们应该继续前进。
down the line and actually launch
顺其自然，最终启动
something that gets to revenue. Yeah.
能带来收入的东西。是的。
&gt;&gt; In your head, think of one person you
在你的脑海中，想一个人
know that should never start a business.
要知道，你永远都不应该创业。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Why did you think of that person without
你为什么会想到那个人？
telling me who they are? because they
告诉我他们是谁？因为他们
make a lot of money at their job and
他们工作收入很高，而且
they like their job well enough. They're
他们很喜欢自己的工作。他们是
not miserable. Um, and they're in their
并不悲惨。嗯，他们正在他们的
late 40s and they probably feel like it
快五十岁了，他们可能感觉就是这样。
would be too big of a risk to start
风险太大，不宜贸然开始。
something.
某物。
&gt;&gt; And do you objectively agree that it
你是否客观地同意这一点？
would be too big of a risk for them?
对他们来说风险太大了吗？
&gt;&gt; I do.
我愿意。
&gt;&gt; So, you're looking at that on a
所以，你现在正在看这个
risk-reward basis thinking the reward
基于风险回报的思考回报
doesn't out outweigh the risk here for
就此而言，其益处不足以抵消风险。
you?
你？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. Cuz people come to me like
是的。是的。因为人们会这样来找我
hoping that I'll encourage them to quit
希望我能鼓励他们辞职
their job, right? Like begging me to do
这是他们的工作，对吧？就像求我做那样
that without actually begging me. And I
他并没有真的求我。我
don't want to do that. Like I I've never
我不想那样做。就像我从未……
had to quit a job. Like I I started with
不得不辞职。就像我一开始那样
entrepreneurship, right? So the thought
创业精神，对吧？所以这个想法
of being 48 with four kids and quitting
48岁，有四个孩子，然后辞职
my $400,000 a year job to test
我年薪 40 万美元的工作是测试
something. It just sounds crazy to me.
某物。我觉得这简直太疯狂了。
&gt;&gt; On the other hand, think of one person
另一方面，想想一个人
you know that isn't an entrepreneur, but
你知道他不是企业家，但是
definitely should be, but you always
当然应该如此，但你总是
think, "Why don't they do it?"
想想，“他们为什么不这样做？”
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Why did you think of that person?
是的。你为什么会想到那个人？
&gt;&gt; Because it's a person that comes to me
因为是人主动来找我。
the most often with ideas and they're
他们最常提出想法，而且他们是
really, really good ideas. He's an
真是非常好的想法。他是一个
engineer. Um, and so he sees the world
工程师。嗯，所以他眼中的世界是这样的
in that way. Engineers make great
那样做。工程师成就斐然
entrepreneurs. Um,
企业家。嗯，
and he has a great work ethic and he's
他工作态度非常认真负责，而且……
like mid-career but not not so far
就像职业生涯中期，但还没到那个阶段。
along. And I know objectively that he's
沿着。而且我客观上知道他是
not
不是
he's actually quite miserable in his
他其实过得很痛苦
job. And I hate that for him because I
工作。我为他感到难过，因为……
see the talent that's there. And I want
看看这里有哪些人才。而我想要
him like I think he would excel and I
我觉得他会很出色，而且我
want to see that dream come true for
希望能看到这个梦想成真。
him.
他。
&gt;&gt; Why isn't he doing it?
他为什么不做？
&gt;&gt; I think it it's insecurity.
我认为这是缺乏安全感的表现。
&gt;&gt; Fear.
害怕。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. fear of
是的。害怕
probably fear of just letting go of
或许是害怕放手
something certain that's provided his
某些确定的事情为他提供了帮助
family a nice lifestyle and not getting
家庭生活美满，没有损失
that back again ever. Um
那段经历再次重现。嗯
I think that insecurities are at the
我认为不安全感是……
root of our best and our worst selves
我们最好和最坏自我的根源
and it can drive us to be our best or
它可以激励我们做到最好。
worst selves um depending on how
最糟糕的自己，嗯，这取决于……
self-aware we are about those
我们有自我意识，我们关注的是这些。
insecurities.
不安全感。
Is there a little bit of a flaw in his
他是不是有点小缺陷？
thinking in your perspective? Like why
换位思考一下？比如为什么
is it you you still even though what
是你吗？即使如此，你还是……
he's saying there about you know what
他说的意思是，你知道的，关于什么
you think he believes there about the
你认为他相信那件事吗？
security for his family is true you
他家人的安全确实得到了保障。
still think he should
仍然认为他应该
&gt;&gt; which suggests that there's some kind of
这表明存在某种
flaw you see in the way he's thinking
你觉得他思考方式中的缺陷是什么？
about it.
关于它。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
Because he doesn't have to quit his job.
因为他不必辞职。
um there's enough time in the day to do
嗯，一天的时间足够做这些事。
this on the nights and weekends to to do
晚上和周末要做这件事
enough of it to really prove itself out.
数量足够多，足以证明其价值。
Often times like
很多时候像这样
whatever our side hustle is, uh it has a
无论我们的副业是什么，它都有一个
very low ceiling if we're only working
如果我们只工作，那上限就非常低了。
on it um after hours, right? Let's say
下班后在做，对吧？比如说
we're spending 20 hours a week on a side
我们每周花20个小时在……
hustle and it makes us $50,000 a year,
努力工作，一年能赚5万美元。
but our job pays us $200,000 a year and
但我们这份工作年薪20万美元，
we spend 40 hours a week on that. One
我们每周要花40个小时在这上面。一
thing that I've noticed, which is kind
我注意到的一件事，这很……
of contradictory to how I feel about
这与我的感受截然相反
quitting something, um, is when we go
放弃某件事，嗯，就是我们离开的时候。
from 20 hours a week on our the $50,000
每周工作 20 小时，年薪 5 万美元
a year side hustle to 40 hours a week
一年兼职到每周 40 小时
and we quit the full-time thing, that
于是我们就辞掉了全职工作。
$50,000 a year goes to 500,000, right?
一年5万美元就变成了50万美元，对吧？
We double the amount of hours, but we 10
我们把工时翻倍，但我们只有10
times the amount of money that comes
乘以所得金额
from it because of the fact that we burn
因为我们燃烧它，所以才从中受益。
the boats that it has to work. I just I
它必须运转的船只。我只是
don't want people to burn the boats too
也不希望人们把船烧掉。
soon, right? Like there has to be a
应该很快了吧？好像必须要有
pathway. Like let's say our Facebook ads
路径。比如说我们的 Facebook 广告
are converting really well. We've tested
转化率真的很高。我们已经测试过
scaling it and they're profitable and we
扩大规模，他们就能盈利，而且我们
know what that would look like. But if
知道那会是什么样子。但是如果
we scale it, then we're going to have
我们扩大规模，然后我们就会拥有
more customer service complaints. We're
更多客户服务投诉。是
going to have to do more architecture of
需要做更多架构设计
the website. But we like we see a path
该网站。但我们就像看到了一条路
to scaling and it's already profitable
规模化生产已经实现盈利
and we know that like probably my boss
我们知道，就像我的老板一样。
will take me back like we have kind of
会带我回到过去，就像我们曾经那样。
these uh safety nets. That's like the
这些安全网。那就像……
perfect time to really burn the boats.
现在是破釜沉舟的最佳时机。
Not when like we have an idea or we've
不是当我们有想法或者我们已经……的时候。
tested it a little bit but not
我稍微测试了一下，但没有
thoroughly. Um that's too soon in my
彻底地。嗯，现在说这个还太早了。
opinion.
观点。
&gt;&gt; And but by burn the boats you mean the
但是，你说的“烧毁船只”是指……
analogy of I guess some of the the
我想，这有点像某些人的类比
wartime leaders who would pull up on an
战时领导人会拉起……
island that they were invading and burn
他们入侵并焚毁了那座岛屿。
the boat so that they had no plan B.
他们没有备用方案，所以他们只能选择那艘船。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. Exactly. Yeah. to quit.
嗯。确切地。是的。退出。
&gt;&gt; Do you think that really matters? The
你觉得这真的重要吗？这
whole idea of a plan B. Do you think
整个备选方案的构想。你觉得
people should have a plan B when they
人们在以下情况下应该有备选方案：
embark on entrepreneurship?
投身创业？
Can I contradict myself 100%. All right.
我可以百分之百自相矛盾吗？好的。
So, the rational Chris, the Chris with
所以，理性的克里斯，那个……
four kids says absolutely like you got
四个孩子说，绝对就像你得到了
to be a dad, you got to be a husband,
要想成为父亲，首先要成为丈夫。
you got to provide for your family,
你得养家糊口，
right? Um, and again, there's so many
正确的？嗯，还有，真的太多了。
tools out there for testing, for
市面上有很多用于测试的工具，例如……
scaling, for outsourcing. We could find
扩展外包规模。我们可以找到
a business partner to help pick up the
一位商业伙伴来帮忙接手
slack. We could use our kids, we could
松弛。我们可以利用我们的孩子，我们可以
use our spouse, whatever. There's so
利用配偶，随便什么都行。有这么多
many ways to really vet something out
有很多方法可以真正检验某件事。
before quitting that we don't have to
在辞职之前，我们不必这样做。
quit.
辞职。
But
但
the other side of my mouth, there's been
我嘴的另一边，一直都有
um two times in my entrepreneurial
嗯，在我创业的生涯中，有两次
career when someone burned the boats for
职业生涯，当有人为了事业而烧毁一切时
me, right? I pull up to an island and
是我吧？我把车停在一座岛上，
it's I've got my plan B. I'm testing
我还有备用方案。我正在测试
this business. This business is
这家公司。这家公司是
profitable. It's paying the bills. And
有利可图。它能支付账单。和
then someone else in the middle of the
然后，中间还有另一个人
night, they snuck out. They burn my
夜里，他们偷偷溜了出去。他们烧伤了我
boats and I wake up and I'm like, whoa,
船，然后我醒来，心想，哇，
where's my plan B? I wasn't ready to
我的备用方案在哪里？我还没准备好
burn those boats yet. Um, and plan A
先把那些船烧了吧。嗯，还有A计划。
just freaking thrives, right? And it's
简直欣欣向荣，对吧？而且是
not so much because of the fact that I
倒不是因为我
don't have a safety net anymore, but
现在没有安全网了，但是
it's because that event put a chip on my
那是因为那件事让我下定了决心
shoulder that makes me want to to prove
肩膀让我想要证明
those bad guys wrong. Right. To
那些坏人错了。正确的。到
oversimplify, those guys that burn my
简单来说，那些烧伤我的人
boat.
船。
&gt;&gt; Toxic motivation.
有害的动机。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. That's a that's a good way to
确切地。那是一个好方法
put it to show them I didn't need those
把它放在那里是为了向他们表明我不需要那些东西。
boats. I'm not going back, right? This
船。我不会回去，对吧？这
island is better than where I came from.
这个岛屿比我以前住的地方好多了。
&gt;&gt; I remember reading about a study on Plan
我记得读过一篇关于“计划”的研究。
B's where they got a group of students,
B 点，他们招收了一群学生，
two groups, and then they told them to
分成两组，然后他们告诉他们……
do a puzzle to win a treat. And then in
完成拼图游戏即可获得奖励。然后是
one of the groups, they told them that
其中一个小组，他们告诉他们：
they could get this treat at a vending
他们可以从自动售货机买到这种零食。
machine down the hallway if they if they
如果他们，如果他们，走廊尽头的机器
wanted it after. And the group that
之后就想要了。以及那个团体
didn't understand they could get the
他们不明白他们可以获得
same reward from a plan B
方案 B 也能获得同样的回报。
&gt;&gt; worked significantly harder to complete
为了完成这项工作，付出了更大的努力。
that puzzle.
那个谜题。
&gt;&gt; So there's something in the human psyche
所以，人类心理中确实存在某种东西。
of know when you know that you could
当你意识到自己可以做到的时候，你就会明白。
&gt;&gt; get the reward in another way. When you
以另一种方式获得奖励。当你
have a plan B, we work less hard at the
有了备选方案，我们就能少花点力气。
plan A.
方案A。
&gt;&gt; Logically, maybe we should, you know,
从逻辑上讲，或许我们应该……
practical and
实用且
&gt;&gt; unresponsible
不负责任
remove the plan B from our mind.
把备选方案从脑海中彻底清除。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah, I just like I I can't think
是的。是啊，我就是……我什么都想不起来。
of any stories from people in my sphere
我身边的人有什么故事吗？
of influence that have tested something,
已经检验过某些事物的影响力，
quit the plan A, and then plan B just
放弃A计划，然后执行B计划。
failed and like they just lost
失败了，就像他们刚刚输了一样。
everything. Like surely that's happened,
一切。这事肯定发生过，
right? That does happen when people like
正确的？当人们喜欢……的时候，这种情况确实会发生。
prematurely quit, but in my experience,
虽然我过早地退出了，但以我的经验来看，
it just it doesn't happen. Like it it
这种事根本不会发生。喜欢它
has the opposite effect. It becomes this
却产生了相反的效果。它变成了这样
huge motivating factor. And when they
巨大的激励因素。当
quit, I ask them like, "How do you feel?
辞职吧，我问他们：“你感觉怎么样？”
Are you freaking out?" And it's always
你是不是吓坏了？而且总是这样。
always, "I'm so excited right now. Like,
总是，“我现在太兴奋了。就像，
I'm going to go all in on this. Like,
我打算全力以赴。喜欢，
this has to work." And it does. It just
这必须奏效。”而且它确实奏效了。就是这样。
does.
做。
&gt;&gt; A lot of people are looking for passive
很多人都在寻找被动收入
income from side hustles. And I wondered
副业收入。我当时就在想
what your your op opinion was on passive
你对被动模式的看法是什么？
income because it's a word that comes up
收入，因为这个词经常出现。
so often in the comment section of this
在这篇文章的评论区里经常出现这种情况。
channel, but when we're doing sort of
频道，但当我们做某种……
sentiment analysis and what people are
情感分析以及人们的感受
what they're interested in. Passive
他们感兴趣的是什么。被动语态
income seems to be a bit of a buzz word.
收入似乎成了一个热门词汇。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's the silver bullet, right?
没错，它就是灵丹妙药，对吧？
It's like it's the uh it's the financial
这就像是……呃，这是金融方面的问题。
oic you could say.
可以说，oic。
&gt;&gt; What is passive income? How would how
什么是被动收入？如何
would one define that? I would define it
那该如何定义呢？我会这样定义它。
as income that you receive um that you
作为你收到的收入，嗯，你
don't have to continually put effort
不必持续付出努力
towards like uh buying treasuries,
比如购买国债，
earning 4% on on your money and you
你的投资可以赚取 4% 的收益，而且你
don't do anything and you just get paid.
什么都不用做，就能拿到工资。
And it's it's very hard to find
而且很难找到
especially early on. Like we have to be
尤其是在早期阶段。就像我们必须那样
willing to create active income, sweaty
愿意创造主动收入，挥汗如雨
income, ugly income, like by whatever
收入，糟糕的收入，就像通过任何方式获得的收入一样。
means necessary. And the more we do
必要手段。我们做得越多
that, the longer we do that, the more um
我们这样做的时间越长，就越……
realistic true passive income actually
实际上，真正的被动收入
is.
是。
Sweaty, ugly income.
辛苦而丑陋的收入。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Give me an example of some sweaty,
是的。给我举个例子，比如出汗的、
ugly income that anyone listening right
任何听得懂的人都会觉得这笔收入很丑陋
now could could create. What are your
现在可以创造。你的
favorite examples of non-obvious
非显而易见的例子
businesses that people have started that
人们创办的企业
have resulted in passive, sweaty, ugly
导致被动、汗流浃背、丑陋
income?
收入？
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
是的，
I mean, most things that I've started
我的意思是，我开始做的大多数事情。
have been just that. I had a uh a
一直都是如此。我有一个呃
concierge car buying business. Um
礼宾式购车服务。嗯
&gt;&gt; a concierge car buying business.
一家提供代购服务的汽车购买公司。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. What's that?
是的。那是什么？
&gt;&gt; So, picture a traditional car
想象一下一辆传统汽车
dealership, a used car dealership. You
经销商，一家二手车经销商。你
got to get your dealer's permit. That uh
你得先拿到经销商许可证。那个呃
enables you legally to go to the
使您能够合法地前往
auctions and buy cars at wholesale, put
拍卖和批发购买汽车，放置
them on your lot, and sell them. So, I
把它们放在你的地里，然后卖掉。所以，我
did all the regulatory stuff. I got my
完成了所有监管方面的事情。我得到了我的
my dealer's permit, but then I would go
我的经销商许可证，但之后我会去
to individuals and they would say, "I
对个人来说，他们会说：“我
want a 2024 Seoia. I want it to be blue,
想要一辆 2024 年款 Seoia。我想要蓝色的。
under 30,000 mi." and I would just go to
不到3万英里。”然后我就去
the auction and buy it for them for like
参加拍卖，然后替他们买下它，就像……
$700 fee. So, they get wholesale, they
费用700美元。所以，他们批发进货，他们
save money, I make money, I don't have
存钱，我赚钱，我没有
to bear the inventory risk and I can buy
承担库存风险，我可以购买
exactly what they want. Um, that sounds
正是他们想要的。嗯，听起来
great, right? On paper. People do that
很棒，对吧？纸面上。人们会这样做
business successfully. I didn't invent
企业经营成功。我不是发明者
it. I copied it, right? I hated it. Uh,
它。我复制的，对吧？我讨厌它。呃，
I was breaking down on the side of the
我当时在路边崩溃了
road driving these things back from the
把这些东西从路上运回来
auction. I'm not a car guy. I don't care
拍卖。我不是个爱车之人。我不在乎
about cars. I don't work on cars. It's
关于汽车。我不修车。它是
not my passion. That was ugly. It was
这不是我的爱好。那场面太难看了。那是
hot in Texas. I was standing out on the
德克萨斯州很热。我当时站在……
black top. I was making money. It was
黑色上衣。我当时在赚钱。那是
profitable. And I got to the point where
有利可图。而我到了那种地步，
I just like quit it. I just shut it
我只想退出。我把它关上了
down. Moved on to something else. Um
向下。去做别的事情了。嗯
that was very active. It was not
那真是太热闹了。并非如此
scalable on the surface. It was ugly. I
表面上可扩展。太糟糕了。我
hated it. And so I pivoted because I had
讨厌它。所以我改变了策略，因为我有
a plan B. I didn't have to do that,
备选方案。我本来不必这么做的。
right? Um that's one example. Uh if
正确的？嗯，这是一个例子。呃，如果
someone likes cars, it's it's a actually
有人喜欢汽车，这其实是真的。
a great business. Like I know a
一家很棒的企业。就像我认识的
gentleman in Alabama that makes a lot of
阿拉巴马州一位收入颇丰的绅士
money doing that, right? For me it was
这样做是用钱，对吧？对我来说是
it was not great.
不太好。
&gt;&gt; So how important then is passion in this
那么，激情在其中究竟有多重要呢？
equation? Like how important it is for
方程？比如它对……有多么重要
for you to love the thing to be
让你爱上它。
successful at it in your view? I think
你认为他做得成功了吗？我认为
you need to fall in love with business
你需要爱上商业。
with commerce and if you can love
与商业有关，如果你能爱
entrepreneurship turning $1 into two and
创业精神将1美元变成2美元
that like if you could focus on that
如果你能专注于此的话……
being your passion then anything that
如果那是你的热情所在，那么任何事都行。
falls underneath that you should win at,
低于你应该获胜的水平，
right? But I I like to say
正确的？但我喜欢说
follow the profit. pro fit T. Um, until
追逐利润。专业健身 T。嗯，直到
you can afford to follow your passion,
你有能力追随自己的热情，
right? Because if we're trying to follow
正确的？因为如果我们试图遵循
our passion from day one, we're probably
从一开始我们就充满热情，我们可能
not ever going to get there because the
永远也到不了那里，因为
statistical likelihood that what we love
我们所爱之物的统计可能性是：
and what makes us money overlaps in the
而让我们赚钱的因素与此重叠
beginning is almost zero. So, ignore
起始值几乎为零。所以，忽略它
passion for a time. Try to build your
激情只持续了一段时间。尝试建立你的
passion around commerce. Um, and then
对商业充满热情。嗯，然后
start anything. And then once you're
开始做任何事。然后一旦你
able to have more passive income, then
能够获得更多被动收入，那么
start things that you're passionate
去做你充满热情的事情。
about like in the in the actual industry
就像在实际行业中一样
that you're passionate about.
你充满热情的事物。
&gt;&gt; Persistence.
坚持不懈。
Persistence is obviously going to create
持久性显然会创造
repetitions to like understand the
重复是为了理解
problem to learn more to, you know, so I
问题是，我想了解更多，你知道，所以我
wonder as it relates to passion and
惊奇与激情有关
persistence, they seem
他们似乎很执着。
&gt;&gt; sort of inextricably linked. Something
某种程度上来说是密不可分的。某物
I'm more passionate about, I'm more
我更热衷于，我更
likely to continue at even when the
即使在以下情况下，这种情况也可能继续下去：
rewards don't show up. Yeah, like my car
奖励没有显示出来。是啊，就像我的车
my car business, right? I had no passion
我的汽车生意，对吧？我毫无热情。
for cars and I had another business that
我还有另一项汽车生意，
was doing great. So, so I abandoned
一切都很好。所以，我放弃了
that. Um, but people think that like
那。嗯，但人们会这样想。
people sometimes look at themselves as
人们有时会把自己看作是
lazy or they're not a hard worker. And
他们要么懒惰，要么不勤奋。和
so they're just they're not confident
所以他们只是缺乏信心。
that they could do this. But there's
他们竟然能做到这一点。但是还有
like everyone is a hard worker. Everyone
就像每个人都很努力工作一样。每个人
on this planet has the same DNA that
这个星球上拥有相同DNA的生物
enables them to work hard. But the
使他们能够努力工作。但是
problem is what they're working on
问题在于他们正在研究什么。
probably gives them no energy, right?
可能根本无法给它们提供能量，对吧？
They're probably not passionate about
他们可能对这方面并不热衷。
it. So, what am I passionate about?
它。那么，我真正热爱的是什么呢？
Well, we got to we got to test
嗯，我们得测试一下
everything. We have to try new things.
一切。我们必须尝试新事物。
We have to take that curious question
我们必须认真对待这个令人好奇的问题。
and turn it into a business. Maybe
并将其发展成一项事业。或许
that's fun. Maybe it's not. Right? We
真有趣。也许并非如此。正确的？我们
need more surface area for finding what
需要更大的表面积来寻找什么
our passions actually are. Cuz we might
我们的热情确实如此。因为我们可能
think that like like I love woodworking,
我觉得就像我喜欢木工一样，
right? I don't have to build a business
正确的？我不需要自己创业。
around that cuz I love business, right?
大概就是因为我喜欢做生意，对吧？
So, I can build a business around
所以，我可以围绕它建立一个企业。
anything. But if I got super hung up on
任何事物。但如果我过于纠结于……
like I cannot make a profit from this
好像我不能从中获利似的
woodworking business um then I would
木工生意，嗯，那我就会
fail at entrepreneurship if I started
如果我开始创业，就会失败。
there, right? Whereas if I approached
就在那儿，对吧？而如果我接近
this from um the angle of all right, I
从这个角度来看，好吧，我
like woodworking. What else do I like?
比如木工。我还喜欢什么？
Maybe I like running, maybe I like
也许我喜欢跑步，也许我喜欢
cooking, maybe I like short form videos,
烹饪，或许我还喜欢短视频。
and I just start trying all those new
然后我就开始尝试所有这些新方法。
things. Then eventually I'm going to
事物。然后最终我会……
have enough surface area for testing
具有足够的表面积进行测试
that I'm going to find things where um
我会找到一些东西，嗯
you've heard of the eeky guy principle.
你一定听说过“书呆子原则”吧。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Right. So what you love, what you're
正确的。所以你所爱的，你是什么
good at, what the world needs, and what
擅长什么，世界需要什么，以及什么
you can charge for, right? The overlap
你可以收费，对吧？重叠
of that is the sweet spot. That's what's
这就是最佳平衡点。这就是……
scalable. That's what you can do until
可扩展的。这就是你能做的，直到……
you die. But if you get super hung up on
你死了。但如果你过于执着于……
that on day one, like I'm just not
第一天，我就感觉自己不像个正常人。
passionate about that, like you're never
对此充满热情，就像你从未如此。
going to find it. Like you're going to
去找找看。就像你要去……
be in that job forever. My career
永远做那份工作。我的职业生涯
follows the same same arc which is I
遵循相同的弧线，即 I
tried tons of things and then I built
尝试了很多方法，然后我搭建了
this marketing business and then that
这家营销公司，还有那家公司。
became more of a product business and
变得更像一家产品公司，
grew and I didn't love it. Like it
长大后，我并不喜欢它。喜欢
wasn't my passion to do um to help like
帮助别人并不是我的热情所在。
Coca-Cola sell more cans of Coke or like
可口可乐公司销售更多罐装可乐或类似产品
you know Uber sell more Ubers
你知道优步卖出更多优步车吗？
necessarily. That wasn't like my passion
一定。那不是我的热情所在。
in life. However, it taught me a bunch
在生活中。不过，它教会了我很多东西。
of skills
技能
&gt;&gt; which then in when I quit that business
后来，当我退出那家公司的时候
and I spent some time in psychedelics,
我曾花过一段时间体验迷幻剂，
DJing, building software, web 3, you
DJing、软件开发、Web 3、你
name it. Um I came out on the other side
说出它的名字。嗯，我从另一边出来了。
and could ask myself that guy question
我也可以问问自己那个人的问题。
which is of all the things that I have
这是我拥有的所有东西之一。
tried what is the thing that I would do
尝试了我会做的事
like really irrespective of money. Now I
真的，跟钱没关系。现在我
had that luxury to do that and actually
我有这样的奢侈条件，而且实际上
in 2020 the answer was this.
2020年的答案是这样的。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Like this was the answer. This answer
仿佛这就是答案。这个答案
was I I literally moved to London from
我当时真的从……搬到了伦敦
New York and found a place without
纽约，找到了一处没有
viewing it properly that looked like
仔细观察，它看起来像
this because I thought this would be a
因为我以为这会是一个
good podcast set and moved into that
不错的播客节目，然后就进入那个领域了。
place called Jack and then we started
一个叫杰克的地方，然后我们就开始了。
about five five years ago um doing doing
大约五年前，嗯，做着
this weekly
本周
&gt;&gt; and it's become a business off the back
这已经发展成一项副业了
of it.
它的。
&gt;&gt; But I didn't have that luxury at the
但我当时没有这种奢侈条件。
start. If I tried that from day one, I
开始。如果我从一开始就尝试那样做，我
wouldn't have had a the skills to know
原本不具备了解此事的技能。
how to scale an audience. Mhm.
如何扩大受众群体。嗯。
&gt;&gt; I wouldn't have had the flexibility to
我当时没有这样的灵活性。
buy all these cameras which cost like 50
买下所有这些相机，每台大概50美元。
grand or whatever at the start. Um so
一开始要盛大或其他什么。嗯，所以
and I do think some people sometimes get
而且我确实认为有些人有时会得到
that inverted.
颠倒了。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And you you're not distracted
是的。而且你不会分心。
anymore, right? You're not looking for
已经没有了吧？你不是在寻找
the next DJ thing or like you found it.
下一个DJ潮流，或者就像你发现的那样。
[clears throat] You're here right now.
[清嗓子] 你现在就在这里。
You're focused on scaling. It's like
你专注于规模化发展。就像
people get so hung up on focus or lack
人们太执着于专注力或缺乏专注力的问题了。
thereof and they just beat themselves up
于是他们就自责不已。
over it. But in my experience, like a
超过它。但以我的经验来看，就像
lack of focus is a signal that there's
注意力不集中是一个信号，表明存在……
something else out there, right? right?
还有其他东西，对吧？正确的？
Then maybe we shouldn't be focusing on
那么或许我们不应该把重点放在……
that thing cuz you've probably worked on
那东西，因为你可能已经研究过了。
things that had perfect product market
拥有完美产品市场的产品
fit and were just crushing and you
状态极佳，而且势不可挡，你
weren't thinking about starting a DJing
我们原本没打算开始做DJ。
business at that point,
当时的商业状况
&gt;&gt; right? You were all in on this one
正确的？你们全都参与其中了。
thing.
事物。
&gt;&gt; But in the times when you were working
但在你工作的时候
on something, you're like, "Maybe I'll
对某件事，你会想，“也许我会……”
try this. Maybe I'll try this." And you
试试这个。或许我会试试这个。”你
beat yourself up. You're like, "Oh, and
责备自己。你会想，“哦，而且
focus, focus, focus." Like, "Let's
集中注意力，集中注意力，集中注意力。”就像，“我们来……”
actually pay attention to those signals.
务必重视这些信号。
Why am I distracted from this thing?" So
为什么我会对这件事分心呢？
that's I don't know if that's just me
我不知道是不是只有我这样。
coping with my own ADHD or if that's
应对我自己的注意力缺陷多动症，或者如果那是……
actually a true principle, but I I try
这其实是一个真正的原则，但我会尽力尝试
to lend some credence to those signals
为了给这些信号增添一些可信度
of distraction that I get on a regular
我经常会遇到各种分心的事情
basis.
基础。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I have a a Sunday shelf,
是的，我有个周日特供架。
&gt;&gt; which is just a digital board on my
那只是我电脑上的一个电子白板。
Monday board where when I have ideas
星期一公告板上我会在上面写下我的想法
that like captivate me at 11:00 p.m. at
晚上11点，我竟然被这种东西吸引住了。在
night one night, instead of trying to
一天晚上，与其尝试……
act on them immediately, cuz I think I'm
立即采取行动，因为我认为我
in some respects like you, I put it on
在某些方面，我和你一样，把它放了进去。
the Sunday shelf.
周日书架。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. And um I wait and see.
嗯。我拭目以待。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; I wait and see how much it pulls at me
我等着看它对我有多大的吸引力。
to come off the shelf.
即将上市。
&gt;&gt; And then sometimes it comes off the
然后有时候它会脱落
shelf. I get a little bit of the way
架子。我稍微明白了这一点
down. I discover that actually there's
向下。我发现实际上还有
something I didn't realize. And then I
我之前没意识到这一点。然后我
quit. But then there's this, you know,
辞职。但还有一点，你知道，
when you think about the like the
当你想到类似的事情时
excitement arc of a new idea. You have
新想法产生的兴奋曲线。你有
the like initial surge of excitement
就像最初那股兴奋劲儿一样
like this is the best thing ever. I'm
这简直太棒了。我是
going to become a billionaire. Why has
即将成为亿万富翁。为什么有
no one ever thought of this before? And
以前没人想到过这一点吗？和
then you kind of get into it and you get
然后你就慢慢沉浸其中，然后你就明白了。
into that sort of valley of oh this
陷入那种“哦，该死”的低谷
is a terrible idea. I'm an idiot. Yep.
这是个糟糕的主意。我是个白痴。是的。
&gt;&gt; If I can come out of that valley, if if
如果我能走出那片低谷，如果
something pulls me up out of that
某种东西把我从那种状态中拉了出来。
valley, then I think it's worth
如果是在山谷里，那我认为就值得了。
pursuing.
追查中。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a good way of looking at
是的，这是一个很好的看待问题的角度。
it. The the valley of despair or
它。绝望之谷或
something that's what they call it.
他们就是这么称呼它的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Do you follow a similar sort of path
你是否也走着类似的道路？
with idea your ideas? It's funny cuz I
你有什么想法吗？这很搞笑，因为我
my kind of framework is
我喜欢的框架是
if I have an idea, am I thinking about
如果我有一个想法，我是在思考……
it still two weeks later? For whatever
两周后还是这样吗？无论如何
reason, that's just my timeline. Two
原因很简单，这只是我的时间线。二
weeks. I had an idea yesterday and I was
几周。我昨天有个想法，当时我……
at the airport. I was excited about it
在机场。我对此感到很兴奋。
and I was doing research. I like forgot
我当时正在做研究。我好像忘了
about it, right? Who cares, you know?
是吧？谁会在乎呢？
But I have ideas where I just cannot get
但我有些想法，却始终无法实现。
it out of my head and I'll see something
把这事从我脑子里赶走，我就会明白。
out there in the world that adds to the
世界上还有更多这样的东西
idea and I tell my friend about it and I
我有了这个想法，然后我把它告诉了我的朋友，然后我
I send these manic voicemails or these
我发送这些疯狂的语音留言或这些
manic voice notes to my friends about it
我疯狂地给朋友们发语音信息谈论这件事
and I'm still thinking about it 2 weeks
我还在思考这件事，已经两周了。
later. That's my signal that there's
之后。那是我发出的信号，表示有……
actually something here. Um,
这里面其实有点东西。嗯，
&gt;&gt; you used the word validating earlier on
你之前用过“验证”这个词。
when you're talking about these ideas
当你在谈论这些想法时
and I I think this is something that
我认为这是……
could really really help a lot of people
真的可以帮助很多人。
who have a lot of ideas is this idea of
有很多想法的人的想法是……
trying to validate your ideas as fast as
尽快验证你的想法
possible.
可能的。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; How might one validate an idea and can
如何验证一个想法？
you give me an example of an idea that
你给我举个例子，说明一个想法是
you have validated? What does validation
你已经验证过了吗？验证是什么？
mean?
意思是？
&gt;&gt; Mhm. [clears throat]
嗯。 [清嗓子]
Yeah. So, I like to see people get joy
是的。所以，我喜欢看到人们获得快乐。
from my product or service, right? Not
来自我的产品或服务，对吧？不是
just like, well, it's good. Like let's
感觉，嗯，挺好的。比如，我们……
say I'm selling a food product. It
假设我正在销售一种食品。它
tastes good. It's good. [clears throat]
味道不错。很好。 [清嗓子]
Okay, people might buy this, but I'm not
好吧，也许有人会买，但我不会。
going to have product market fit. I'm
实现产品市场契合。我是
going to be pushing a boulder up the
我要把一块巨石推上去
hill, right? But if people are like, "Oh
山坡，对吧？但如果人们这样想，“哦”
my gosh, this is the best thing I've
我的天哪，这是我见过最好的东西！
ever had. Where did you make this? How
曾经有过。这是你在哪里做的？如何
did you make this?" It lights up in
这是你做的吗？它亮了起来。
their face. That's an example of a
他们的脸。这是一个例子
validation in my case, right? Same
对我来说，这算是验证了，对吧？相同的
industry, food product, completely
工业、食品、完全
different reactions, right? So, one
不同的反应，对吧？所以，一个
specific example is um my wife has a
具体例子是，嗯，我妻子有一个
cookie bar business, right? Square
是做饼干店生意吗？正方形
cookies, and they're amazing. And we're
饼干，而且味道棒极了。而我们是
not trying to scale it. We don't want to
不打算扩大规模。我们不想
scale it. It's a way to teach our kids
缩放它。这是教导我们孩子的一种方式
entrepreneurship, and we love it. But
我们热爱创业。但
the best way to validate this was going
验证这一点的最佳方法是去
to our local farmers market and just
去我们当地的农贸市场，然后就
posting up and just giving people
发帖，然后给人们一些建议
samples and just watching them, right?
就看看样品，对吧？
What do they say versus how do they
他们说了什么，以及他们如何做。
react? And is it the same?
有反应吗？它们是一样的吗？
&gt;&gt; What do you mean by that?
你这话是什么意思？
&gt;&gt; Well, sometimes we try to use the
嗯，有时候我们会尝试使用
internet in places where it's it's not
在某些地方，互联网是不畅通的。
needful, right? She sold these online,
有必要吗？她把这些东西卖到了网上。
right? She shipped them to friends and
正确的？她把它们寄给了朋友。
family across the country. Like, they're
家人遍布全国各地。比如，他们是
great. We love them. Okay. I didn't see
伟大的。我们喜欢他们。好的。我没看到
you eat it. I don't know how you
你把它吃了。我不知道你
actually love it. Are you saying that
我真的很喜欢。你是说……
because you're my mom, right? Or you're
因为你是我的妈妈，对吗？或者你是
my friend. But when you solicit feedback
我的朋友。但当你征求反馈意见时
on your product or service in person,
亲自介绍您的产品或服务，
even if it's like an internet tool or an
即使它像一个互联网工具或一个
app, in person makes all the difference.
应用程序和面对面交流的效果截然不同。
You want to take note of what they say
你要记下他们说的话。
and take note of their body language and
并注意他们的肢体语言和
how they react when they experience your
当他们经历你的行为时会作何反应
product or service, right? And if all
是产品或服务，对吧？如果所有
three of those things overlap, then
这三件事有重叠之处。
either they're a psychopath and they're
要么他们是精神变态者，要么他们是……
just lying for no good reason or you
无缘无故撒谎，或者你
have something really special on your
在你的……上放一些特别的东西
hands. Uh, and so that's what we did
手。嗯，所以我们就这么做了。
with her cookie bar business. And um,
以及她的饼干店生意。嗯，
and they loved it. And you can do that
他们很喜欢。你可以这样做。
with any business. It doesn't have to be
任何企业。不一定非得如此
food.
食物。
&gt;&gt; And what does validation mean? is it's
验证究竟意味着什么？是的
checking if the market gives a
看看市场是否在乎
about the thing you're making as fast as
关于你正在制作的东西，速度要快得多
you can. Yeah. Yeah. Um I like to kind
你可以。是的。是的。嗯，我喜欢友善
of picture a you know a boulder up a
图片a你知道一块巨石向上
hill, right? And most people in their
山坡，对吧？大多数人
businesses, even businesses that are
企业，甚至包括那些
working, there are two steps forward,
工作中，有两步向前迈进，
one step back. Two steps forward, one
后退一步。向前两步，一步
step back. And that's okay. Like that's
后退一步。这样也没关系。就像那样
not a bad thing. But in my experience,
这不是坏事。但以我的经验来看，
5% of the time I'll have a business
5% 的时间里我会有生意
where the boulder is chasing me. Like
巨石在追赶我。喜欢
I'm trying to not die because this
我努力不让自己死掉，因为……
boulder's chasing me down a hill. And
一块巨石正追着我滚下山坡。和
that boulder in this case represents
在这种情况下，那块巨石代表着
customers demand, right? Like I can't
顾客有这样的需求，对吧？就像我不能
sleep because I'm fulfilling orders. I'm
因为我在忙着处理订单，所以没时间睡觉。我是
answering emails like I'm not getting
回复邮件的时候好像我根本没收到。
distracted by the next shiny object.
被下一个闪闪发光的东西吸引了注意力。
That is validation. That's product
这是验证。那是产品
market fit in my experience. You don't
根据我的经验，这符合市场需求。你没有
have to have that to launch. I don't
必须具备这个条件才能启动。我不
want people to misunderstand. Um but if
想让人们误解。嗯，但是如果
you have that, like you have something
你拥有那种感觉，就像你拥有了什么。
very special and you need to go all in
非常特别，你需要全力以赴。
on that thing. There was a book
就那东西。有一本书
published uh several years ago called
几年前出版的，名为
the lean startup which talks about this
精益创业理论也谈到了这一点。
idea of just like testing an MVP as
就像测试MVP一样，这个想法就像……
quick quick quickly as you possibly can.
尽快，尽可能快。
&gt;&gt; Can you explain that to the audience who
你能向观众解释一下吗？
probably have ideas but in their head
可能有一些想法，但都还停留在脑子里。
are thinking I've got to quit my job.
我觉得我得辞职了。
I'm going to have to raise money. I'm
我得筹集资金。我是
going to have to spend two to three
需要花费两到三个月
years building something to figure out
多年来一直在构建一些东西来弄明白
if this is a good idea or not. What is
这究竟是不是个好主意。什么是
the alternative approach that you adopt
你采取的替代方法
when you're trying to stress test an
当你试图对一个设备进行压力测试时
idea quickly?
快速想出主意？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, if I had to pick one tool, I
是的。所以，如果非要我选一个工具的话，我会选……
mean, it's one that one in four humans
也就是说，每四个人中就有一个是这种情况。
use every day, and it's Facebook, right?
每天都用，而且是Facebook，对吧？
You've got Facebook groups, you got
你有Facebook群组，你有
WhatsApp, um, Instagram, Facebook
WhatsApp，嗯，Instagram，Facebook
Marketplace, Facebook pages, uh,
Marketplace、Facebook 页面、呃，
Facebook ads, right? Let's just say
对吧？Facebook广告？这么说吧
there's six different meta products,
共有六种不同的元产品，
Facebook products. That's everything you
Facebook产品。这就是你全部的感受
need right there, right? Why why don't
就在那里，对吧？为什么？为什么不？
you give me an example of just a random
你给我举个随机的例子
business and I'll I'll tell you or the
生意上的事，我会告诉你或者
the audience how they could validate
观众如何验证
that with a Facebook product.
那是Facebook的产品。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Um
好的。嗯
I'm thinking of starting a
我正在考虑开始
creatine brand for women that has makes
专为女性设计的肌酸品牌
creatine taste good. Okay. All right.
肌酸味道不错。好的。好的。
Are we talking powder gummy? What form
我们说的是粉状软糖吗？什么形式
factor?
因素？
&gt;&gt; I don't know.
我不知道。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Well, let's let's try both. Okay.
好的。好，我们两种都试试吧。好的。
So, I'm going to do something that seems
所以，我打算做一件看似……的事情。
very non-obvious and probably won't
非常不明显，而且可能不会
work, but it's the lowest amount of
工作量，但这是最低的
friction. I'm going to take a
摩擦。我要去
description for that and I'm going to
关于那件事的描述，我将要……
use Nano Banana, Chad GBT, any of the AI
使用 Nano Banana、Chad GBT 或任何其他人工智能
image generators to come up with what
图像生成器用来生成什么
the product could look like, right? In
产品可能长这样，对吧？在
both a gummy form and a powder form.
既有软糖形式，也有粉末形式。
Okay. Then I'm going to go to Facebook
好的。然后我要去Facebook。
Marketplace. You You're just going to
市场。你你只是要
post a photo.
上传一张照片。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I'm just going to say like women's
是的。我只想说，就像女性的
creatine brand actually tastes good.
这个牌子的肌酸味道确实不错。
tastes good, right? Like, did you know
味道不错，对吧？你知道吗？
that creatine and improves cognitive
肌酸可以改善认知能力
function or whatever? Just your standard
功能或其他什么？就是标准配置。
pitch. I could even use AI to generate
沥青。我甚至可以使用人工智能来生成
it. It doesn't really matter at this
它。现在这其实并不重要。
point and I'm gonna post it to Facebook
我指着它，然后把它发到Facebook上。
marketplace simply because that's the
市场，仅仅因为那是市场。
lowest amount of friction to get some
尽可能减少摩擦力
level of validation or not, right?
验证程度如何？对吧？
Because in my experience, focus is
因为根据我的经验，专注力是
overrated and momentum is underrated,
被高估了，而动量被低估了。
right? And so you could have told me any
正确的？所以你本来可以告诉我任何事
idea and my first step that I tell you
想法和我的第一步，我要告诉你
to do is going to be something very very
要做的将会是一件非常非常……的事情。
low friction because I want you to get
低摩擦，因为我希望你得到
something back from the world, right?
这是来自世界的某种回应，对吧？
Cuz the most likely way to sell that
因为最有可能卖掉它的方法就是
product is with meta ads, right? But
该产品包含元广告，对吗？但
there's a lot of friction there. Like
那里存在很多摩擦。喜欢
it's it's hard to use. So you're going
它很难用。所以你要走了
to be like, "Okay, you're going to go
就像是，“好吧，你要走了
choose met ads and you're going to burn
选择 Met 广告，你就会吃亏。
out and you're going to have be on to
出去，你就得继续前进了。
something else by tomorrow." But that
明天之前会有别的办法。”但是
might be an amazing idea, right? So, I'm
这或许是个绝妙的主意，对吧？所以，我是
going to tell you to go to Facebook
我要告诉你去Facebook
Marketplace, even though people don't
市场，即使人们不
sell creatine on Facebook Marketplace.
在 Facebook Marketplace 上出售肌酸。
And then we're going to see, you know,
然后我们就会看到，你知道，
Facebook gives us like three stats when
Facebook 只给我们提供了三个统计数据
you post something to Facebook
你在 Facebook 上发布了一些内容
Marketplace clicks and then how many
市场点击量，然后是多少
people that reach out and then how many
有多少人主动联系我？
views. Okay, so I'm going to post one
浏览量。好的，那我发一个。
Facebook Marketplace ad for the gummies.
在 Facebook Marketplace 上投放软糖广告。
Different picture. It'll look like
不同的画面。它看起来会像这样
gummies. Um, basically same headline,
软糖。嗯，标题基本一样。
same benefit, same description. post to
相同的益处，相同的描述。发布到
Facebook in the same local market with
Facebook 与 同一本地市场
the same radius. Don't want to change
半径相同。不想改变
any variables. And then I'm going to
任何变量。然后我打算
open a Google sheet and I'm going to say
打开一个谷歌表格，然后我要说
how many views, how many clicks, how
浏览量、点击量、如何
many messages for that ad. Then I'm
该广告收到了很多信息。然后我
going to do the same thing. Take the
我也打算这样做。拿
same features, the same benefits,
相同的功能，相同的优势
different picture cuz this one's powder.
图片不一样，因为这个是粉末状的。
Post it in the same market with the same
把它发布到同一个市场，使用相同的
radius to Facebook Marketplace and have
到 Facebook Marketplace 的半径，并且有
a new column um views, reachouts, and um
新增一列，包括浏览量、联系量等。
clicks, right? And then I'm going to
点击，对吧？然后我打算
watch and I'm going to see what's
看着，我要看看会发生什么。
getting more clicks and I'm going to
获得更多点击量，我打算
know within two hours where there's more
两小时内就能知道哪里有更多
demand. Now, does that little sample
要求。现在，这个小样本
size indicate like what form factor I
尺寸表示我使用的外形尺寸
should go all in on? Not necessarily,
应该全力以赴吗？未必，
but it's something. It's a relevant data
但总比没有强。这是相关数据
point, right? There's not very likely to
没错吧？不太可能
be a large amount of people searching
会有很多人搜索
for creatine gummies on Facebook
在 Facebook 上搜索肌酸软糖
Marketplace, but it doesn't matter
市场，但这无关紧要
because there's two billion people using
因为有20亿人使用
it, right? So, we're just trying to
对吧？所以，我们只是想……
capture some of that traffic. So, I'm
截获部分流量。所以，我是
going to do that with two ads. And then
打算用两个广告来实现这个目标。进而
after a day or two, I'm going to boost
过一两天，我就要加速了。
those two ads, put $10 behind each of
那两则广告，每则广告背后都放10美元。
them to see how my results differ. Does
让他们看看我的结果有何不同。做
it make any difference? Do I get a lot
这有什么区别吗？我能得到很多吗？
more clicks, a lot more views, or is it
更多点击量，更多浏览量，还是另有其他原因？
just wasted? And then I'm going to um
就这么浪费了？然后我打算……
I'm going to probably post like 10 more
我大概还会再发十来条。
ads of like different photos, different
广告就像不同的照片，不同的
headings, different descriptions,
标题、不同描述、
different price points, and then put all
不同的价格点，然后把所有
those in a Google sheet and track it.
把这些数据记录在谷歌表格里并进行跟踪。
All right. Now, I have a lot of data.
好的。现在，我有很多数据。
Now, concurrently, so while I'm doing
现在，与此同时，所以当我在做……的时候
all these things, I'm going to go to
所有这些事情，我都要去……
Facebook groups and I'm going to join
我打算加入Facebook群组。
Facebook groups like moms who work out,
Facebook 群组，例如健身妈妈群
moms who love creatine, moms who love
喜欢肌酸的妈妈们，喜欢
rucking, ultrarunner moms, like healthy
负重行军、超级马拉松妈妈、喜欢健康
moms, whatever. I'm going to join all
妈妈们，随便吧。我要加入所有人
these groups and just start doing
这些小组，然后就开始行动吧。
searches for creatine, gummies, powders,
搜索肌酸、软糖、粉末、
price points, vendors, websites, and
价格点、供应商、网站和
just start like pulling pieces of data
就从提取数据片段开始吧
out of out of the atmosphere, right? and
脱离大气层，对吧？和
I'm gonna put that in my spreadsheet and
我要把它输入到我的电子表格里。
I want to wait till the Facebook
我想等到Facebook
marketplace tests are done. I want to do
市场测试已完成。我想做
that at the same time. Then I'm going to
与此同时。然后我打算
start learning Facebook ads because
开始学习Facebook广告，因为
everything I've told you to do so far
我之前吩咐你做的所有事情
takes like 2 hours. Let's say we have an
大概需要2个小时。假设我们有一个
afternoon to dedicate to this, right?
下午的时间可以用来做这件事，对吧？
Then I'm going to learn Facebook ads and
然后我要学习Facebook广告，
I'm going to watch a YouTube video
我要去看一个YouTube视频。
about, you know, how to get Facebook ads
关于如何投放 Facebook 广告
up in 10 minutes. How important is it to
10分钟后就好了。它有多重要？
understand Facebook ads and how long
了解 Facebook 广告及其效果持续时间
would it take me to get a sufficient
我需要多久才能获得足够的
understanding of Facebook ads? you could
对Facebook广告的了解程度如何？你可以
be proficient in a couple days if if you
如果你……几天之内就能熟练掌握。
had like one thing to sell and you just
你只有一样东西要卖，然后你就
wanted to go all in on that thing. Um,
想在那件事上全力以赴。嗯，
and you actually learned by launching
而你实际上是通过发布产品来学习的。
ads and not just learning, not just
广告，而不仅仅是学习，不仅仅是
endlessly watching YouTube videos, you
你不停地观看 YouTube 视频。
could be fairly proficient uh within a
在某个领域可能相当熟练
couple days easily. Do you think that's
轻松几天就能搞定。你觉得那是吗？
the skill everybody should have?
每个人都应该具备的技能？
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. I mean, Facebook ads are
绝对地。我的意思是，Facebook广告是
like the infinite money glitch. It's
比如无限金钱漏洞。它是
just like a a magic money machine. It's
简直就像一台神奇的印钞机。它是
the reason they're a trillion dollar
他们之所以价值万亿美元，原因就在于此。
company. Um, it's like a cheat code.
公司。嗯，这就像作弊码一样。
Yeah. It's a We should know Facebook ads
是的。这是我们应该了解的Facebook广告
like we know how to write emails. Like
好像我们都知道怎么写电子邮件似的。喜欢
we should know Facebook ads like we know
我们应该像了解Facebook广告一样了解它。
how to build websites or to do anything.
如何搭建网站或做任何事情。
It should be foundational.
它应该是基础性的。
H
H
I wonder how many people actually have
我想知道究竟有多少人拥有
that skill. Very few. That's why there
那项技能。极少。这就是为什么……
are so many ad agencies charging a lot
很多广告公司收费都很高。
of money.
钱。
&gt;&gt; And then so you've got the data back
这样你就拿回了数据。
into your spreadsheet on this creatine
将这份肌酸信息添加到你的电子表格中
situation. How do you then make a
情况。那么，你如何制作一个
decision whether this is something worth
决定这是否值得
pursuing?
继续？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Then I would go find like a a
是的。然后我会去找一个像a
c-acker that could
那个可能
&gt;&gt; it's a company that will take my idea
这是一家会采纳我想法的公司。
and put it into a physical form, right?
然后把它变成实物，对吧？
Um I'd find like a supplement company
嗯，我会找一家保健品公司。
that could actually make this and I
那确实有可能实现这一点，而我
would tell it roughly like what I'm
大概就是我的意思吧
thinking and then ask for samples and
思考片刻后，再索取样品。
then I would use those samples to go get
然后我会用这些样品去获取
feedback from people in person, right?
来自人们当面的反馈，对吧？
But I wouldn't get those samples until I
但我直到……才能拿到那些样品
got feedback from all these Facebook
从所有这些 Facebook 页面都获得了反馈
tests telling me what form factor, what
测试结果告诉我什么外形尺寸，什么
price point, what color, what flavor,
价格、颜色、口味
um, etc. And then I would go to a
嗯，等等。然后我会去……
farmers market and actually have people
农贸市场，而且真的有人。
try it. I've had so many founders speak
试试看。我听过很多创始人的演讲
to me and say, "Why didn't this
跟我说：“为什么这没有发生？”
particular ad that I ran on this
我在这上面投放的那个广告
platform work for me?" Maybe the copy
平台工作对我来说怎么样？也许是副本
wasn't good, the creative wasn't strong,
不好，创意不够强。
but usually the problem is they're not
但通常的问题是他们并非如此。
having the right conversation because
进行正确的对话，因为
that ad never reached the right person.
那则广告始终没有触达目标人群。
And if you're in B2B marketing, that is
如果你从事B2B营销，那就是
much of the game. And this is where
游戏的大部分时间。而这里就是
LinkedIn ads solves that problem for
LinkedIn 广告解决了这个问题。
you. Their targeting is ridiculously
你。他们的目标选择简直荒谬至极。
specific. You can target by job title,
具体的。您可以按职位名称进行筛选，
seniority, company size, industry, and
资历、公司规模、行业和
even someone's skill set. And their
甚至包括一个人的技能。以及他们的
network includes over a billion
网络包含超过十亿
professionals, about 130 million of them
专业人士，约有1.3亿人
are decision makers. So when you use
都是决策者。所以当你使用
LinkedIn ads, you're putting your brand
LinkedIn广告，就是在推广你的品牌
in front of the right people. And
在合适的人面前。和
LinkedIn ads also drive the highest B2B
LinkedIn 广告也带来了最高的 B2B 转化率。
return on ad spend across all ad
所有广告支出回报率
networks in my experience. If you want
以我的经验来看，网络。如果你想
to give them a try, head over to
想试试看吗？请前往
linkedin.com/diary.
linkedin.com/diary。
And when you spend $250 on your first
当你第一次消费满 250 美元时
LinkedIn ads campaign, you'll get an
LinkedIn广告活动，您将获得
extra $250 credit from me for the next
我额外提供 250 美元信用额度，供下次使用。
one. That's linkedin.com/diary.
一。那是 linkedin.com/diary。
Terms and conditions apply.
须遵守相关条款和条件。
&gt;&gt; I've heard you say that there's various
我听你说过有很多种
types of entrepreneurs. There's the sort
企业家的类型。有那么一种。
of zero to one entrepreneur who's good
从零到一位优秀的创业者
at starting things. There's the
开始做事情。那里有
maintainer. And then there's the
维护者。然后还有……
finisher.
终结者。
&gt;&gt; Which one are you?
你是哪一个？
&gt;&gt; I'm a starter. Yeah. Through and
我是首发球员。是的。通过和
through. I
通过。我
if I stay in a business too long, it all
如果我在一个行业待得太久，一切就会结束。
falls apart, right? Just objectively.
崩溃了，对吧？客观地说。
So, I need to hand off the reigns at a
所以，我需要把控制权交出去。
very specific point or I need to have a
非常具体的观点，或者我需要一个
partner from the outset that knows me,
从一开始就了解我的合作伙伴，
my strengths and my weaknesses um that
我的优点和缺点，嗯……
just takes over at a certain point. So,
在某个特定时刻，它就接管了一切。所以，
I like to say there are starters,
我喜欢说，这里有一些开场白。
maintainers, and finishers. A starter
维护者和完成者。开胃菜
could be called like a visionary and not
可以称他为有远见的人，而不是
as like a backhanded compliment way, but
就像一种反讽式的恭维，但是
someone an idea guy, right? Not just a
他是个很有点子的人，对吧？不仅仅是
business idea guy, but like a marketing
有商业想法的人，但像个营销人员
idea guy. Uh, let's change the subject
出主意的人。呃，我们换个话题吧。
line to this idea guy. Like a an idea
给这个想出主意​​的人打电话。就像一个想法
machine, right? That's a visionary. And
是机器，对吧？那真是个有远见的人。和
then you have the maintainer, which
然后还有维护者，
would be an operator. That's a guy that
会是一名操作员。那家伙
just wakes up every day and loves
每天醒来就喜欢
tweaking little things, making small
调整一些小细节，做一些小改动
improvements. uh process oriented,
改进。呃，流程导向型，
someone that loves growing something and
喜欢种植植物的人
just fixing little problems all day,
整天都在修修补补，解决各种小问题。
right? And then you have a finisher,
正确的？然后你还有一个终结技，
which is like a deal guy, right? That's
这就像个做交易的人，对吧？那是
the guy that's a super connector. Uh he
这个人很擅长人脉拓展。呃，他
likes to, oh, you need to talk to Barry.
喜欢，哦，你需要和巴里谈谈。
And then he calls him, he connects them,
然后他给他打电话，把他们联系起来，
and like he just gets a lot of energy
他好像精力特别充沛。
from connecting deals, coming up with
从促成交易，到提出
creative deals for an exit, for a sale,
创造性的退出或出售方案
putting people together, hiring the
将人们聚集在一起，招聘
right people, um seeing something to its
没错，是这些人，嗯，看到了一些东西。
completion. Um, but I'm definitely in
完成。嗯，但我肯定会参加。
the first camp.
第一营地。
&gt;&gt; Is it possible to be all three?
有可能同时具备这三种特质吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. When you're all three, you're Mark
是的。当你同时具备这三点时，你就是马克。
Zuckerberg. I mean, truly, like you
扎克伯格。我是说，真的，就像你
start something from scratch and you see
从零开始，你会发现
it to a trillion dollars. Um, there's
使其价值达到万亿美元。嗯，有
been like I think there have been three
我觉得好像已经有三个了。
people on the planet that have brought
地球上带来这一切的人们
something from zero to a trillion.
介于零到万亿之间的某个数值。
Jensen Wang, Nvidia, um, Elon Musk, and
Jensen Wang、Nvidia、嗯、埃隆·马斯克，还有
Mark Zuckerberg. I think like even Bill
马克·扎克伯格。我觉得比尔也一样
Gates, even Steve Jobs, I might be
盖茨，甚至史蒂夫·乔布斯，我可能
wrong. Yeah. But even Steve Jobs got out
错误的。是的。但就连史蒂夫·乔布斯也逃脱了。
long before they hit a trillion market
早在它们达到万亿美元市场之前很久
cap.
帽。
&gt;&gt; But a billion, a lot of [clears throat]
但是十亿，很多[清嗓子]
people get zero to a billion.
人们的财富可以从零增长到十亿。
&gt;&gt; That's not nothing. Also very
那可不是小事。也非常
impressive. But when you get all three,
感人的。但当你同时拥有这三者时，
that's what you get.
这就是你得到的。
&gt;&gt; One of the things that I find really
我发现的其中一件事是……
interesting about your story is you
你的故事最吸引我的地方在于……
you've started what is it 75 80
你已经开始了，那是什么？75 80
businesses.
企业。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. When I speak to people like Kevin
嗯。当我与像凯文这样的人交谈时
Olirri who have worked with some of the
奥利里曾与一些人合作过
greatest entrepreneurs to ever live like
史上最伟大的企业家们是如何生活的
Steve Jobs and he's [clears throat] very
史蒂夫·乔布斯，他（清了清嗓子）非常
familiar with Elon Musk, they talk to me
他们熟悉埃隆·马斯克，他们跟我说话。
about focus.
关于专注。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And he says to me that the great thing
他对我说，最伟大的事
about Steve Jobs is he was 80% signal
关于史蒂夫·乔布斯，有一点是他80%都在传递信号。
and 20% noise. I.e. 80% of his time he
噪音为 20%。 IE。他80%的时间都在……
was focused on the most important thing
专注于最重要的事
and he was brutal about not entertaining
他对待招待客人毫不留情。
anything else. M
还要别的吗。 M
&gt;&gt; Johnny Ives has famously said that the
约翰尼·艾夫斯曾说过一句名言：
one thing Steve Jobs was most known for
史蒂夫·乔布斯最出名的一件事
is his remarkable ability to focus. He
他惊人的专注力。他
would literally ask you what have you
他会直接问你有什么
said no to in order to focus on the most
为了专注于最重要的事，他拒绝了。
important thing.
重要的事情。
&gt;&gt; Uh I think about Mark Zuckerberg and his
嗯，我想到了马克·扎克伯格和他的
unbelievable ability to focus. I
惊人的专注力。我
remember uh several people at Meta but
记得Meta公司有几个人，但是
also I think it's a public story telling
而且我认为这是一种公开的叙事方式。
me that when he realized he was late to
当他意识到自己迟到时，我告诉他
mobile he refused to take any meetings
他拒绝在手机上参加任何会议。
about anything other than mobile like
除了移动设备之外的任何东西，比如
extreme levels of focus.
极高的专注力。
&gt;&gt; And then Kevin Olirri from Shark Tank
然后是《创智赢家》（Shark Tank）的凯文·奥利里。
said the same to me about Elon Musk. He
他也曾对我说过关于埃隆·马斯克的同样话。他
says Elon Musk is the only person that I
他说埃隆·马斯克是唯一一个……
think operates close to 100% signal
认为信号强度接近 100%。
which is he and I interviewed Walter
就是他，我和沃尔特采访了他。
Isaac and his biographer and he said
艾萨克和他的传记作者，他说
Elon will sit in a meeting and if people
埃隆会参加会议，如果人们
aren't talking about something that is
我们不是在谈论某件事。
the most important thing he'll
他最看重的是什么？
completely zone out and then the minute
完全走神，然后是那一分钟
he hears something that he considers to
他听到了一些他认为是……
be the most important thing it's like he
成为最重要的事，就像他
snaps into reality and he takes control
他猛然回过神来，掌控了局面。
and he's deep into the detail and I it
他非常注重细节，而且我……
sits in contradiction to a lot of the
这与很多……相矛盾
the narrative of like lots of side
就像很多旁观者一样的叙事
hustles, lots of businesses, do as many
忙碌的生意，很多生意，尽可能多地做。
things as you can. How do you but you've
尽你所能。你怎么能这样，但你已经
both kind of you know you've managed to
两种情况你都知道你已经设法
create a life for yourself where you're
创造属于你自己的生活，在那里你
you're a millionaire and you're free in
你是个百万富翁，而且你自由自在
that regard
就此而言
&gt;&gt; but when I look at the biggest companies
但当我审视那些最大的公司时，我发现它们
in the world there's this like there
世界上有这样的地方
appears to be obsessive focus.
似乎是过度专注。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; I love that question. I I think that all
我喜欢这个问题。我认为所有这些
else equal the guy who focuses more is
否则，专注力更强的人就是
more likely to be a billionaire. But
更有可能成为亿万富翁。但
back to momentum, right? The person that
又回到正轨了，对吧？那个人
keeps and has and mo maintains momentum
保持并拥有和维持势头
and has gets energy from what they do,
并从自己的工作中获得能量。
they're more likely to be a millionaire
他们更有可能成为百万富翁
by the average than the average person,
平均而言，比普通人要高，
right? I I genuinely have no desire to
正确的？我真的没有这个意愿
be a billionaire. Genuinely, if I get
成为亿万富翁。说真的，如果我得到
there, cool. But I don't want to leave
好了，酷。但我不想离开
my kids tens of millions of dollars
我的孩子们有数千万美元
anyway. I know where I get most of my
反正。我知道我的大部分收入来自哪里
energy from. I have a lot of surface
来自……的能量。我有很多表面
area for this. I've tried the focus.
这片区域。我试过集中注意力。
I've tried having a board. I don't want
我试过用电路板。我不想
any of that. Genuinely, I don't. Right.
任何一种。说实话，我没有。正确的。
So, if my life with hyperfocused Chris
所以，如果我和高度专注的克里斯的生活……
looks like billion-dollar exits, uh,
看起来像是价值十亿美元的退出交易，嗯。
reporting to a board, uh, being chairman
向董事会汇报工作，呃，担任董事长
of the board, being CEO, um, sitting in
董事会成员，担任首席执行官，嗯，坐在
meetings all day, that's miserable
整天开会，太痛苦了。
Chris, right? And if I'm not going to,
是克里斯吧？如果我不打算去，
if I don't want to leave a ton of money
如果我不想留下很多钱的话
to my kids anyway, then why am I making
反正对我的孩子们来说是这样，那我为什么要这么做呢？
Chris miserable so my fourth great
克里斯很痛苦，所以我的第四大伟大
grandkids can be rich instead of just my
我的孙辈们可以富有，而不仅仅是我的。
second great grandkids? Like that's
第二代曾孙？就像那样
that's genuinely how I look at it. I'm
我的确就是这么看的。我是
one of my superpowers is my my long-term
我的超能力之一是我的长期……
perspective, right? I think of things on
从另一个角度来看，对吧？我想到一些事情
an eternal scale. And if I have to have
永恒的尺度。如果我必须……
a miserable life so my kids in year 2300
2300 年，我的孩子们将过着悲惨的生活。
can still be wealthy, forget that. Like
别忘了，你还是可以变得富有的。喜欢
I don't I don't I don't want them to
我不想，我不想，我不想让他们
have all that money anyway, you know? So
反正你手头有很多钱，你知道的。所以
I want to live an awesome life where I'm
我想过上精彩的生活，在那里我可以……
a good and present father. And to me
一位好父亲，一位尽职尽责的父亲。对我来说
that looks like focusing less, not more.
这看起来像是减少了专注力，而不是增加了。
What if you focused for the next 10
如果你专注于接下来的10个月呢？
years? You made it to a billion dollars
年？你赚到了十亿美元。
on one thing
一件事
&gt;&gt; and then because you've done that you
然后因为你做了那件事，你
can take even more sort of experimental
可以采取更多实验性的方法。
bets
赌注
&gt;&gt; with higher risk and more enjoyment and
风险更高，乐趣更多
more sort of pleasure ccentric bets over
更多类型的快乐古怪赌注
the next 40 50 60 years of the rest of
接下来的40、50、60年，其余的人
your life.
你的人生。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I just don't think that that juice
是的，我只是觉得那种果汁
would be worth the squeeze. I think that
值得一试。我认为
those bigger bets that I take will just
我下的那些大注只会……
amount to more meetings and more travel
这意味着更多的会议和更多的旅行
and more time away from my kids. And I
这样我就有更多时间远离孩子了。我
don't like it might sound controversial
不喜欢的话可能会引起争议
like I'm I'm not trying to change the
就像我一样，我并不是想改变什么。
world. Like I want to help people start
世界。我想帮助人们起步
businesses and I can do that with my
我的企业，我可以用我的
iPhone. Uh and that will change the
iPhone。嗯，那将会改变……
world, right? But I'm not trying to
世界，对吧？但我并不是想……
solve world hunger. I think that's
解决世界饥饿问题。我认为那是
someone else's problem to solve. And so
那是别人的问题，需要解决。所以
I I just want to be a good dad and work
我只想做一个好爸爸，好好工作。
on really cool things. And it's been a
一些很酷的东西。而且一直以来都是如此
it's been a grind to get here, right?
走到今天这一步很不容易，对吧？
Like I've had more years with zero
就像我经历过更多零年一样
income than I've had up years, right?
比我过去几年的收入都高，对吧？
But my up years have more than
但我的上半身经历远不止于此。
compensated for my down years. So what
弥补了我人生低谷的岁月。所以呢
you're looking at today is the end
你今天看到的，就是终点。
result of 17 years of a lot of testing.
经过17年的大量测试，最终取得了成果。
Like a very patient wife that was
就像一位非常有耐心的妻子
unquestioning and unwavering and
毫不质疑、毫不动摇的
extremely loyal, which I could not have
极其忠诚，这是我无法想象的。
done it without. Um, and so there were a
没有做也做到了。嗯，所以当时……
lot of periods in my life where I beat
我生命中有很多时期我都战胜了
myself up over that lack of focus. I
我因为注意力不集中而感到懊恼。我
went and got my MBA because of my lack
因为我缺乏……，所以我去读了MBA。
of focus. I finished my undergrad
专注。我完成了本科学习。
because of my lack of focus. Like how
因为我注意力不集中。比如如何
getting a full-time job has never really
找到一份全职工作从来都不是件容易的事。
been off the table until the last five
直到最近五年才被提上日程。
or so years. So I've I've never been
大约几年。所以我从来没有……
unwilling to get a job or to focus. U
不愿找工作或集中精力。 U
and I probably did it the hard way,
我可能走了条弯路，
honestly. Um, but I'm to the point now
诚实地。嗯，但我现在说到重点了。
where I don't feel the need to focus all
在那里，我感觉没有必要集中精力。
on one thing. Did you ever feel guilty
就一件事而言。你是否曾感到过内疚
because of the situation you put your
因为你所处的境地
family or your partner in?
家人还是伴侣？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
More than once. Yeah. More than many
不止一次。是的。比许多人
times.
次数。
Give me an example. I spent
请举个例子。我花了
I spent 18 months working on a project
我花了18个月时间参与一个项目。
um
嗯
that had no cash flow along the way with
一路走来，它都没有现金流。
the hope of a big payout. Um, and we
希望能获得巨额回报。嗯，我们
were making no income, right? And I was
我们没有收入，对吧？而我当时
focused on this one thing. And that is
专注于这一件事。就是这样。
kind of the downside of focus is if you
专注的弊端之一在于，如果你
focus on the wrong thing, it can really
如果把注意力放在错误的事情上，真的会很危险。
come back to bite you, right? But to me,
最终会反噬自身，对吧？但对我而言，
this was objectively the right thing. It
客观来说，这是正确的做法。它
was showing all the signals it was
它显示出了所有信号。
growing. Um, we we had like a few rental
生长。嗯，我们当时有一些出租房。
homes, we had some assets, and I was
我们有房产，我们有一些资产，而我当时
selling those things so my family could
卖掉那些东西，这样我的家人就能……
maintain their quality of life, right?
维持他们的生活质量，对吗？
So I felt guilty but I was also
所以我感到内疚，但我也
insulating them from feeling the the
隔绝它们，使它们感觉不到
pinch that I was feeling in the office,
我在办公室里感觉到的那种刺痛感，
right? And then at the end of that
正确的？然后，在最后……
experiment it all went to zero. I was
实验结果全部归零。我当时
out money, I was out time, I was out
没钱了，没时间了，我出局了
everything. And I felt I felt very
一切。我感觉我感觉非常
guilty. That was one one example. Um
有罪的。那只是一个例子。嗯
but thankfully like we we didn't have to
但值得庆幸的是，和我们一样，我们不必如此。
sell our house. We didn't have to do
卖掉我们的房子。我们不必这样做。
anything drastic. And what that looked
任何极端措施。而那看起来
like at home was dad was quiet more
就像在家一样，爸爸更安静了。
often than not. Dad was grumpy more
往往如此。爸爸更爱发脾气了。
often than not, but dad wasn't really
大多数时候是这样，但爸爸其实并不是。
talking freely and openly about the
自由、公开地谈论
things he was going through because he
他经历的这些事情是因为他
was trying to, you know, put on a brave
当时我努力装出一副勇敢的样子。
face and insulate um the family from
面对并隔离家人
that. Even when my wife was begging to
那。即使我妻子苦苦哀求
know more to get more out of me, I just
知道更多才能更好地发挥我的潜力，我只是
if I talk about stressors, then it
如果我谈论压力源，那么
becomes more stressful to me often
这让我经常感到压力更大。
times. So, I just keep it in.
次数。所以，我就一直把它留着。
&gt;&gt; I find the same. I think my partner
我也这么觉得。我觉得我的伴侣
understands this of me and I tried to
他理解我这一点，我也试着……
explain to her that I don't like talking
跟她解释一下，我不喜欢说话。
about the stress because
压力很大
&gt;&gt; in this environment you're it's actually
在这种环境下，你实际上是
d-stressing me from not having to
不必为此感到压力
explain and conversate about it.
解释并讨论它。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; So, which is a bit of a paradox because
所以，这有点自相矛盾，因为
then they don't really understand.
那他们就真的不明白了。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And if they don't understand, they might
如果他们不理解，他们可能会
misunderstand. Misunderstandments might
误解。误会可能
lead to arguments and the arguments
导致争论，而这些争论
create stress and then you're going to
制造压力，然后你就会
have to tell them in some sort of like
必须以某种方式告诉他们
argument what's going on.
争论到底发生了什么。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. I've lived that for sure. I
是的。是的。我肯定经历过那种事。我
don't know how to navigate that, but but
不知道该怎么操作，但是
it's definitely true that me going
我去
through something in work and then
通过工作中的某些事情，然后
having to come home and like go through
不得不回家，然后经历这一切。
it for another hour to someone else and
再花一个小时把它交给别人。
stress them out potentially.
可能会给他们带来压力。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Doesn't feel like the right approach.
感觉这不是正确的方法。
&gt;&gt; No, but I don't know what the right
不，但我不知道正确的是什么。
approach is because they they have a
之所以采取这种方法，是因为他们拥有
right to know about it as well, right?
我也有权知道这件事，对吧？
&gt;&gt; I think we just need an outlet whether
我认为我们只是需要一个发泄渠道，无论
it's a friend that kind of understands
这是个有点理解我的朋友。
or someone else that,
或者其他人，
&gt;&gt; you know, is in our space that we can
你知道，在我们能够的空间里
just talk to about the situation. I
跟对方谈谈情况。我
think having no outlet is also bad.
我觉得没有插座也很糟糕。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And I'm I'm guilty of that. I I
是的。我承认我犯了这样的错误。我 我
find a lot of joy in my work and so I I
我从工作中获得了许多快乐，所以我……
don't look at it as work often, but it's
不要经常把它看作工作，但它确实是。
still work, right? Like it's still
还能用吗？就像仍然如此
taxing. Um so I need to be better about
征税。嗯，所以我需要在这方面做得更好。
having an outlet.
有插座。
&gt;&gt; Have you developed a new relationship
你发展出一段新的关系了吗？
with rejection and failure because, you
因为你遭遇了拒绝和失败，所以你
know, starting 80 odd businesses, you
你知道，创办了 80 多家企业，你
must have dealt with a lot of failure.
肯定经历过很多次失败。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And and how does that feed into
那么，这又如何影响呢？
everything we're talking about today?
我们今天讨论的所有事情？
Oh man, [sighs] I would I don't know
哦，唉，我不知道
where I'd be without rejection and
如果我没有遭到拒绝，我就不会这样了。
failure. Um I'm not good at sales. So if
失败。嗯，我不擅长销售。所以如果
anyone's watching this and like I can't
有人在看这个吗？我简直……
start a business, business is all sales.
开办企业，企业就是销售。
Like you don't have to be good at sales.
好像你不一定要擅长销售。
I'm not good at sales. I I can't think
我不擅长销售。我无法思考
of a business that where I had to rely
一家我必须依赖的企业
on like early customers coming from
就像早期客户一样
friends and family cuz I cared a lot
朋友和家人，因为我非常关心他们。
about what people thought. I didn't want
关于人们的想法。我不想
to post my side hustle number 37 to
发布我的第37个副业
Facebook cuz I just thought my friends
Facebook，因为我觉得我的朋友们
would roll their eyes. So I created this
他们会翻白眼。所以我创建了这个
stupid constraint for me where like I
对我来说，这是一个愚蠢的限制，就像我
had to launch things without the help of
不得不独自启动项目
my ever willing friends and family
我一直以来都非常乐于助人的朋友和家人
because I was too prideful, right? So I
因为我太骄傲了，对吧？所以，我
I advise against that first of all.
首先，我不建议这样做。
Second [snorts] of all, um I served a
其次（嗤笑）首先，嗯，我服务了一个
mission for my church. I went to Eastern
我为教会所做的使命。我去了东部
Europe for two years and I knocked doors
我在欧洲待了两年，挨家挨户敲门拜访。
in Hungarian for two years straight. I
连续两年用匈牙利语学习。我
approached people on the street in
在街上接近人们
freezing weather wearing a big Russian
寒冷的天气，穿着一件大号俄罗斯外套
hat. Like I got rejected tens of
帽子。我好像被拒绝了几十次
thousands of times over the course of
在漫长的过程中，发生了数千次
two years being an introvert, staying an
两年内向生活，一直保持着
introvert, still an introvert, still bad
内向者，依然是内向者，依然很糟糕
at sales, still hating sales today at
即使在今天，我仍然讨厌销售。
age 38, right? But that like changed me
38岁，对吧？但那件事改变了我
as a man, as a person, right? That
作为男人，作为一个人，对吧？那
rewired my brain to just realize that
重新调整我的大脑，让我意识到这一点。
every no is closer to a yes. If my
每一个“不”都让“是”更近一步。如果我的
conversion rate is 0.1%, I got to talk
转化率只有0.1%，我得说点什么。
to a thousand people and I will surely
对一千个人来说，我肯定会
get a conversion. If I talk to a
获取转换结果。如果我和一个
thousand and I don't get a conversion,
一千美元，但我无法进行转换。
then I'm going to get two conversions by
然后我将通过以下方式获得两个转换结果：
the time I get to 2,000, statistically
统计上来说，当我达到2000的时候
speaking. So, I just need to keep
请讲。所以，我只需要继续
getting rejected. Um, and that changed
被拒绝。嗯，后来情况发生了变化。
everything for me. I think it's super
一切都是为了我。我觉得它超级棒
underrated to give kids a job in like
低估了给孩子们提供类似工作的价值
cold sales.
冷销售。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. It's what I did when I was 16 till
嗯。那是我16岁时做的事，直到
19. Sounds like it's what you did
19. 听起来像是你做的。
&gt;&gt; as a young man. Are your kids going to
年轻的时候。你的孩子将来会……
do that? Yeah, hopefully. And two of my
这样做吗？是啊，但愿如此。还有我的两个
kids are introverts, two are
孩子们都是内向的，其中两个是
extroverted, but uh they will they are
外向，但是呃，他们会的，他们是
selling like they already have
卖得好像他们已经卖出去了一样
businesses, little side hustles here and
这里有一些生意和小副业。
there. Um but I am encouraging them to
那里。嗯，但我鼓励他们这样做
go on missions and to do selling because
去执行任务和进行销售，因为
it's it's the fastest way to learn. Like
这是最快的学习方法。喜欢
it's the fastest way to test. If I talk
这是最快的测试方法。如果我说话
to a thousand people, then I can have a
如果能有上千人，那我就可以……
thousand different approaches and if my
上千种不同的方法，如果我的
conversion rate is 0.1%. Um, I'm going
转化率为0.1%。嗯，我要走了
to get that to 5% over time because I'm
为了随着时间的推移将这个比例提高到 5%，因为我
able to test and iterate and and pivot
能够测试、迭代和调整
based on all that feedback I get.
基于我收到的所有反馈。
&gt;&gt; What have you learned about team
你对团队有什么新的认识？
building and business partners through
通过建立和发展业务伙伴关系
this process? What advice would you give
这个过程？你会给出什么建议？
to someone who's sat there alone
对一个独自坐在那里的人来说
listening to this right now? Do they
你现在正在听这个吗？他们会吗？
need a business partner? If they do,
需要商业伙伴吗？如果他们真的这么做了，
who, how, what? Oh [sighs] man. Um,
谁？如何？什么？唉，真是的。嗯，
usually people don't need a business
通常人们并不需要一家企业。
partner. Um, if you look at the stats on
伙伴。嗯，如果你看一下统计数据……
like business failure rates with
例如企业倒闭率
companies that have co-founders, it's
拥有联合创始人的公司，就是这样。
significantly higher than companies that
远高于那些公司
have solo founders. We see the
由单人创始人创立。我们看到
survivorship bias examples, right? The
幸存者偏差的例子，对吧？这
the Apples and the a lot of companies we
苹果公司和我们很多公司
can look at that had two co-founders
可以看看那家有两个联合创始人的公司
that that won, but nobody talks about or
那场胜利，但没人谈论或
writes about the 90 60 80% of companies
撰写关于90%、60%、80%的公司
that fail with co-founders. Think about
与联合创始人失败。想想
it this way. When we get married, we'll
就这样。当我们结婚的时候，我们会
spend years talking about our potential
多年来一直在谈论我们的潜力
plans, like big goals, like where do we
计划，比如远大目标，比如我们该去哪里
want to live? How many kids do we have?
想活下去吗？我们有几个孩子？
My wife and I wanted seven kids when we
我和妻子想要七个孩子，当时我们
got married. We settled on four, right?
结婚了。我们最终决定是四个，对吧？
It changed over time. It took years to
随着时间的推移，它发生了变化。这花了数年时间
change. We realized kids are actually
改变。我们意识到孩子们实际上是
freaking hard, right? And we So then
难到爆，对吧？所以，我们就这样
we're like, where do we live? What kind
我们当时就想，我们到底住在哪儿？什么类型的
of a house do we want? We spend all this
我们想要什么样的房子？我们花了所有这些
time, maybe while we're engaged, maybe
或许在我们订婚期间，或许会有时间。
while we're dating, maybe after we're
在我们约会期间，或许在我们……之后
married. But those are big decisions,
已婚。但这些都是重大决定。
right? But when we choose a business
正确的？但当我们选择一家企业时
partner, we go get avocado toast
伙伴，我们去吃牛油果吐司吧。
together and we're like, "50-50, cool,
我们俩一起说：“五五开，酷。”
sounds good. Let's do this." You know,
听起来不错。我们开始吧。”你知道，
I'll get the doc signed. It's like, who
我会去把文件签好。就像，谁
is that guy? You might have even known
是他吗？你甚至可能知道
him your whole life, but who is he as a
你一生都和他在一起，但他究竟是谁？
business partner or as a business
商业伙伴或作为企业
person? I just I feel like business
人？我只是觉得这像是在做生意。
partnerships are significantly harder
建立合作关系要困难得多。
than marriages even. But we put 99% less
甚至比婚姻还要糟糕。但我们减少了99%。
thought into like the structure of
思考就像结构一样
things. And that's a giant failure that
事物。那真是一次巨大的失败。
I've made over and over again. What do
我已经做了好几遍了。什么
you wish someone had said to you in the
你希望有人曾经对你说过
situations where it didn't work out with
有些情况下，这种方法并不奏效。
business partners or really like across
商业伙伴或非常喜欢
the board? Because I I read that you'd
董事会？因为我读到过你会
had what, seven business partners? It
他有多少个商业伙伴？七个？它
says that I've had like 15.
他说我已经有15个了。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, in those 15 occasions, what is
好的。那么，在这15次事件中，什么情况是……
the advice you wish someone had given
你希望有人当初给你的建议
you before you engaged in those business
在你从事这些业务之前
relationships? Yeah. Well, what do they
关系？是的。那么，他们做什么呢？
say about dating? It's like be a be a
谈谈约会？就像成为……
good like the best way to find a good
好就像找到好东西的最佳方法
spouse is to be a good spouse. Best way
配偶应该做一个好配偶。最佳方法
to find a good girlfriend. You know what
找到一个好女朋友。你知道吗
I'm saying? You've got to learn more
我的意思是？你需要了解更多
about yourself before you partner with
在与人合作之前，请先了解自己。
someone else. Most people have no idea
他人。大多数人对此一无所知
like who they are as a business person
比如他们作为商人是什么样的人
or as an entrepreneur when they partner.
或者作为合伙人，以企业家的身份出现。
They don't know what their strengths are
他们不知道自己的优势是什么。
or their weaknesses are. They sure don't
或者说，他们的弱点是……他们当然不会。
know what the other guys strengths or
了解对方的优势或
weaknesses are. So, I suggest people
弱点是……所以我建议人们
solo found things to start to learn more
独自一人时，我发现了一些可以开始学习的东西。
about themselves. Are they a visionary?
关于他们自己。他们是富有远见的人吗？
Are they an integrator, starter,
他们是整合者、创业者吗？
maintainer, finisher? Who are they? And
维护者，完成者？他们是谁？和
then when they want to jump into another
然后当他们想跳到另一个时
thing, because inevitably if we launch
这件事，因为不可避免地，如果我们发射
one thing, we're going to launch more.
有一件事，我们将推出更多产品。
they know more about what to look for in
他们更清楚应该寻找什么。
a partner. Um, and they can optimize for
一位合伙人。嗯，他们可以针对以下方面进行优化：
that. What about equity?
那。那么公平性呢？
Yeah. I mean, 50/50 is the old standby,
是的。我的意思是，五五开是老一套了。
right? Um, could you imagine if you like
正确的？嗯，你能想象如果你喜欢的话……
you go on a first date and it's like,
你第一次约会，感觉就像……
how many kids do you want? Four. Okay,
你想要几个孩子？四、好的，
we'll have four. We'll get married and
我们会有四个。我们会结婚的。
that's how many we will have. Uh, no
我们将拥有这么多。呃，不
matter what. That's a 50/50 partnership,
无论如何。这是五五分成的合作关系。
right? It's making an incredibly
正确的？它正在创造一个令人难以置信的
important decision based on they both
基于这两点的重要决定
equal 100. Numbers sound clean to me,
等于100。这些数字听起来很干净。
but like what is the statistical chance?
但统计概率是多少呢？
This is what needs to be true for a
这是必须满足的条件
50/50 partnership to work. Okay, they
五五分成的合作关系。好吧，他们
both have to be allin. They both have to
两人都必须全力以赴。他们俩都必须
always be allin for the whole lifespan
一生都要全力以赴
of the business. Maybe years, maybe
这家公司。也许几年，也许
decades. They have to put in the same
几十年。他们必须投入同样的资源。
amount of money, same amount of effort,
投入的资金量相同，付出的精力也相同。
same amount of connections, value,
连接数相同，价值相同，
history, background. Also, both of them
历史背景。而且，他们俩
should be completely selfless, right?
应该完全无私，对吗？
And not care if the other one's not
不在乎对方是否在乎
pulling his weight. I'm taking a
他尽了自己的一份力。我正在服用
month-long vacation. Cool. You'll make
长达一个月的假期。凉爽的。你会做出
up for it later. They have to be like
待会儿再说。他们必须像
that chill of a human being. And of
人类的冷漠。以及
course, like they have to be the same as
当然，就像它们必须相同一样
the other person. If all those things
另一个人。如果所有这些事情
are true, 50/50 works great.
确实如此，50/50 的效果很好。
&gt;&gt; And they need to develop going forward
而且他们需要在未来不断发展。
in the same way because for the next 10
同样地，因为接下来的10
future,
未来，
&gt;&gt; they need to grow at the same rate.
它们需要以相同的速度增长。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Which will never never ever be the
是的。那将永远、永远、永远不会是
case. So, I like to say like you don't
案件。所以，我喜欢说，就像你不会那样。
want to uh DTR, define the relationship
想明确一下关系
too early or too late. If you sit down
太早或太晚。如果你坐下来
at brunch and you're like, "Let's do
在早午餐时，你会说：“我们来做……”
50/50. Cool." Big mistake. If you you're
五五开。 “酷。”大错特错。如果你是
2 years down the line and you've got all
两年后，你就拥有了一切
this revenue and customers and you're
这些收入和客户，还有你
like, "All right, we should probably
比如，“好吧，我们大概应该……”
formalize this." Too late. Cuz like that
正式化这件事。” 太迟了。因为那样就太晚了。
only works if the business just stays at
只有当企业保持现状时，这种方法才有效。
like a steady state forever, which it
就像永远处于稳定状态一样，它
won't. It's going to go up or it's going
惯于。它要么会上涨，要么正在下跌
to go down, right? And like things get
下去，对吧？事情就是这样发展的。
really ugly when either one of those two
这两个人中的任何一个都真的很丑。
scenarios happen. So the sweet spot in
各种情况都会发生。所以最佳点是
my experience is listen, this is how
我的经验是，听着，就是这样。
this conversation would would work.
这样的对话会奏效。
We're going to partner together. Hey, um
我们将携手合作。嘿，嗯
I think you're going to be great for
我认为你将会非常出色
this business because you have a sales
因为你有销售业绩，所以才做这项业务。
background. You're great at sales. You
背景。你的销售能力很强。你
have a lot of contacts in the industry.
在业内有很多关系。
I don't have any of that. I don't even
我一个都没有。我甚至都不认识
like sales. I don't know anything about
例如销售。我对此一无所知。
sales. But I'm an amazing engineer. Like
销售量。但我是一名非常优秀的工程师。喜欢
I know I can build this thing. You've
我知道我能把它做出来。你已经
seen me build other websites, other apps
他们见过我搭建其他网站和其他应用程序。
in the past. I already have like a
在过去。我已经有一个了
wireframe in mind. Like, we're going to
脑海中已有线框图。比如，我们要……
be great for this, right? So, let's just
这样做肯定很棒，对吧？所以，我们就这么办吧
do this. I don't know how this is going
这样做。我不知道事情会如何发展。
to go. I don't know how much time you
走吧。我不知道你花了多少时间
have. We both have full-time jobs. Um,
有。我们俩都有全职工作。嗯，
why don't we just get to $10,000 in
我们为什么不直接达到 10,000 美元呢？
revenue? Um, let's get product market
收入？嗯，我们来谈谈产品市场吧。
fit. Let's get some good traction. Maybe
合身。让我们取得一些进展。或许
we'll get like you really have to set a
我们会觉得你真的必须设定一个
a defined metric around it. Not like
围绕它制定了明确的衡量标准。不像
let's see how this goes in 30 days, but
让我们看看30天后情况如何，但是
something like a revenue number, number
类似收入数字之类的东西
of customers, or something. at that
顾客之类的。当时
point, let's sit down. Let's just like
说，咱们坐下吧。我们就这么吧
put it in the calendar today and let's
今天就把它记在日历上，我们开始吧！
have a conversation about what our
就我们的……进行一次对话
equity looks like. Uh because almost
股权看起来是这样的。呃，因为几乎
every time they're going to be remote
每次他们都要远程办公的时候
just based on the world we live in or
仅仅基于我们所生活的世界，或者
one person will put in more money or one
一个人会投入更多钱，或者一个人
person has more experience. Um and all
这个人更有经验。嗯，等等
those things are are relevant, but
这些事情固然重要，但是
&gt;&gt; you're going to get resentment
你会招致怨恨。
&gt;&gt; 100%. And you're probably not going to
100%。而且你可能不会
talk about that resentment and it's only
谈到那种怨恨，那就只是
going to get worse. um it'll only get
情况会变得更糟。嗯，它只会得到
worse if you know things either go up or
更糟糕的是，如果你知道事情要么上涨要么下跌
down. So they they will always get
向下。所以他们总是会得到
worse. Um but it's it's hard to define
更糟。嗯，但是很难定义。
because one person might have 30 years
因为一个人可能有30年
of industry experience and contacts and
行业经验和人脉
expertise and he can make one phone call
他拥有专业知识，只需打一个电话就能搞定。
that changes everything and the other
那将改变一切，以及其他一切。
person might be 18 years old and just a
这个人可能只有18岁，而且只是个……
hustler and willing to put in 80 hours a
积极进取，愿意投入80个小时
week. So is the level of value the same
星期。那么价值水平是否相同呢？
if the level of hours put into the
如果投入的时间水平
business not the same?
业务模式变了吗？
It's hard. Like it's it's really hard to
这很难。感觉真的很难
say, "Hey, my one phone call made us 10
比如说，“嘿，我打的一个电话就让我们10
millions of dollars, tens of millions of
数百万美元，数千万美元
dollars, but you've done all the work.
虽然花了不少钱，但所有工作都是你做的。
You're the operator, so we should be
你是操作员，所以我们应该
50/50." They're both going to take issue
五五开。”他们俩都会提出异议。
with that. The only instance I was
就这样。唯一一次我是
thinking about all the business
思考所有业务
partnerships that I'm aware of. So
据我所知，存在合作关系。所以
companies I've invested in. There's
我投资的公司。有
about 60 or 70 companies I've invested
我投资过大约60到70家公司。
in and then businesses I've started
然后是我创办的企业
myself. And the one time I've seen it
我。我唯一一次看到它
work to split equally, the two people
两人努力平分。
had known each other for a long long
他们认识很久很久了。
time and they were both late in their
他们俩都迟到了。
career. M
职业。 M
&gt;&gt; so they're like you know when we think
所以他们就像，你知道，当我们想到……
about rate of development and potential
关于发展速度和潜力
not only did they have a strong
他们不仅拥有强大的
relationship they'd known each other a
他们之间的关系始于他们彼此认识。
long time they'd worked together for
他们已经合作了很长时间
more than 5 years together and they're
他们在一起超过5年了，而且
sort of later in a more mature phase of
后来，在更成熟的阶段
their career
他们的职业生涯
&gt;&gt; where you know like the kids situation's
你知道，比如孩子们的情况……
figured itself out are they going to
他们自己想明白了，他们会怎么做？
have kids or not and there hasn't been
无论有没有孩子，目前还没有……
some of the big life disruptors that
一些重大的生活干扰因素
sometimes can come along and change
有时候，情况可能会发生变化。
things and then I can think of another
然后我还能想到其他事。
example where um two people knew each
举个例子，两个人彼此认识。
other. They were very, very young.
其他。他们当时年纪非常小。
They'd worked together before. The
他们之前就共事过。这
contract went in 50/50, although it was
合同最终以五五分成的方式达成，尽管
never really equal. And then their rate
永远不可能真正平等。然后是他们的利率
of growth changed wildly where one
增长方式发生了巨大变化，其中一种
person
人
&gt;&gt; really just like became a superstar. And
真的就像成了超级巨星一样。和
they look back at the contract and it
他们回顾了合同，然后……
was 50/50. And I remember being privy to
五五开。我记得我曾有幸目睹……
the conversation where that person
对话中那个人
turned around to their business partner
他们转身看向他们的商业伙伴
was like, "This is not fair."
当时我就想：“这不公平。”
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; This company without me goes to zero.
没有我，这家公司就完了。
Without you, it keeps growing.
没有你，它会继续增长。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And there was an adjustment made
是的。因此做出了一些调整。
to the equity at that point, which is
到那时的股权，即
hard to do because of tax reasons and
由于税务原因，这很难做到；
stuff. But
东西。但
&gt;&gt; yeah, the one thing I will say about a
是的，关于这一点，我只想说一点
50/50 and going in with someone that
五五开，和某人一起合伙
you've known for a long time, or going
你很久以前就知道，或者即将
in with your best friend, that can be
和你的好朋友一起，那可能会
really freaking fun. Like, it can just
真的超级好玩。比如，它就可以
be the most enjoyable life ever. So,
过上最快乐的生活。所以，
it's just very high risk and very high
风险非常高，而且非常高
reward. And if you can make it work,
报酬。如果你能做到的话，
like often times the biggest and the
就像通常情况下最大的和
best and the most well-ran companies you
最好、管理最好的公司
see were 50/50 partners that knew each
双方都是50/50的合伙人，彼此都认识。
other for a long time for that reason.
其他人也因为这个原因长期如此。
Um, but the rate of failure is higher
嗯，但是失败率更高。
than average. So, in these uh three
高于平均水平。所以，在这三个方面
suitcases in front of me, I have
我面前摆着几个行李箱，我有
different amounts of money.
不同金额的钱。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And all I want you to do is to let me
而我只想让你让我
know if I was giving you this amount of
知道我是否会给你这么多钱
money, what business you would start.
如果有钱，你会创办什么企业？
Okay, so the first one
好的，那么第一个
has
有
$500 here.
这里是500美元。
Awesome. So, most people would look at
惊人的。所以大多数人会看
this and think, "What am I going to do
然后我想，“我该怎么办？”
with $500?" That's a lot of money,
用500美元？那可是一大笔钱啊。
right? In in the age of today with
正确的？在当今时代
30-day free trials and uh a lot of
30 天免费试用，还有很多其他服务
Silicon Valley funded companies willing
硅谷投资的公司愿意
to give you a lot of money to test your
给你很多钱来测试你的
product, this goes a long way. So the
这款产品非常耐用。所以
first thing to come to mind that comes
首先想到的就是
to mind is probably my favorite business
我最关心的可能是我最喜欢的行业。
idea of all right now and thankfully you
现在一切都好，谢天谢地你
can start it with even less than this
甚至可以用更少的钱开始。
and that would be a business that helps
那将是一家有助于……的企业。
implement AI into small businesses small
将人工智能应用于小型企业
to mediumsiz businesses. So some facts
面向中型企业。一些事实
for you there's 400 million small
对你来说，有4亿个小
businesses on the planet. They've
全球企业。他们有
surveyed some of these business owners
我们调查了其中一些企业主。
um and 77% of them have admitted that
嗯，其中77%的人承认了这一点。
like AI would be transformational to
例如，人工智能将带来变革。
their business. They need AI. It's not a
他们的生意。他们需要人工智能。它不是
fad. It's not going away. 5% of them
时尚。它不会消失。其中5%
have claimed they're using AI in a
他们声称正在使用人工智能
meaningful way, right? And define that
有意义的方式，对吧？并定义这一点
as you will. So, basically, we have this
如你所愿。所以，基本上，我们有这样
knowledge gap, right? We know it's like
对吧？这算是知识上的差距？我们知道这就像
a it's like a business cognitive
它就像一个商业认知
dissonance, if you will. We know we need
可以说是不和谐。我们知道我们需要
to do something and we're not doing it.
应该做某件事，但我们却没有去做。
Doesn't matter how easy the tools are.
工具是否简便并不重要。
Doesn't matter how much you can create a
你能创造多少东西并不重要
new website or an app with one prompt.
一个全新的网站或应用程序，只有一个提示信息。
Um, they need someone to do it, right? I
嗯，他们需要有人来做这件事，对吧？我
know how to vacuum my floor. I know how
知道如何用吸尘器清洁地板。我知道该怎么做
to clean my house. I still would rather
打扫我的房子。我仍然宁愿
just pay someone to do it. Okay. And so
花钱请人做就行了。好的。所以
with a fifth of the money, call it a
用五分之一的钱，称之为
$100, I would start learning some vibe
100美元，我就可以开始学习一些氛围营造技巧了。
coding tools. Um, Replet, Lindy, there's
编码工具。嗯，Replet，Lindy，那里有
a ton of them out there.
市面上有很多这样的。
&gt;&gt; What is vibe coding for anyone that
什么是氛围编码？
doesn't?
不是吗？
&gt;&gt; Vibe coding is the non-technical person,
Vibe 编码是为非技术人员设计的，
the non-coder such as myself using their
像我这样的非程序员使用他们的
natural language to just say, "Hey,
用自然语言直接说：“嘿，
build me an app that manages customers
帮我开发一个客户管理应用
for dog trainers." You'll have an app,
适用于训犬师。”你会有一个应用程序，
right? Is it fully functional? Is
正确的？它功能齐全吗？是
workable yet? Not quite, but 10 to 20
可以操作了吗？不完全是，但大概10到20。
more prompts and you're good to go.
更多提示，你就可以开始了。
&gt;&gt; And for anyone that doesn't know, I I
对于那些不知道的人，我
would suggest I'm an investor in both
这表明我既是投资者又是投资者。
Lovable and Replet. So, disclaimer, but
可爱又充足。所以，先声明一下，但是
I would recommend going on Replet or
我建议去Replet或
Lovable and um typing in any website ID
可爱，嗯，在任何网站 ID 中输入
you have just to have that sort of
你必须具备那种能力
eureka moment of watching it be made in
观看制作过程时的顿悟时刻
front of you. I think that Eureka moment
在你面前。我认为那是灵光乍现的时刻
is the moment your mind expands to the
那是你思维扩展到……的时刻
possibilities that are currently right
目前正确的可能性
in front of all of us.
当着我们所有人的面。
&gt;&gt; Yes. You know, we think of building
是的。你知道，我们想到的是建造
websites or apps as exclusive to those
网站或应用程序仅限这些网站或应用程序使用。
that have spent 5 years learning to
花了五年时间学习
code. That has now changed.
代码。现在情况已经改变了。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we can all do it. Yeah. And
是的，我们都能做到。是的。和
everyone should, like you said, one
就像你说的，每个人都应该有一个
prompt, develop an app. Oh, what do I
提示，开发一个应用程序。哦，我该怎么办？
prompt? What do I build? Ask Chad GBT
迅速的？我该建造什么？问问查德·GBT
what to build. Copy paste one of those.
要建造什么。复制粘贴其中之一。
Ask Chad to prompt it. Take it over to
请查德提醒他。把它带过去
repletter lovable, paste it, and see
填满可爱的，粘贴它，然后看看
what it builds. So, I would use this as
它所构建的。所以，我会这样使用它
my education and also to build a
我的教育，以及建立一个
website, right? Chris's automations.com,
网站，对吧？ Chris 的 automations.com，
whatever, anything.
随便什么都行。
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
[嗤笑]
&gt;&gt; And then I would take the rest of the
然后我会拿走剩下的……
money and I would put it into ads,
我会把钱投入到广告中。
right? Um, preferably meta ads, Facebook
正确的？嗯，最好是Facebook的元广告。
ads, and I would target local
广告，我会针对本地市场投放。
businesses. Even though this is a global
企业。尽管这是一个全球性的
thing, if I live in Omaha, Nebraska, I
如果我住在内布拉斯加州奥马哈市，我
could sell this to people in Tokyo.
可以卖给东京人。
Doesn't matter. I'm going to put a
没关系。我打算放一个
radius around Omaha and my ads are going
以奥马哈为中心，我的广告正在投放。
to say, "I'm Chris and I can help put AI
比如说，“我是克里斯，我可以帮助实现人工智能。”
into your business." I'm going to use
进入你的业务。”我打算使用
fifth grade words. I'm not going to use
五年级词汇。我不会使用
LLM. I'm not even going to say Chad GPT.
法学硕士。我甚至都不想提查德·GPT。
I'm just going to say, I will make your
我只想说，我会让你的
business more money or save your
企业需要更多资金或节省开支
business money with AI, just a service
利用人工智能进行商业资金运作，这只是一项服务。
business. And then I'll get on discovery
商业。然后我就要上探索频道了。
calls with these business owners and
与这些企业主通话
I'll just start peppering them with
我这就开始往他们身上撒粉
questions about their business. And over
询问他们的业务情况。以及
time, I'm going to learn based on their
时间到了，我将根据他们的经验来学习。
answers what their problems are, what
回答他们的问题是什么，什么
they're struggling with. Is it hiring?
他们正在为此苦恼。该公司正在招聘吗？
Is it payroll? Is it sales? Usually,
是工资单吗？是销售额吗？通常，
it's going to be sales, right? And then
肯定是销售额，对吧？进而
I'm going to take this money over here,
我要把这笔钱带过来。
this $100, and go back to those apps and
这100美元，然后回到那些应用程序上去。
start building solutions for them for
开始为他们构建解决方案
free. just to kind of implement myself
自由的。只是为了实现我自己
as an expert.
作为专家。
&gt;&gt; And what are you going to charge them?
你们打算向他们收取多少费用？
&gt;&gt; I'm going to charge them between $500
我打算向他们收取 500 美元。
and $5,000 upfront one time to implement
以及一次性预付 5,000 美元用于实施
it. And then I'm going to charge them
它。然后我就要向他们收费了。
20% of that amount in an ongoing basis
持续支付该金额的20%。
to maintain it and fix it as it breaks.
负责维护和修理，并在出现故障时进行维修。
Let's say there's a gutter cleaning
假设需要清理排水沟。
business in Omaha, Nebraska that doesn't
内布拉斯加州奥马哈市一家不
want to take calls after hours. He's
想在下班后接听电话。他是
with his wife watching Netflix and he
他和妻子一起看Netflix，他
knows that's a $3,000 job. he doesn't
他知道这是一份价值 3000 美元的工作。他没有
want to take it. So, it's going to
想拿走它。所以，它将要
voicemail and they're calling someone
语音信箱，他们正在给某人打电话。
else that is taking it, right? So, I'm
否则就是有人在服用它，对吧？所以，我是
going to build an AI voice agent for
准备构建一个人工智能语音代理
him, which sounds really intimidating.
他，听起来真让人害怕。
It feels like we have to have all these
感觉我们必须拥有所有这些
skills. You don't. You just need to
技能。你没有。你只需要
prompt a couple tools a couple times.
提示使用几个工具几次。
I'm going to build a voice agent for him
我打算为他开发一个语音代理。
and then I'm going to tell him to call
然后我会让他打电话
that agent as if he were a customer and
那位代理人就像对待顾客一样，
say, "Hey, pretend you're a customer
比如说，“嘿，假装你是顾客。”
that needs uh gutter cleaning. You're
那需要清理一下排水沟。你是
calling at 9:30 p.m. and just see how it
晚上9点30分来电看看效果如何
reacts." He's expecting there to be a
做出反应。”他预计会有一个
delay. There's really not. He's
延迟。确实没有。他是
expecting it to be dumb. It's not. He's
以为它会很蠢。它不是。他是
expecting it to need to know all about
期望它需要了解所有关于
his business. It doesn't, right? The AI
他的生意。不会吧？人工智能
knows about gutter cleaning businesses.
了解排水沟清洁公司的情况。
Then he's sold, right? Charge him $3,000
那他就被卖掉了，对吧？判他3000美元罚款
for that. You build it and then you
为此。你把它建好，然后你
charge them, call it 500 or 600 a month
向他们收费，比如每月 500 或 600 美元。
to maintain it over time. And then the
以便长期保持其性能。然后是
beautiful thing is you can go to every
最棒的是你可以去任何地方
other gutter cleaning business in Omaha
奥马哈其他排水沟清洁公司
or anywhere and copy and paste that same
或者复制到任何地方，然后复制粘贴相同的内容。
app and sell it to them.
应用程序并把它卖给他们。
&gt;&gt; Gotcha. So selling AI to small business
明白了。所以，向小型企业销售人工智能
owners who are in huge demand but don't
那些炙手可热但却不……的业主
have the time or think they need some
有时间或者认为他们需要一些时间
sort of incredible
简直不可思议
expensive time and resource expensive
耗时耗力
competence to understand AI when
具备理解人工智能的能力
actually AI is really really simple.
其实人工智能真的非常简单。
&gt;&gt; Yes.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And we see this play out over history
纵观历史，我们看到这种情况不断上演。
where there's an initial arbitrage when
当存在初始套利机会时
a new technology comes into play. Mhm.
一项新技术开始发挥作用。嗯。
&gt;&gt; In fact, one of the call center jobs
事实上，呼叫中心的工作之一就是……
that I had when I was very very broke
那是我穷困潦倒时拥有的。
many many years ago when I was like 18
很多很多年前，大概18岁的时候。
um or [clears throat] 19 was calling
嗯，或者（清了清嗓子）19号打来的电话
businesses from the yellow pages and
黄页上的商家
selling them Facebook ads.
向他们投放Facebook广告。
&gt;&gt; I would call a builder on a building
我会打电话给建筑商，询问建筑情况。
site. I'd speak to Dave who's the owner
地点。我会和老板戴夫谈谈。
of the building company and I'd explain
我会解释建筑公司的情况
Facebook ads to him over the phone and
通过电话向他推送Facebook广告
then I'd set them up for him and manage
然后我会帮他安排好并进行管理。
them for him on an ongoing basis and
他们持续不断地为他提供帮助，
just send him the leads
把线索发给他就行了。
&gt;&gt; because he didn't understand Facebook
因为他不懂脸书。
ads. And these opportunities seem to
广告。这些机会似乎
exist
存在
&gt;&gt; for years when there's a new technology
多年来，每当出现一项新技术
as as we're seeing with AI.
正如我们在人工智能领域所看到的。
&gt;&gt; But the thing is with that idea and with
但问题在于这个想法以及
most ideas in my experience, we think
以我的经验来看，大多数想法，我们认为
there's a very limited time span. But if
时间非常有限。但是如果
I were to start that business today and
我今天就要开始做那项生意了，
just start calling, it would work.
直接开始打电话，应该会管用。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you could still do it. Yeah, I
是的，你仍然可以做到。是的，我
might have more competitors, but like it
或许竞争对手更多，但我喜欢它
it doesn't matter. It would still work.
没关系。它仍然有效。
Interestingly, the the issue back then
有趣的是，当时的问题
was people didn't even know what
人们甚至不知道什么
Facebook ads were. So maybe it works to
Facebook广告就是如此。所以也许它有效
some degree better now. People have
现在情况好多了。人们有
heard the word.
听到了这个词。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You were pretty early. Yeah, it
是的。你来得挺早的。是的，就是这样。
was 2015 or something.
大概是2015年左右吧。
&gt;&gt; So, it was it was quite rough, but it
所以，过程相当艰难，但是
was a business nonetheless. Yeah.
但那毕竟是一门生意。是的。
&gt;&gt; And there was 40 other people in the
当时还有其他40个人。
room with me in that call center doing
和我一起在那个呼叫中心的房间里做
it.
它。
&gt;&gt; Wow.
哇。
&gt;&gt; So, that's the first idea you have.
所以，这是你的第一个想法。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; What else? $500. What else could you do?
还有什么？ 500美元。你还能做些什么？
&gt;&gt; Okay. Do you want a uh you want a
好的。你想要一个呃，你想要一个
physical business or an online business?
实体店还是网店？
Or does it not matter?
或者，这根本无关紧要？
&gt;&gt; What about a physical one?
那实体的呢？
&gt;&gt; All right. For a physical one, I would
好的。如果是实体的，我会
um have you heard of dropervicing?
嗯，你听说过滴注疗法吗？
&gt;&gt; No. So the phrase drop shipping has kind
不。所以“代发货”这个词组有一种……
of has a bad rap and some of it for good
的名声不太好，其中一些好名声是好的。
reason which is basically buying a
原因基本上是购买
product in China uh having a website for
在中国销售的产品，呃，有一个网站
it and basically having the Chinese
它，基本上就是中国人。
manufacturer or the supplier ship it
制造商或供应商发货
directly to your customer so you don't
直接联系您的客户，这样您就无需
have to take possession of the inventory
必须接收库存
right drop servicing is doing something
正确的投递服务正在进行一些事情
similar with a service call it a let's
类似地，我们可以称之为一项服务。
call it a home service business right so
就叫它家庭服务公司吧，对吧？
in this case it would look like um a
在这种情况下，它看起来就像……
garage repair company that has a website
拥有网站的修车厂
that looks like they have a physical
看起来他们有身体方面的问题。
presence in a market, but is really just
在市场上占有一席之地，但实际上只是
a lead genen factory, right? And so what
铅基因工厂，对吧？所以呢？
you're doing is you're using Facebook or
你正在做的就是使用Facebook或
Google ads to generate leads, kind of
利用谷歌广告来获取潜在客户，某种程度上来说
like what you were doing on Facebook um
就像你在Facebook上做的事情一样
for a local business, and then you're
对于一家本地企业来说，然后你就是
you're instead of just selling the leads
你不是仅仅出售潜在客户名单。
for $20, you're actually doing more of
花20美元，你实际上可以做更多的事情
the work. You're you're subcontracting
这项工作。你是分包商
out the work to a local business that
将这项工作外包给一家当地企业
actually repairs garage doors. They're
实际上，他是修理车库门的。他们是
the fulfillment arm of the business.
公司的物流配送部门。
You're the marketing arm of the
你是公司的市场营销部门
business. So, in essence, you have a
商业。所以，本质上，你有一个
garage repair um business without
没有车库维修业务
actually having one. Like, you don't
实际上我有一个。比如，你不会
know anything about garage doors. You've
你对车库门一窍不通吗？你已经
never been on site. You're just drop
从未到过现场。你刚掉下去
servicing. You're you're sending all the
维修。你发送了所有
work to a local company to do it.
委托当地公司来完成这项工作。
&gt;&gt; So, I a car repair company. I I put up a
所以，我是一家汽车修理公司。我建了一个
car repair website. I use Facebook ads
汽车维修网站。我使用 Facebook 广告
to drive people towards it. When they
引导人们走向它。当他们
click to buy my my car repair, I call a
点击购买我的汽车维修服务，我打电话给
local car repair person and say, "Hey,
当地修车师傅说：“嘿，
I've got a customer here for you. Um can
我这里有个顾客要找你。嗯，可以
you take them?" I book the customer in.
你接收他们吗？我帮顾客登记。
&gt;&gt; They handle the car repair. I take the
他们负责汽车维修。我接受
payment and pay the garage. Yep. Great
付款并支付车库费用。是的。伟大的
question. So, let's just say in your
问题。所以，我们不妨这样说，在你的
example, um, an oil change at at some at
例如，嗯，在某个地方换机油
Bob's car repair that doesn't have a
鲍勃的汽车修理店没有
website is 40 bucks, which is a great
网站售价40美元，这很划算。
price. Your website is clean, it's nice,
价格。你的网站很简洁，很漂亮。
they can pay with a few clicks and it's
他们只需点击几下鼠标即可付款。
80 bucks, right? So, you call Bob one
80美元，对吧？所以你称鲍勃为一
day and say, "Hey, congratulations. I
白天，我会说：“嘿，恭喜你。”
have a lead. I don't have a lead. I have
领先。我没有线索。我有
a customer. I want to send you $40. Her
一位顾客。我想给你寄40美元。她
name is Mary. She's going to be coming
我的名字是玛丽。她要来了
in. She has a sequoia. She needs an oil
她有一棵红杉树。她需要一种油
change, right? And so Mary just
改变了，对吧？于是玛丽就……
interacts with you. She's trusting you
与你互动。她信任你
with the money. You don't have to trust
用这笔钱。你不必信任
Bob with the money. Uh you just send Bob
鲍勃有钱。呃，你只要把鲍勃派过去就行了。
the money. You make even more margin
钱。你还能赚取更多利润。
than Bob makes. Right? It's a higher
比鲍勃赚的还多。正确的？这是一个更高的值。
price service, but what you're charging
价格服务，但你收取的费用是多少？
for is the better UI, the better user
更好的用户界面，更好的用户体验。
experience, and having a a cleaner
经验，以及拥有一个更清洁的
checkout method. And is there particular
结账方式。是否存在特别之处
types of businesses you would target
你会瞄准哪些类型的企业？
with that approach? Are you targeting
用那种方法？你的目标是什么？
ones that have a shitty customer
那些顾客服务很差的商家
experience, bad website, etc. in the
体验、糟糕的网站等等
home services, like take your pick. Um,
上门服务，任您选择。嗯，
they pretty much all do, right? Um,
他们几乎都这么做，对吧？嗯，
there are some more established
还有一些更成熟的
industries like roofing that don't have
像屋顶工程这样的行业没有
those issues, uh, because they have
那些问题，呃，因为它们有
higher margins, so they can afford
更高的利润率，所以他们能够负担得起。
better websites, but um, they pretty
更好的网站，但是，嗯，它们相当
much all have a bad experience.
几乎所有人都有过糟糕的经历。
&gt;&gt; Any others at that $500 level that stand
其他任何价格在 500 美元左右的竞争对手
out to you?
对你来说？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I love um, directory websites.
是的，我喜欢目录网站。
What's that?
那是什么？
&gt;&gt; So, Travel Velocity is a directory
所以，Travel Velocity 是一个目录
website. Yelp is a directory website.
网站。 Yelp是一个目录网站。
It's a website with a list of things
这是一个列出各种物品的网站。
that helps people find answers to their
帮助人们找到问题的答案
questions more easily. So, another
更容易提问。所以，还有另一个
example of a website could be like
网站示例可能如下所示
Wisconsin um ice suppliers.com. I don't
威斯康星州冰供应商网站。我不
know if that's a website, right? Where
你知道那是不是个网站吧？在哪里
if I need to go buy ice for my party,
如果我需要去买冰块办派对，
I'm going to Google ice near me. Um some
我要在谷歌上搜索附近的冰块。嗯，一些
categories are so niche or so unevenly
类别要么过于小众，要么发展极不均衡。
distributed that Google Maps is not a
分发的信息显示，谷歌地图并非
good solution for it. Right? So, you're
这是个不错的解决方案。正确的？所以，你是
directed to these random directory
指向这些随机目录
websites that are just lists of other
只是列出其他内容的网站
businesses. Um, and what people are
企业。嗯，还有人们是什么样的人
doing is they're proactively creating
他们正在积极主动地创造
their own directories by scraping uh
他们通过抓取数据来创建自己的目录
let's say every dog park in Seattle,
假设西雅图的每个狗公园，
Washington, and putting them on a
华盛顿，并将它们置于……
website and then they don't they don't
网站上，然后他们又不，他们不
even drive traffic to it. There's no
甚至可以吸引客流。没有
paid ads. They just wait for Google and
付费广告。他们只是在等待谷歌。
for SEO to do its trick. And it's very
让搜索引擎优化发挥作用。而且非常
much an 8020 rule. you could kind of
这与8020规则非常相似。你可能有点
build the architecture for a directory
构建目录架构
website with replet or lovable and then
网站内容丰富或可爱，然后
you just copy and paste it right in
你只需复制粘贴即可。
different markets. Uh so the play here
不同的市场。呃，所以这里上演的是这个剧本。
is to have dozens of directory websites
就是要有几十个目录网站
and some of them make $0 a month, some
他们中有些人每月收入为零，有些
make a few hundred, some make a few
有些人做几百个，有些人做几个。
thousand, but it's very passive. It's
一千，但它非常被动。它是
like one of those rare things that's
就像那种罕见的事物之一
passive yet also doesn't need a ton of
被动式，但也不需要大量的
money to get to get started.
启动资金。
&gt;&gt; Where's the money coming from? Where's
钱从哪里来？在哪里？
the revenue?
收入呢？
&gt;&gt; Great question. You can either do like
问得好。你可以这样做
display ads.
展示广告。
&gt;&gt; What's a display ad? just a banner ad on
什么是展示广告？只是一个横幅广告
a website.
一个网站。
&gt;&gt; And are you having to go and sell that
你非得去卖掉那些东西吗？
ad to someone that wants to buy it?
向想买它的人推荐？
&gt;&gt; You would just take Google's like ad
你只需要像谷歌广告那样做就行了。
network and just put it on your website.
网络链接，然后把它放到你的网站上。
So you don't have to do anything.
所以你什么都不用做。
&gt;&gt; So you can just click a button and it'll
所以你只需点击一个按钮，它就会
add adverts to your website which you'll
在你的网站上添加广告，你将
you'll then paid for.
然后你就得付钱了。
&gt;&gt; Yep. Or you could um you could just
是的。或者你可以……你可以直接
aggregate those leads. Like if we had
汇总这些线索。就像如果我们有
dog parks in Seattle and you know we see
西雅图有很多狗公园，你知道我们看到
on our Google Analytics that we're
我们在 Google Analytics 中表示
driving traffic to this one dog park,
吸引人流到这个狗公园，
then we reach out to them proactively
然后我们会主动联系他们。
and say, "Hey, you notice all these
然后说：“嘿，你注意到所有这些吗？”
customers you've been getting?" That's
你最近都接待了哪些客户？
because I put you on my website. Would
因为我把你放在了我的网站上。会
you like to pay $300 a year or a month
你愿意每年或每月支付 300 美元吗？
or whatever for priority placement?
或者其他什么优先排序方式？
Right? So, I like to call this
正确的？所以，我喜欢把这叫做……
permissionless marketing. Um, you're
无需许可的营销。嗯，你是
just proactively adding these businesses
主动添加这些企业
to a website. They have nothing to lose.
跳转到网站。他们没什么可失去的。
You have nothing to lose. And then once
你没什么可失去的。然后，一旦
you see traffic, then you reach out to
你看到流量，然后你联系
them and say, "Hey, I've been bringing
然后对他们说：“嘿，我一直在带
you more business. Would you like to
你会获得更多业务。你是否想要
start paying for that?"
“开始为此付费吗？”
&gt;&gt; Interesting.
有趣的。
And how much money can someone hope to
一个人究竟能期望赚多少钱？
make if they execute that strategy well
如果他们能很好地执行该策略，就能取得成功。
in your view? What's realistic
你的看法是什么？什么是现实的
&gt;&gt; with a directory website? It could be
有目录网站吗？有可能
tens of dollars a month and it could be
每月几十美元，就可能
tens of thousands of dollars a month,
每月数万美元，
but we're not talking about building
但我们说的不是建造。
another Yelp or Travel Velocity. This is
另一个 Yelp 或 Travel Velocity。这是
a zero employee business with that cost
零员工企业，成本如此之高
almost nothing, less than $100 to start.
几乎不需要什么，起步价不到100美元。
Um, but it's just a numbers game. You're
嗯，但这只是一场数字游戏。你是
not really going to know what directory
不太清楚具体是哪个目录
really hits until months have passed and
这种影响会持续数月之久。
until you have a lot of surface area for
直到你拥有很大的表面积
these experiments.
这些实验。
I hear a lot of people talking about
我听到很多人都在谈论……
vending machines online and I've always
在线自动售货机，我一直
been really curious about that. People
我一直很好奇。人们
say you can make money from vending
假设你可以通过自动售货机赚钱
machines.
机器。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Could you do that with $500?
是的。 500美元能做到吗？
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. So, if we were doing another
绝对地。所以，如果我们要做另一件事的话
physical business, um I would go to
实体店，嗯，我会去
Facebook Marketplace and I would find an
Facebook Marketplace，我会找到一个
existing vending machine uh for $3 to
现有的自动售货机，售价 3 美元
$400, right? That could be a snack or a
400美元，对吧？那可能是零食，也可能是
drink vending machine. Um often times
饮料自动售货机。嗯，很多时候
the expensive part of a vending machine
自动售货机中最昂贵的部分
is the credit card reader. It can often
是信用卡读卡器。它通常
cost more or as much as the whole
成本高于或等于整个成本
machine itself. And then I would use a
机器本身。然后我会使用一个
$100 to stock the machine um with
100美元用来给机器补充燃料
Costco. Costco Sam's Club is where all
好市多。 Costco 和 Sam's Club 是所有……的地方
of these operators buy their snacks,
这些运营商会购买他们的零食，
believe it or not. And then I just need
信不信由你。然后我就只需要
one business owner to give me a chance
一位企业主愿意给我一个机会
um to allow me to put the vending
嗯，允许我放置自动售货机
machine in his lobby. Let's say it's a
他大厅里的那台机器。假设这是一个
car repair business. I can say, "Hey,
汽车修理业务。我可以说，“嘿，
I'll pay you 100 bucks a month or hey,
我每月付你100美元，或者，嘿，
I'll split the revenue with you. I'll
我会和你平分收益。患病的
give you 30% of the revenue." And then
给你30%的收入。”然后
once I have one, that's the hardest
一旦我有了，那才是最难的。
part. Now you have a track record. Now,
部分。现在你已经有了业绩记录。现在，
you can say, "Hey, Bob's Auto Repair
你可以说：“嘿，鲍勃汽车修理厂
makes $700 a month passively cuz he let
他每月被动收入700美元，因为他放任不管。
me put uh this vending machine there."
我把这台自动售货机放在那里。”
This is a business that can be passive
这是一项被动型业务。
if you have an employee to restock it.
如果你有员工负责补货的话。
That is the active part of the business
那是业务的活跃部分。
is the restocking and the selling of new
是补货和销售新产品
locations. Um, but if you have an ATM,
地点。嗯，但是如果你有自动取款机的话，
then that becomes even easier because
这样就更容易了，因为
you can outsource all of the restocking
你可以将所有补货工作外包出去。
to a cash management company.
给一家现金管理公司。
&gt;&gt; How much money could one person hope to
一个人能期望赚多少钱？
make from a vending machine business?
从自动售货机业务中获利？
And have you ever run this business
你经营过这家公司吗？
yourself?
你自己？
&gt;&gt; I have. I've actually been in a
我有。我其实一直身处……
different part of the vertical. I've
垂直方向的不同部分。我已经
sold vending machines. I posted a a
售卖自动售货机。我发帖了
video to Instagram that got tens of
一段发布到 Instagram 的视频获得了数十万赞。
millions of views and we started just
数百万的浏览量，而我们最初只是……
importing those vending machines that I
进口那些我
was talking about in the video uh and
视频里提到的那个
then selling them to entrepreneurs. But
然后将它们卖给企业家。但
the level of revenue is I mean it's as
收入水平，我的意思是，它就像
much as you want to scale it. I have a
随心所欲地扩展它。我有一个
friend in San Diego that makes seven
我在圣地亚哥的朋友，这样就有了七个朋友。
figures a year uh on vending machines,
每年自动售货机的相关数据，
just snacks and drinks. Is there an art
只提供零食和饮料。是否存在艺术
to good vending machine placement or the
自动售货机摆放位置是否合理？
right things to sell in the vending
自动售货机里适合卖的商品
machine or anything else?
机器还是其他什么东西？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's funny that you asked that
是啊，你问这个问题真有意思。
because he said, you know, I'm in San
因为他说，你知道，我在圣安东尼奥
Diego, people are health consscious here
迭戈，这里的人们都很注重健康。
and he tested all these healthy concepts
他检验了所有这些健康理念。
and they all failed. Like people want
他们都失败了。就像人们想要的那样
Doritos and Coke and Diet Coke, right?
对吧？多力多滋配可乐和健怡可乐？
So that's all they have now. That's
这就是他们现在拥有的一切。那是
where the demand is. But the biggest
哪里有需求，哪里就有需求。但最大的
needle mover on this is the location.
指针移动的位置就在这里。
And it's a matter of testing. Back to
这需要通过测试来验证。返回
testing, right? Testing what types of
测试，对吧？测试哪些类型的
locations he landed on. um apartment
他降落的地点。嗯，公寓
complexes, like apartment lobbies. He
类似公寓大堂的综合体。他
tried auto repair shops and they just
我试过几家汽车修理店，他们都……
weren't high volume. But it's the type
数量不多。但这是那种类型
of business kind of like directories
类似于商业名录
where if you have a 100 vending
如果你有100个自动售货机
machines, um you're going to have 20 of
机器，嗯，你会有20台。
them that make $3,000 a month each and
他们每个人每月收入3000美元，
then you're going to have 80 of them
那么你就会拥有80个了。
that make $400 a month each. But once
他们每人每月收入400美元。但曾经
you find out what types of locations are
你会发现有哪些类型的地点
the most profitable, then you just start
然后你就开始做最赚钱的事。
directly reaching out to those types of
直接联系这类人
locations.
地点。
&gt;&gt; I've just finished writing my third
我刚写完我的第三本书。
book. I haven't firmed up the title yet,
书。我还没最终确定书名。
but I have started mocking up some
但我已经开始做一些模拟图了。
different designs. And I've been doing
不同的设计。我一直在这样做
this with Adobe Express, which is one of
这与 Adob​​e Express 有关，它是其中之一。
our sponsors. What I love about Adobe
我们的赞助商。我喜欢Adobe的地方
Express is that it makes it so easy for
Express 的优势在于它让一切变得如此简单
me to obsess over the tiniest details.
让我变得过于关注细节。
The typography, the font, the color, the
排版、字体、颜色、
text placement, the stuff that might
文本位置，以及其他可能影响文本位置的内容
sound petty to most people, but actually
在大多数人看来这似乎微不足道，但实际上
compounds to create something that
化合物可以创造出某种东西
stands out, something that's one better
脱颖而出，更胜一筹。
than the rest. And designing my cover
比其他所有情况都好。以及设计我的封面
art has reminded me of how many creative
艺术让我意识到有多少创意人士
things I've learned over the year. But
我这一年来学到的东西。但
it's also reminded me that there are so
这也提醒了我，还有很多很多。
many creative minds around me that are
我身边有很多富有创造力的人。
also sitting on their own secrets. So
他们也各自保守着自己的秘密。所以
I've created the one better guide in
我已经创建了最好的指南。
Adobe Express to bring those tips to
Adobe Express 将这些技巧带到
you. And in it, you'll find principles
你。其中，你会发现一些原则
from the very, very best in their
来自他们中最非常优秀的人
industry turned into quick and easy
行业变得快捷方便
practices for you to apply. So you can
供您参考应用。所以你可以
train yourself to create exactly like
训练自己创造出完全相同的效果
the best performing teams in the world
世界表现最佳的团队
do. Just head over to adobe.
做。直接去Adobe网站看看。
One better to download Adobe Express
更好的选择是下载 Adob​​e Express
now. And make sure you visit the learn
现在。务必访问学习页面
tab to discover how you can become one
点击此标签了解如何成为其中一员
better than the rest. You know, every
比其他都好。你知道，每一个
once in a while you come across a
偶尔你会遇到
product that has such a huge impact on
该产品对……有着巨大的影响
your life that you'd probably describe
你大概会如何描述你的人生
as a gamecher. And I would say for about
作为一名游戏玩家。我会说大约
35 to 40% of my team, they would
我的团队中有 35% 到 40% 的人会
currently describe this product that I
目前我对该产品的描述是
have in front of me called Ketone IQ,
我面前摆着一种叫做酮体智商（Ketone IQ）的东西，
which you can get at ketone.com
您可以在ketone.com网站上找到它。
as a game changer. But the reason I
改变游戏规则。但我之所以这样想，是因为我
became a coowner of this company and the
成为这家公司的共同所有人，并且
reason why they they now are a sponsor
他们现在成为赞助商的原因
of this podcast is because one day when
这个播客之所以存在，是因为有一天……
I came to work there was a box of this
我来上班的时候，看到一个盒子装着这个
stuff sat on my desk. I had no idea what
我的桌子上堆着东西。我完全不知道是什么
it was. Lily in my team says that this
确实如此。我团队里的莉莉说这
company have been in touch. So I went
公司已经联系过我了。于是我就去了
upstairs tried it and quite frankly the
楼上的人试过了，坦白说，
rest is history in terms of my focus, my
就我的关注点而言，其余的都已成为过去。
energy levels, how I feel, how I work,
精力水平、我的感受、我的工作状态
how productive I am. Game changer. So if
我的工作效率有多高？颠覆性的。所以如果
you want to give it a try, visit
如果你想尝试一下，请访问
ketone.com/stephven for 30% off. You'll
访问 ketone.com/stephven 可享 30% 折扣。你会
also get a free gift with your second
购买第二件商品还可获赠一份免费礼物。
shipment. And now you can find Keton IQ
运输。现在你可以找到 Keton IQ
at Target stores across the United
在美国各地的Target商店
States where your first shot is
你第一次射击的州是
completely free of charge. Um, so I have
完全免费。嗯，所以我有
another box here. This box
这里还有一个盒子。这个盒子
has slightly more money in double. Okay.
双倍的金额略多一些。好的。
$1,000. What would you do with $1,000?
1000美元。如果你有1000美元，你会怎么做？
All right. So,
好的。所以，
for whatever reason, when I see $1,000,
不知为何，每当我看到1000美元时，
I think um about the wedding rental
我在想婚礼租赁的事儿。
business. Do you know anything about
商业。你知道什么吗？
that?
那？
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
&gt;&gt; So,
所以，
believe it or not, um weddings are
信不信由你，嗯，婚礼是
increasing in popularity. People are
越来越受欢迎。人们是
getting out uh getting married outside
出去……呃，在外面结婚
more than ever. I think like 75% of
比以往任何时候都更加如此。我认为大约75%
weddings are outside now, which is
现在婚礼都在户外举行了，这
increasing every year. Um and that
逐年增长。嗯，还有那个
increases the market for these random
这增加了对这些随机商品的需求市场。
one-off rentals, right? I read an
一次性租赁，对吧？我读了一篇
article on Reddit about a guy that built
Reddit 上有一篇关于一个建造者的文章
a wedding arch from his garage with some
他车库里搭起了一个婚礼拱门，还有一些
2x4s, some lumber. I think he spent like
2x4木条，一些木材。我觉得他花了……
200 or $300 to build it. And he rents it
建造它需要200到300美元。他租下了它。
out to weddings for like $1,000 per
去参加婚礼，每次大概要花1000美元。
wedding. And it's just a a piece of wood
婚礼。它只是一块木头。
for the couples to stand under as they
供情侣们站在下面
say, "I do." Right. And so he works with
说：“我愿意。”正确的。所以他与……合作
event organizers or wedding organizers
活动策划人或婚礼策划人
to continually rent it to the wedding
不断将其出租给婚礼
organizer.
组织者。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. He doesn't go through the
确切地。他没有经历
brides. He goes through the wedding
新娘。他参加了婚礼
planners because surface area they have
规划者因为他们拥有表面积
they're touching all kinds of weddings
他们涉足各种类型的婚礼
on a regular basis. To find these
定期进行。为了找到这些
wedding planners, you go to the knot,
婚礼策划师们，你们可以去婚礼网站The Knot看看。
you go to zola, wedding wire, you scrape
你去佐拉，婚礼网站，你刮刮乐
them and all of their phone numbers and
他们以及他们的所有电话号码
emails and names and businesses are on
电子邮件、姓名和公司信息都已上传。
the website for everyone to see and you
所有人都可以访问的网站，你
just start reaching out. And one contact
开始主动联系吧。以及一个联系人
could be one wedding a week. So that
可能每周都会有一场婚礼。以便
could be started that could be in the
可以开始，这可能在
$500 box, right?
500美元一盒，对吧？
&gt;&gt; You could [clears throat] spend $300 on
你可以[清嗓子]花300美元
supplies. You could spend $100 on
补给品。你可以花100美元
scraping all the emails quite cheaply.
以非常低的成本抓取所有电子邮件。
Um, and then you could spend $100 on gas
嗯，然后你可能要花100美元加油。
and then or let's say another $100 on
然后，或者说再加100美元
renting a truck and trailer from Home
从 Home 租一辆卡车和拖车
Depot. Say you have a car. Say you don't
仓库。假设你有一辆车。就说你不这么认为
have a car, right? You've got $400 left
你有车吗？你还剩400美元。
over to go to a nice meal or to uh or
过去吃顿好的，或者呃，或者
for Facebook ads.
用于 Facebook 广告。
So, photo walls are very popular.
所以，照片墙非常受欢迎。
shakuerie carts where wedding uh patrons
婚礼顾客的餐车
can make their own shakuderie board. Um
他们可以自己制作沙库德里板。嗯
you can do like custom pizzas at
你可以定制披萨之类的东西
weddings. You could do wedding arches.
婚礼。你可以做婚礼拱门。
Um there's a lot of different
嗯，有很多不同的
opportunities there.
那里有很多机会。
&gt;&gt; Weddings and funerals.
婚礼和葬礼。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, cuz everything you said there
是啊，因为你刚才说的那些话……
could also apply to funerals.
也适用于葬礼。
&gt;&gt; That's true.
这是真的。
&gt;&gt; They don't seem to be stopping either.
他们似乎也没有停止的打算。
&gt;&gt; Guess funerals are going to get more
看来葬礼会越来越隆重了。
popular with the population.
深受民众欢迎。
&gt;&gt; Yep.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Continuing to increase.
持续增长。
What else? So, wedding rentals is the
还有什么？所以，婚礼租赁就是
first one you do with $1,000. Anything
你用1000美元做的第一个。任何事物
else?
别的？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Should we do a an online one?
是的。我们应该做线上版本吗？
&gt;&gt; Sure.
当然。
&gt;&gt; So, there's a lot of people nowadays
所以，现在人很多。
making money with local email
利用本地电子邮件赚钱
newsletters.
电子报。
&gt;&gt; Are you very familiar with that?
你对此很熟悉吗？
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
&gt;&gt; So, basically what you do, we keep
所以，基本上，你所做的，我们都会保留
coming back to this is like a big ad for
回到这里就像是在做一则大型广告
Facebook, right? I swear it's not.
是Facebook吧？我发誓绝对不是。
&gt;&gt; But, um, people are using local Facebook
但是，嗯，人们正在使用本地 Facebook
ads. Um, let's say you live in Boise,
广告。嗯，假设你住在博伊西，
Idaho. There's 200,000 people there. You
爱达荷州。那里有20万人。你
post a Facebook ad that says, "Hey, find
在 Facebook 上发布一条广告，内容为：“嘿，寻找
out what's happening in Boise, Idaho.
了解一下爱达荷州博伊西正在发生的事情。
One email per week in your inbox. You
每周一封邮件发送到您的邮箱。你
can acquire a subscriber for about 50
获取一个订阅用户大约需要 50 美元
cents from Facebook or Instagram." Okay,
来自 Facebook 或 Instagram 的小费。” 好的，
let's call it a dollar to be to be more
我们姑且称之为“一美元，才能更多”。
conservative. Acquire a subscriber for a
保守的。获取订阅用户
dollar. If you sell ads inside that
美元。如果你在里面投放广告的话
email newsletter, you can charge about
电子邮件简讯，您可以收取大约
50 cents per month um per subscriber.
每位订阅者每月 50 美分。
So, if we had $1,000,
所以，如果我们有1000美元，
I would use a free trial for an email
我会使用电子邮件的免费试用版。
newsletter software like Beehive or
像 Beehive 或类似的邮件订阅软件
ConvertKit or any of those. And so, I've
ConvertKit 或任何其他类似工具。所以，我
already spent $0. And I would give all
已花费 0 美元。我愿付出一切
$1,000 to Meta. I would set a defined
给 Meta 1000 美元。我会设定一个明确的
radius in a local area. Preferably, it's
局部区域内的半径。最好是
where you live, but it doesn't have to
你居住的地方，但也不一定非得是
be. It could be on the other side of the
是。它可能在另一边
world. I've launched this. I tested this
世界。我已经启动了这个项目。我测试过这个
in New Mexico, and it worked. I'd spend
在新墨西哥州，这招奏效了。我会花
$1,000 to acquire a,000 subscribers. Um,
投入 1000 美元获取 1000 名订阅者。嗯，
and then I would start sending them
然后我就开始给他们发邮件。
weekly newsletters. What's happening in
每周新闻简报。发生了什么事
Boise, Idaho? Um, discounts in Boise,
爱达荷州博伊西？嗯，博伊西的折扣，
Idaho. News in Boise, Idaho. I would not
爱达荷州。爱达荷州博伊西新闻。我不会
use Chad GPT to write it. I would write
使用 Chad GPT 来编写。我会写
it myself in my own natural language,
我自己用我的自然语言写的，
whether I'm a good writer or not.
无论我写作水平如何。
&gt;&gt; Why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; Cuz it needs to feel personal. It needs
因为它需要让人感觉是个人化的。它需要
to feel like a local is writing it. Not
感觉像是当地人写的。不是
like an author, not like Chad GBT. Um,
像个作家，而不是像查德·GBT那样。嗯，
and then I would use those same
然后我会使用那些相同的
subscribers to source sponsors.
订阅用户寻找赞助商。
So Bob's car repair owner is potentially
所以鲍勃的修车店老板可能是
in your list. There are 10% of all
添加到您的列表中。占总数的10%。
adults are business owners, right? So if
成年人也可以是企业主，对吧？所以如果
I have a thousand email subscribers, 100
我有一千个邮件订阅用户，100
of them are going to be business owners
他们中有些人将会成为企业主。
are going to be potential sponsors to my
他们将成为我的潜在赞助商。
newsletter. So after a month or so, I'm
通讯。大约一个月后，我
going to put send out an email that
准备发送一封电子邮件
says, "Hey, your ad here. I'd love to
他说：“嘿，你的广告在这里。我很乐意……”
sponsor your business. It's a very
赞助您的企业。这是一个非常
relevant market. It costs $500 uh per
相关市场。每台售价500美元。
send to send your email." Um, so then if
发送到您的邮箱。” 嗯，那么如果
I spend $1,000 to acquire these
我花了1000美元购买了这些
customers, I will get that money back
客户们，我会把钱要回来的。
within two months because I'm I'm making
两个月内，因为我正在制作
$500 a month. 50 cents per subscriber
每月500美元。每位订阅者 50 美分
from a,000 newsletter subscribers. And
来自 1,000 名电子报订阅者。和
that can scale um as much as you want.
它可以根据需要进行任意扩展。
If Boise, Idaho is only so big, you copy
如果爱达荷州博伊西市只有这么大，你就复制它
and paste the template in another city
然后将模板粘贴到另一个城市
or a bigger city. Okay, let's move up
或者更大的城市。好的，我们向上移动。
then. This
然后。这
This briefcase has a lot more money in
这个公文包里装的钱比其他地方多得多。
it.
它。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
$5,000. What side hustle do you start if
5000美元。如果……你会开始做什么副业？
you've got $5,000?
你有5000美元吗？
Okay. So, if we've got a sliding scale
好的。所以，如果我们有一个滑动标尺
of active to passive income, the closer
从主动收入到被动收入的转变，越接近
you get to this to $5,000, the more
当你攒到 5000 美元时，越多
realistic the passive income becomes.
被动收入变得现实起来。
Okay. So, I'm going to go closer to
好的。所以，我要更靠近
that. Um,
那。嗯，
I love RV parks.
我喜欢房车营地。
&gt;&gt; What's an RV park?
什么是房车营地？
&gt;&gt; An RV park is one of two things. It's a
房车营地只有两种可能。这是一个
place for someone to live in full-time
可供某人全职居住的地方
for months or years at a time where they
在长达数月或数年的时间里，他们
live in an recreational vehicle in an
住在休闲车里
RV.
房车。
&gt;&gt; A camper van.
露营车。
&gt;&gt; A camper van. It could be a fixed income
露营车。这可能是固定收入
uh retired person. It could be a
呃，退休人士。这可能是一个
bluecollar worker. It could be a a
蓝领工人。这可能是一个
digital nomad. Right? That's kind of the
数字游民。正确的？那有点像……
three categories. Um, the other type of
分为三类。嗯，另一种类型的
RV park is a a recreational, like a more
房车公园是一种休闲场所，更像是……
short-term RV park that might be right
短期房车公园，或许正合适
outside of the Grand Canyon or, you
在大峡谷之外，或者，你
know, a popular tourist destination
知道，这是一个热门旅游目的地
where people are staying one to four
人们居住的地方一到四人
nights at a time, right? This is a
一次只待几个晚上，对吧？这是
business I've been in for about 7 years
我从事这个行业大约7年了。
now. They have very small RV parks out
现在。他们有一些非常小的房车营地。
there that are 3 to 10 pad sites that
那里有3到10个垫片位置
are about 3 to 10 times more profitable
盈利能力大约是其他产品的3到10倍。
than buying a single family home as a
比购买独栋住宅更划算
rental. Okay. So, I genuinely I don't
出租。好的。所以，我真的不
understand why people buy single family
了解人们为什么购买独栋住宅
homes because like buying a small RV
因为买房就像买小型房车一样。
park costs the same but is significantly
公园费用相同，但差别很大
more profitable and more flexible
更具盈利能力和更灵活
because you have your your risk is more
因为你承担的风险更大
distributed amongst five to 10 tenants
分配给五到十个租户
as opposed to one tenant that could go
与可能搬走的单个租户不同
bankrupt or disappear in the middle of
破产或在中途消失
the night. So, with this $5,000,
夜晚。所以，有了这5000美元，
um, I would call every small RV park in
嗯，我会给每个小型房车公园打电话。
my area, preferably within a three-hour
我所在的地区，最好在三小时车程以内。
drive. I would just find them on Google
驾驶。我会在谷歌上找到它们。
Maps. This would take a little more time
地图。这需要多花一些时间。
because we can't allocate any of this
因为我们无法分配任何这些
budget to the finding of the park. We've
为寻找公园制定预算。我们已经
got to do that very manually with the
必须完全手动操作才能完成。
our iPhone and our internet connection.
我们的iPhone和网络连接。
Okay. I'm going to find, in my
好的。我将在我的
experience, for every 100 parks I find,
经验是，每找到100个公园，
about two or three of them can be a
其中两到三个可能是
really good deal. Okay. So, if I get a
非常划算。好的。所以，如果我得到一个
100 people on the phone, I I know I can
电话里有100个人，我知道我可以
find one good deal from that with seller
从卖家那里找到一个好交易
financing because we can't use any of
因为我们无法使用任何融资方式
this to buy the park either. Got a lot
这也是为了买下这个公园。有很多
of constraints. I'm going to use uh
约束条件。我打算用呃
let's say
比如说
2,000 of these dollars um for my due
这其中2000美元，嗯，是我应得的。
diligence. I've got to get inspections
勤勉。我需要进行检查。
on the park. I've got to get a title
在公园里。我必须拿到头衔。
policy on the park to make sure it's not
制定公园相关政策，以确保它不会
a scam to make sure that the owner who
这是一场骗局，目的是确保所有者……
says they own it actually owns it. Um,
他们说拥有它，实际上也拥有它。嗯，
and then with the remainder of the
然后是剩下的部分
money, I need some operating capital. I
资金方面，我需要一些运营资金。我
need to be able to pay the power bill to
需要有能力支付电费
maybe trim some trees to get the park
或许可以修剪一些树木来美化公园
looking nice on day one. And then to
第一天看起来不错。然后到
actually buy the park, I need to set up
实际上，我需要买下这个公园，然后进行装修。
creative financing with the seller. And
与卖方协商创新融资方案。和
the best way you can do that is by
做到这一点的最佳方法是……
building a relationship with the seller,
与卖家建立关系，
building some trust with them, um,
与他们建立一些信任关系，嗯，
showing them that you're going to take
向他们表明你会采取
good care of the park. Now, the unit
公园维护得很好。现在，该单位
economics on this, let's say you buy a
从经济学的角度来看，假设你买了一个
park for $200,000.
公园耗资 20 万美元。
In the real estate world, they're valued
在房地产领域，它们具有价值。
on a cap rate basis, which is the profit
按资本化率计算，即利润
of the park divided by the asking price
公园面积除以要价
of the park. So, if I buy a park for a
公园。所以，如果我买一个公园……
10% cap rate, that means it's going to
10%的资本化率，这意味着它将
make $20,000 a year of profit and it's
每年赚取 2 万美元的利润，而且
going to cost me $200,000. Okay? So,
这将花费我20万美元。好的？所以，
that park probably has no website. It
那个公园可能没有网站。它
probably has way undermarket rents. It
租金可能远低于市场价。它
probably has occupancy issues because
可能存在入住率问题，因为
they're it has no website. They're not
他们没有网站。他们不是
doing anything. So, I'm going to get the
做任何事。所以，我要去拿
park to perform by literally posting ads
公园通过张贴广告进行表演
on Facebook Marketplace, free ads,
在 Facebook Marketplace 上，免费广告
making a free website with a vibe coding
使用 Vibe Code 制作免费网站
app and um and increasing the occupancy.
应用程序和嗯，以及提高入住率。
And that $20,000 a year goes to $30,000
而那份每年2万美元的收入将增加到3万美元。
a year and the park is worth an 8% cap
一年后，公园的价值将达到上限的 8%。
rate. You bought it undervalued at 10%.
速度。你以10%的折扣买入了它。
So it's now at $3, I don't know, $60,000
所以现在价格是3美元，我不知道，也可能是6万美元。
park that you paid $200,000 for. So you
你花了20万美元买下的公园。所以你
can either sell it or you can just
你可以把它卖掉，或者你也可以……
manage it um and enjoy the profits.
好好管理，享受利润吧。
&gt;&gt; When you said seller financing, what
您说的卖方融资是指什么？
what does that mean?
这意味着什么？
&gt;&gt; That means the seller is holding the
这意味着卖方持有
note. They are bearing the risk of you
笔记。他们承担着你的风险。
buying the park, but what's in it for
买下这座公园，但这样做有什么好处呢？
them is a they can get the park back if
如果他们能够重新获得公园的控制权，
you default.
你默认。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, they're not actually giving
好的。所以，他们实际上并没有给予。
you the park up front. They're letting
前面就是公园。他们允许
you have it today on the basis that
你今天拥有它，是基于以下前提：
you'll pay them in the future with
你将来会用这些钱来偿还他们。
profits you make.
你获得的利润。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. So, you're making monthly
确切地。所以，你每月收入……
payments to them. Um because often times
向他们支付款项。嗯，因为很多时候
they're going to take that money that
他们会拿走那笔钱。
you give them and they're going to have
你给他们，他们就会有
to invest it in something else,
把它投资到其他方面。
something they don't understand. So,
这是他们不理解的事情。所以，
your pitch to them is, "Hey, you know
你向他们推销的方案是：“嘿，你知道
this park better than anyone, right? you
这个公园比任何公园都好，对吧？你
know what I can do to fix it. You know
我知道该如何解决这个问题。你知道
what the deficiencies are. If for some
有哪些不足之处？如果对于某些
reason I'm not who I say I am, you just
你就是那个不属于我所声称的那个人的原因。
get it back. You take it back and you
把它找回来。你把它拿回去，然后你
where you started and you keep all the
从你开始的地方开始，你保留所有的一切
money that I've paid you some so far.
我之前付给你的一些钱。
&gt;&gt; How much money have you made from doing
你通过做这件事赚了多少钱？
this?
这？
&gt;&gt; I've made net profit
我实现了净利润
probably 4 to $600,000
大概40万到60万美元
&gt;&gt; revenue.
收入。
&gt;&gt; I would say between 3 and 4 million a
我估计在300万到400万之间。
year
年
&gt;&gt; with these RV parks
这些房车公园
&gt;&gt; and mobile home parks as well. Yeah. How
以及移动房屋园区。是的。如何
many of them?
他们当中有很多吗？
&gt;&gt; I've been involved with 35 or so over
我参与过大约35个项目。
the last seven years.
过去七年。
&gt;&gt; What a bad business.
真是糟糕的生意。
&gt;&gt; No, I mean, you're capitalizing on baby
不，我的意思是，你是在利用婴儿这个概念赚钱。
boomers retiring and on millennials
婴儿潮一代退休以及千禧一代
traveling and on Yeah, it's just it's a
旅行，还有，是的，就是这样
growing market. People are getting
市场正在增长。人们正在获得
outside more.
更多外出活动。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. What What are the macro things you
是的。宏观层面上，你指的是什么？
you think about at the moment when
你此刻在想什么？
you're trying to decide on a new side
你正试图选择一个新的阵营
hustle or a new business to start? Are
是想找份兼职，还是想创办一家新公司？是
there like obvious macro things that
有一些显而易见的宏观事物
happening that we should all be thinking
一件值得我们所有人思考的事情
about? you just can't ignore AI. Like
关于？你不能忽视人工智能。喜欢
whatever you're doing, AI has to be part
无论你做什么，人工智能都必须参与其中。
of it. So I like the the framework of
它的。所以我喜欢这个框架。
implementing new AI tools into old
将新的人工智能工具集成到旧系统中
businesses. And I like the framework
企业。我喜欢这个框架。
that 10,000 um baby boomers are retiring
大约有1万名婴儿潮一代即将退休
every single day and that will be the
每天都是如此，那将是
case for the next 5 to 10 years. What's
未来5到10年的情况。是什么
the opportunity there
那里的机会
&gt;&gt; to either buy the businesses or to
要么收购这些企业，要么
implement AI into the businesses? Um
将人工智能应用于企业？嗯
those are the two biggest opportunities
这是两大最大机遇。
I see. That's true.
我懂了。这是真的。
&gt;&gt; Get them to give you the business. So,
让他们把生意交给你。所以，
and you run it better in a more digital
而且在更数字化的环境下运行效果更好。
way.
方式。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And you pay them off for that
是的。然后你付钱给他们。
business when you've made profit from
当你从业务中获利时
it. If you don't make the profit, they
它。如果你不盈利，他们
get their business back.
让他们重新光顾。
&gt;&gt; Yes. Now, I will say finding seller
是的。现在，我要说的是寻找卖家
financing on a business is harder than
企业融资比……更难
on a piece of real estate. Um, but it is
在一块房地产上。嗯，但是是
possible.
可能的。
&gt;&gt; Of all the businesses you you've
在你所有的企业中，你已经
started, which one has been most
开始之后，哪一个最受欢迎
profitable?
有利可图？
&gt;&gt; And was the easiest?
最容易吗？
&gt;&gt; Oh, man. So, like what is the winner?
哦，天哪。那么，谁是赢家呢？
&gt;&gt; I would say either um [clears throat] my
我会说要么嗯[清嗓子]我的
RV parks business or my my Texas snacks
房车公园生意或我的德州零食
business, my e-commerce business. Um and
我的生意，我的电子商务生意。嗯，还有
they weren't easy because they're easy
它们之所以容易，并非因为它们容易。
businesses or industry industries.
企业或行业。
They're easy because I had matured
它们很容易，因为我已经成熟了。
enough to a point to find
足够多，可以找到
good operators to run those businesses
优秀的经营者才能成功运营这些企业
where I had little to no involvement in
我几乎没有参与其中
them. Does that make sense?
他们。这样说得通吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You found people to run them for
是的。你找到了人来运营它们。
you so that as a starter they didn't die
这样，作为开局，他们就不会死了
the minute you got bored.
你感到无聊的那一刻。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. Whereas
确切地。然而
&gt;&gt; they carried on growing and evolving.
它们不断发展壮大。
&gt;&gt; Right. Whereas those are both quite hard
正确的。然而，这两者都相当困难。
industries. E-commerce is quite hard and
行业。电子商务相当困难，
uh and real estate is as well. But I had
嗯，房地产也是如此。但我曾
good operators.
优秀的运营商。
&gt;&gt; What have you learned about finding good
你从寻找好东西中学到了什么？
operators?
操作员？
H.
H.
Oh man,
我的天哪，
it all comes down to
归根结底，一切都取决于
trust. How much trust am I able to put
相信。我究竟能给予多少信任？
in them? How much trust do I have them?
它们里面有吗？我对他们有多信任？
I've found a um a direct correlation
我发现了一种直接的相关性。
between people I know really well um and
在我非常熟悉的人之间，嗯……
people that have made really good
那些真正优秀的人
operators.
操作员。
&gt;&gt; How do you incentivize them?
如何激励他们？
&gt;&gt; Directly from the profits of the
直接从利润中
business
商业
&gt;&gt; so that they feel more like a
这样他们就会感觉自己更像一个
entrepreneur. they've got more of a of a
企业家。他们拥有更多……
piece of the pie.
分一杯羹。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I made the mistake in my 20s of
是的，我二十多岁的时候犯过这个错误。
dangling a carrot of equity too often.
过于频繁地用股权作为诱饵。
Genuinely meaning it like but it most
真心实意地喜欢它，但它最
equity goes to zero period. Um I put a
权益归零。嗯，我放了一个
lot more emphasis on cash flow now in my
现在我更加重视现金流了。
30s than I do on equity. I think equity
30岁以上的人在股权方面比我做得更好。我认为公平
is overrated. And so nowadays, I'm less
被高估了。所以现在，我没那么……
likely to give an operating partner
可能会给运营合伙人
equity, not because I don't think they
公平，并非因为我认为他们不公平
deserve it, but because it's more likely
理应如此，但更有可能的是
to go to zero, and I'm more likely to
归零，我更有可能
cut them in on the profits so they can
让他们分得利润，这样他们就可以
get paid ongoing
持续获得报酬
&gt;&gt; on an annual basis or quarterly basis,
按年或按季度计算，
etc.
ETC。
&gt;&gt; Quarterly. Yeah.
季刊。是的。
&gt;&gt; Interesting. H [clears throat] is there
有趣的。 H（清了清嗓子）在吗？
any side hustles that you've heard about
你听说过的任何副业
that you wish you'd started?
你是否后悔当初没有开始？
&gt;&gt; It's funny because a lot of the ones
这很有趣，因为很多
that I wish I started, I started. Like a
我希望我当初就开始了，但我已经开始了。就像
lot of the 80 that I've done, I just
我做的80多部作品中，很多都是这样。
it's something that I thought about for
这是我思考过的事情
2 weeks. I can't get it out of my head.
两周。我一直忘不了这件事。
And I just I have to get it out of my
我必须把它从我的……中解脱出来
head. And so if I start something and it
头。所以如果我开始做某件事，而它
fails,
失败，
I don't really care because I don't
我并不在意，因为我并不
invest a lot of money into it. And I
投入大量资金。我
answered the question. I don't have to
回答了这个问题。我不必
like stay up at night wondering if that
就像晚上睡不着觉，想着是不是那样
thing would have worked anymore.
这东西已经不再管用了。
Sometimes I'll like run these tests on
有时我会运行这些测试
Facebook that show me such amazing
Facebook 向我展示了如此惊人的景象
results that just kind of unlock an
结果就像是开启了某种……
opportunity for me. Can I give you an
对我来说是个机会。我可以给你一个
analogy?
类比？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Have you ever been deep sea fishing? Uh,
你曾经进行过深海捕鱼吗？呃，
not deep sea fishing. No.
不是深海捕鱼。不。
&gt;&gt; Okay, so here's a real story. I was out
好吧，下面是一个真实的故事。我当时不在。
deep deep sea fishing and we were just
深海捕鱼，我们当时就在
throwing lures and we weren't getting
我们抛掷鱼饵，但一直没钓到鱼。
any any uh bites and the captain reaches
任何任何呃咬，船长都伸手去拿
in under the seat and he pulls out
他把东西从座位底下抽了出来。
straws from McDonald's, McDonald's
麦当劳的吸管，麦当劳
straws specifically because they have
吸管，尤其是因为它们有
red and yellow stripes along the side of
侧面有红色和黄色条纹
them and he pulled out scissors and he
他掏出剪刀，然后……
started cutting them into fourths. And
开始将它们切成四份。和
then he he took the hook off the line
然后他把鱼钩从鱼线上取了下来。
and he he put the string through the
他把绳子穿过了
straw and then he tied the hook back on.
然后他用稻草把钩子绑了回去。
He's like, "I know, seems crazy. Just
他就像在说：“我知道，这听起来很疯狂。只是
stick with me." And we casted it out and
“跟着我。”于是我们把它赶走了。
we started getting bites. And I'm like,
我们开始被咬了。我当时就想，
"What is it was the same place with the
“如果那是同一个地方的话……”
same lure, same hook with just a straw."
同样的鱼饵，同样的鱼钩，只不过换成了一根吸管。
And I'm like, "What? Why does this
我当时就想，“什么？为什么会这样？”
work?" And he's like, "It's the colors.
是工作吗？”他回答说：“是颜色。”
It's like the white and the red and and
就像白色和红色，还有
it just spins as you reel it in and it
当你收线的时候，它就会旋转，而且
it mimics a fish." And I was like, "How
它模仿鱼的动作。” 我当时就想，“怎么会这样？”
did you learn this? Like what made you
你学到这个了吗？是什么造就了你
think to try this?" He's like, "I don't
你觉得试试这个怎么样？”他回答说：“我不这么认为。”
know. Uh maybe alcohol was involved. I
知道。呃，或许跟酒精有关。我
don't know." But like that worked and we
不知道。”但好像那样就奏效了，我们
started catching fish the rest of the
剩下的时间里，我开始捕鱼。
day. So it just got me thinking like
天。所以这让我开始思考……
entrepreneurship is this massive ocean
创业精神就像一片浩瀚的海洋。
with millions of varieties of fish,
拥有数百万种鱼类，
billions of fish, some sharks, some
数十亿条鱼，一些鲨鱼，一些
minnows. And so many of us go out there
小鱼。我们很多人都会去那里。
and we cast a few times and we just go
我们试了几次，然后就走了。
back home. We're like, "Entreneurship
回家了。我们就像是“创业精神”。
doesn't work. It's not for me. Back to
行不通。这不适合我。返回
the 9 to5." But we're not testing enough
朝九晚五。”但我们的检测量还不够。
stuff. There's different depths. There's
东西。深度各不相同。有
different baits. We could spray
不同的饵料。我们可以喷洒
something on it to make it smell
在上面放点东西，让它有香味
different. We could put a McDonald's
不同的。我们可以开一家麦当劳
straw on it. And occasionally we'll find
上面铺着稻草。偶尔我们会发现
something. We'll get a bite. And maybe
某物。我们去吃点东西。或许
we won't get another bite for another
我们再也吃不到一口了
hour, but the bite is a signal. And it's
虽然时间不长，但咬人是一个信号。而且是
like, oh, there's something there. Okay,
就像，哦，那里有什么东西。好的，
let's try that again, but try this. Or
我们再试一次，但这次试试这个。或者
maybe let's just cast a 100 more times.
或许我们可以再尝试100次。
And then you get a fish. And then you
然后你就得到了一条鱼。然后你
get a bigger fish. And like the more
换条更大的鱼。而且更喜欢
you're out there, not just focusing on
你身处其中，不仅仅关注……
one type of fishing, but increasing your
一种钓鱼方式，但增加你的
surface area and trying all kinds of
表面积和尝试各种
different things, the more you learn.
学得越多，就会发现不同的东西。
Like the more you you test and like now
你测试得越多，就越喜欢现在的样子。
you have a bunch of sharks in the boat
船上有一群鲨鱼
and you have this and you have this and
你有这个，你还有这个
you have all these options at your
您拥有所有这些选择
disposal. We're eating shark tonight.
处理。我们今晚吃鲨鱼肉。
We're eating grouper. We're eating
我们在吃石斑鱼。我们正在吃饭
snapper. You have this amazing life
鲷鱼。你拥有如此精彩的人生
that's dynamic and full of color and all
它充满活力，色彩缤纷，等等
these other awesome things are coming
其他一些很棒的事情即将到来
into play because you stayed out there
因为你一直待在那里，所以才得以发挥作用。
and you didn't just do one thing, you
而且你做的不止一件事，你
tried all these other things. So that's
其他方法我都试过了。就是这样。
how I look at business. Like I'm out
我看待商业的方式。就像我出局了一样
there on the ocean testing other things
在那里，在海洋上测试其他东西
and even if I don't catch anything, it's
即使我什么都没抓到，那也是
fun. And uh I think other people should
乐趣。嗯，我觉得其他人也应该
try that too.
也试试这个方法。
A lot of people want sexy stuff, don't
很多人想要性感的东西，别这样。
they? They want to build the next
他们？他们想要建造下一代
Facebook or they want to do the a chat
他们想通过 Facebook 聊天。
GPT or the AI app that does this, that,
GPT 或能做这做那的 AI 应用
and the other. Do you think that's in
以及另一个。你认为这算数吗？
part a trap for for the average person
对普通人来说，这部分是一个陷阱
to be aiming at sexy? Yeah. Because the
目标是性感吗？是的。因为
fact that everyone wants sexy means the
每个人都想要性感，这意味着
fact that the sexy things are the most
事实上，性感的东西是最……
competitive. It's the exact reason why
竞争的。这正是原因所在。
we should go as unsexy as possible
我们应该尽可能地不性感。
because no one's looking at it.
因为没人看。
And looking forward, Chris, what is um
展望未来，克里斯，嗯……
is there anything that you're mulling
你有什么正在考虑的事情吗？
over now in terms of new business ideas
就新的商业理念而言，现在已经结束了。
that you could give me?
你能给我什么？
&gt;&gt; Man, I lately it's been about like stuff
唉，最近我一直在想这些事。
I can launch with my content. Um I like
我可以用我的内容发布。嗯，我喜欢
I love the phrase unfair advantage,
我喜欢“不公平优势”这个说法。
right? I will only start businesses
正确的？我只会创办企业。
today where I have an unfair advantage.
今天我拥有不公平的优势。
Everyone has an unfair advantage in
每个人都拥有不公平的优势
something, right? Even a a 13-year-old
算是吧？即使是13岁的孩子
has an unfair advantage. they might know
拥有不公平的优势。他们或许知道
roadblocks better than anyone, right? So
比任何人都更擅长设置障碍，对吧？所以
unfair advantage is not, you know, only
不公平优势不仅仅是，你知道，仅仅
for the rich or the wealthy or the elite
对于富人、有钱人或精英阶层而言
or the most experienced or the PhDs,
或者经验最丰富的，或者拥有博士学位的，
right? So I try to start businesses
正确的？所以我尝试创业。
where I have an unfair advantage and
我拥有不公平的优势，
that might be because I can grow it with
那可能是因为我可以用它种植它
my content. It might be because I have a
我的内容。可能是因为我有一个
bunch of friends in that space or I have
那里有一群朋友，或者我有
a unique knowledge or insight into that
对某事有独特的了解或见解
space. So if I have a zillion ideas and
空间。所以如果我有很多想法，
a spreadsheet a mile long with a bunch
一张长长的电子表格，里面有很多东西
of business ideas, the ones I'm most
在我的商业想法中，我最……
likely to start are the ones where I
最有可能开始的就是我
have an unfair advantage. a right to
拥有不公平的优势。一项权利
win.
赢。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; I have this phrase called mirage
我有一个词组叫做“海市蜃楼”。
opportunity
机会
&gt;&gt; which um which I use when I look at an
嗯，我看的时候会用到它
industry that never seems to work for
似乎永远无法奏效的行业
anybody but seems so obvious.
但任何人都可以，这似乎显而易见。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Do you know what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I do. I'm thinking of something.
是的，我有。我在想一件事。
Yeah. And I this has been a bit of a a
是的。而这对我来说有点……
way for me to know what not to work on
让我知道哪些事情不该做。
is if I see everybody trying to solve
如果我看到每个人都在试图解决
this particular problem and nobody's
这个问题，而且没有人……
been successful yet more and more people
已经成功，而且越来越多的人
are plowing in and yet it seems obvious
正在奋力耕耘，但这似乎显而易见
to me I just stay away from it
我宁愿远离它。
&gt;&gt; because there's something in my
因为我心里有东西。
understanding of consumer behavior or
对消费者行为的理解或
current alternatives that I'm like
目前我喜欢的替代方案
misunderstanding.
误解。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. An example I'll give you.
嗯。我给你举个例子。
Everyone at the moment is trying to
目前每个人都在努力
start a So this is the first the sort of
开始，所以这是第一种……
first principles they're reasoning up
他们依据第一原则进行推理
from. They're saying people are more
从。他们说人们更
lonely than ever before. They're saying
比以往任何时候都更加孤独。他们说
there's no clear place to organize a
没有明确的地方来组织
group of people. WhatsApp has its um has
一群人。 WhatsApp有它的嗯有
its limitations, its restrictions,
它的局限性，它的限制，
doesn't have the feature set one would
不具备人们想要的功能集
like. Facebook groups aren't working for
喜欢。 Facebook 群组对……不起作用
a certain generation of people anymore
某一代人已经不再是了。
for for sort of Gen Z's and younger
适用于Z世代及更年轻的人​​群
generations, millennials. So, what I'm
世代，千禧一代。所以，我……
going to do is I'm going to make an app
我打算做的就是开发一个应用程序。
for groups. Mhm. Your run club, your
适用于团体。嗯。你的跑步俱乐部，你的
friends, your piano recital group, your
朋友们，你的钢琴演奏小组，你的
your entrepreneurs. We're going to build
你们的创业者。我们将建造
all the group features into this app and
将所有群组功能整合到此应用程序中
it's going to be dedicated to that. I've
它将专门用于此。我已经
heard this pitch over and over again.
我已经听过无数遍这样的推销话术了。
I've seen all of them. None of them seem
我全都看过了。他们似乎都没有。
to have any traction or work.
没有任何效果或作用。
&gt;&gt; It's a mirage. Something fundamental
这是海市蜃楼。一些基本的东西
about your assumptions is off.
你的假设是错误的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. When I said mirage opportunities,
是的。我说的是海市蜃楼般的机遇，
did you think of anything in particular?
你有没有想到什么特别的事情？
&gt;&gt; I stay away Yeah. Just I stay away from
我尽量远离。我只是远离它
businesses where where I I don't know
我不知道哪些商家在哪。
why it's not working, but clearly it's
为什么它不起作用，但显然它就是不起作用。
not working.
无法运行。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I think of banking or healthcare,
是的。我想到了银行业或医疗保健行业。
right? Like banking is terrible. Like
正确的？银行业糟透了。喜欢
look at the UI at Bank of America. It's
看看美国银行的用户界面。它是
why is it it's like h it's probably like
为什么会这样？就像这样，可能就像这样
that for a reason, right? Or like
那肯定是有原因的，对吧？或者像
Amazon's UI is terrible. It's like what
亚马逊的用户界面太糟糕了。这就像什么
is it? It's like they probably know why
是吗？他们好像知道原因似的。
it looks like that, right? I assume
看起来是这样，对吧？我假设
they're smarter than I am. One idea that
他们比我聪明。一个想法是
I thought of is like everyone hates
我想到的是，就像每个人都讨厌的那样。
typing in their password a zillion times
他们输入密码无数次
a day. So you have like these password
一天。所以你有这样的密码
managers, but I've seen a dozen
经理们，但我见过十几个。
companies that are like going to fix the
就像要去修理……的公司
password, right? Some like replacement
密码，对吧？有些人喜欢替代
to a password and they've all failed and
密码都试过了，但都失败了。
it's probably because it's it's a really
这大概是因为它真的……
hard problem to solve and I don't want
问题很难解决，我不想解决。
to try to invest in a person that's
试图投资于这样一个人
trying to solve it cuz statistics are
试图解决这个问题，因为统计学是
not on their side. Another one that
不站在他们那边。另一个
comes to mind for me is at university
我首先想到的就是在大学里。
every entrepreneurial college kid
每个有创业精神的大学生
decides that they're going to build a
决定要建造一个
onampus what's going on app to let
onampus 发生了什么？应用程序允许
everybody know what's going on on
大家都知道发生了什么事。
campus.
校园。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And they never seem to work.
而且它们似乎从来都不起作用。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And I think the reason why they
是的。我认为他们这样做的原因是
don't work is because both you're losing
行不通是因为你们双方都在输。
33% of your potential customers every
33% 的潜在客户
year and gaining 33% new customers every
每年新增客户 33%
year. So you have a bit of an
年。所以你有点……
acquisition problem, but then also
收购问题，但同时也存在其他问题。
people don't decide what they're going
人们无法决定自己要去哪里。
to do based on some notice board. They
根据公告栏上的信息去做。他们
decide based on their dorm room friends
根据宿舍朋友的意见来决定
and where they're going and where the
以及他们要去哪里，以及……
girl they like is going.
他们喜欢的女孩要走了。
&gt;&gt; And you and so it's not really about
所以，这其实与你无关。
what's going on. It's like what does my
这是怎么回事。这就像我的……
group of people want to do. I think
一群人想做这件事。我认为
that's I think that's the mirage in
我想那就是海市蜃楼吧。
that. Well, I thought of another example
那。我又想到了一个例子。
that's like building apps around
这就像围绕着构建应用程序一样
podcasting.
播客。
&gt;&gt; Oh my god. Yeah. Right. Yeah. Yeah.
我的天啊。是的。正确的。是的。是的。
&gt;&gt; I have a friend that he had a podcast.
我有个朋友，他做过播客。
&gt;&gt; It's a great one.
这是个很棒的例子。
&gt;&gt; That helped podcasters, right? And it
那对播客主播们有帮助，对吧？而且它
was great. Like really I listen to it
很棒。我真的会听。
and he he realized over time like I'm
随着时间的推移，他逐渐意识到，就像我一样
selling to a market that quits, right?
对吧？你卖的东西市场会随时退出市场。
I'm asking for customers to pay for my
我要求顾客为我的东西付费。
thing that are statistically like 95% of
统计上类似于95%的事物
them are going to quit within 6 months.
他们将在6个月内辞职。
So it's just a broken market to sell to.
所以，这是一个根本无法有效销售的市场。
And then the 5% that are successful,
然后，还有那5%的成功者，
what percentage of them are actually
其中实际占多少百分比
profitable? What percentage of them can
有利可图？他们中有多少百分比可以
afford to pay for an expensive agency or
有能力支付昂贵的代理费用吗？
software? Very few
软件？极少
mirage opportunities. I like that. I I
海市蜃楼般的机遇。我喜欢这个。我 我
would Yeah, it's a it's been a really
是的，这确实是一个……
useful framework because it's the
有用的框架，因为它是
obvious ones that no one's doing, but
那些显而易见却没人做的事，但是……
there's clearly a huge opportunity that
显然存在着巨大的机遇，
I think pulls people in the most. But
我认为这是最吸引人的地方。但
for me now with the with the amount of
对我来说，现在的数量是
time I've spent starting businesses,
我花在创业上的时间，
those are the ones that push me away the
正是这些人让我疏远他们。
most.
最多。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, it all comes back to the
是的。嗯，这一切最终都归结于……
value of just copying what's already
仅仅复制现有内容的价值
working.
在职的。
&gt;&gt; Amen. Is there anything we haven't
阿门。还有什么我们没考虑到的吗？
talked about that we should have talked
谈到我们应该谈谈
about, Chris? For young and old people
克里斯，你在说什么？对于年轻人和老年人
that are considering starting their own
正在考虑创业的人
business, their own side hustle,
生意，他们自己的副业，
building passive income.
打造被动收入。
Many of the people that think they want
许多自认为想要的人
to be an entrepreneur, they just like
他们喜欢成为企业家。
the idea of it and they think there's
他们有这个想法，而且他们认为有
freedom in entrepreneurship when
创业自由
oftentimes it's even more of a prison
很多时候，它甚至更像是一座监狱。
than their 9 to5. [laughter]
比朝九晚五的工作时间要好得多。 [笑声]
&gt;&gt; It can be at least in the first years,
至少在最初几年可能是这样的。
not months, not years, sometimes
不是几个月，也不是几年，有时
decades, right? And so I want people to
几十年了，对吧？所以我希望人们
answer the question for themselves. Is
请自行回答这个问题。是
this for me? So they don't regret.
这对我来说？所以他们不后悔。
They need to find out if they love the
他们需要弄清楚自己是否爱……
idea of it or they like the actual
他们喜欢这个想法，或者他们喜欢实际的
day-to-day grind of it. um because they
日复一日的重复劳动。嗯，因为他们
they probably won't, but I want them to
他们可能不会，但我希望他们这样做。
find out.
查出。
&gt;&gt; Such an important point because the
这一点非常重要，因为
narrative online at the moment is, you
目前网上流传的说法是，你
know, be your own boss, etc., etc. And I
我知道，要自己当老板等等。而我
I just I don't think people I'm speaking
我只是觉得，我跟人们说话的方式不太一样。
for myself here. I don't want to speak
就我个人而言。我不想说话
for you, but I don't think people
对你来说是这样，但我认为人们不会这样。
realize how many people I have to answer
意识到我得回答多少人的问题
to.
到。
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
&gt;&gt; I have all of my team members, which is
我拥有我的所有团队成员，他们是：
hundreds of people. Then I have my
数百人。然后我还有我的
investors. I have my suppliers, my
投资者。我有我的供应商，我的
clients. So, it's not like I'm living as
客户。所以，我并不是过着这样的生活：
a free man.
一个自由人。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I'm less free now than I was
是的。我现在不如以前自由了。
before.
前。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; When I started all this stuff,
当我开始做这一切的时候，
&gt;&gt; isn't it nice when someone just also
当有人也这样做的时候，难道不是一件很美好的事吗？
just tells you what to do and exactly
它会告诉你该怎么做，而且是确切地告诉你。
what path to take?
我该走哪条路？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Like my wife does that. She's like,
就像我妻子那样。她就像是，
"Hey, I need you to do this." It's like,
“嘿，我需要你做这件事。”就像，
"Oh, it's so nice. I don't have to like
“哦，真好。我不必喜欢。”
think like thank you." You know, so I
想想“谢谢”之类的话。你知道，所以我
have bosses in other areas of my life
我生活中其他领域也有老板。
and it's really nice. Like there's
真的很不错。就像有……
something to be said for a 9 to5. And
朝九晚五也有它的好处。和
some people have no desire to even test
有些人甚至连测试的意愿都没有。
an entrepreneurship. Great. All power to
创业精神。伟大的。所有权力
you, but I want people to test it. And I
你，但我希望人们来测试它。我
think, you know, people would look at
想想，你知道，人们会看
someone like me or you and think, oh,
像你我这样的人会想，哦，
you know, they've got total freedom. But
你知道，他们拥有完全的自由。但
this is just not the case. Even for me
事实并非如此。即使对我来说也是如此
as a podcaster, you know, I'm now kind
作为一名播客主播，你知道，我现在很友善
of somewhat
有点
constrained by the fact that I need to
受限于我需要……这一事实
publish on a Monday and I need to
周一发布，我需要
publish on a Thursday and that means
周四发布，这意味着
lots of other work takes place
还有许多其他工作要做。
throughout the week and
整周和
&gt;&gt; um I can't just go to Hawaii and chill
嗯，我不可能就这么去夏威夷放松一下。
out and spend a month off and then I've
出去休息一个月，然后我就……
got all my clients now and the team
现在我的所有客户和团队都到位了。
members, etc. So, I'm I'm I think I'm
成员等等。所以，我，我，我想我是
starting a bit of a war against this
开始与此展开一场小小的战争
idea that
想法
&gt;&gt; independence and total freedom.
独立和完全自由。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Is both something to aim for but also
既是努力的目标，也是
like realistic
逼真
&gt;&gt; when you're pursuing something you love.
当你追求自己热爱的事物时。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; I think a generation have been sold this
我认为一代人都被灌输了这种观念。
idea of independence. And I don't think
独立思想。而且我不认为
it's gotten us anywhere. Yeah.
它带我们去任何地方。是的。
&gt;&gt; Like that. That's the goal. Freedom,
就是这样。这就是目标。自由，
independence. Don't depend on anybody.
独立。不要依赖任何人。
&gt;&gt; Right. But when I look on your your
正确的。但是当我看着你的……
life, you've got four kids, you've got
生活就是这样，你有四个孩子，你有
lots of responsibility, you've got
你肩负着很多责任。
employees, you've got businesses, you've
员工，你们有企业，你们有
got so much dependency
产生了太多的依赖性
and that's probably the source of much
而这很可能就是很多问题的根源。
of your happiness.
你的幸福。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, exactly. My quote of this year is
对，没错。我今年的座右铭是：
there are no solutions, only trade-offs.
没有完美的解决方案，只有权衡取舍。
&gt;&gt; Entrepreneurship is not a solution.
创业并非解决之道。
You're trading something for it. The
你是用其他东西交换的。这
question is, is that trade-off worth it
问题是，这种权衡是否值得？
or not? And we won't know until we try
或不？不试怎么知道呢？
it.
它。
&gt;&gt; And what's the trade-off you're making?
你做出的权衡是什么？
stability, um, lack of volatility. Um,
稳定性，嗯，缺乏波动性。嗯，
yeah, predictability. My life has been
是啊，可预测性。我的人生一直如此
volatile and unpredictable. Um, but the
波动剧烈且难以预测。嗯，但是
more I do it, the more predictable it
我做得越多，结果就越可预测。
becomes in a good way. Uh, but that's
情况好转了。呃，但是那是
been the trade-off is the mental load of
权衡之下，需要付出的代价是精神负担。
not knowing where my paycheck's coming
不知道我的工资从哪里来。
from or if it's coming at all.
究竟会不会有消息。
&gt;&gt; It's not for the faint-hearted.
胆小者勿入。
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
Chris, we have a closing tradition where
克里斯，我们有个结束仪式的传统，
the last guest leaves a question for the
最后一位客人留下了一个问题。
next not knowing who they're leaving it
接下来，他们不知道自己会把东西留给谁。
for. And the question left for you, I
为了。而留给你们的问题，我
love this question for obvious reasons,
我喜欢这个问题，原因显而易见。
is during your interview with Steven
是在你和史蒂文的访谈期间。
today, what is one thing he did that you
今天，他做的一件事是什么？
genuinely appreciated.
衷心感谢。
I would say that I
我会说我
I appreciate that the questions you
我很感激你提出的问题。
asked me got me to look at the things
问我，让我看看这些东西。
I've been looking at in one way
我一直在从某种角度看待这个问题。
completely differently. I came into this
完全不同。我进入了这个领域
conversation,
对话，
you know, looking at things in a
你知道，从某种角度看待事物
specific way in in ways that I always
以我总是特有的方式
have, but your questions got me to
有，但你的问题让我……
approach it from a different angle. um
换个角度来看。嗯
that made me learn something more about
这让我对……有了更深入的了解。
my own story, if you will.
如果可以的话，这算是我自己的故事吧。
&gt;&gt; And what was that in particular? Was
具体来说，那是什么？曾是
there a specific thing you're you're
有一件特定的事情，你是
thinking about?
在想什么？
&gt;&gt; Maybe just the overall framework that
或许只是整体框架而已
maybe it's just recency biased, but
也许只是近因效应，但是
just that it's it's not for everyone.
只是它并不适合所有人。
It's not for everyone. Um, and that we
它并不适合所有人。嗯，还有我们
just need to learn if the trade-offs are
只需要了解这些权衡取舍是否合理。
worth it.
值得。
&gt;&gt; There's an element of your personal
这其中包含你个人的因素。
trauma, experiences, upbringing,
创伤、经历、成长环境
insecurities, toxic fuel that makes the
不安全感，是造成这种状况的有害因素。
trade-offs worth it makes you in some
值得的权衡会让你陷入某种境地
respect unreasonable,
尊重是不合理的，
&gt;&gt; unrealistic, willing to take the risk.
不切实际，但愿意承担风险。
And we don't talk about that enough
我们在这方面讨论得还不够。
because we're not able to go into
因为我们无法进入
people's trauma and the nuance of their
人们的创伤及其细微差别
life and childhood and what their dad
生活、童年以及他们的父亲
said to them and what the how they were
对他们说了些什么，以及他们当时的情况。
bullied
被欺凌
&gt;&gt; to be able to like
能够喜欢
trans transmit into their mind to make
跨性别者将信息传递到他们的脑海中，从而产生
that to figure that out for themselves.
让他们自己去弄清楚。
But I think probably is in both your
但我认为可能你们俩都有这种感觉。
life and my life. I mean you we both I
生活和我的生活。我的意思是，你我俩我
think have ADHD to some degree and we
我认为自己有一定程度的注意力缺陷多动症，而且我们
have a brainwire in a certain way. So
在某些方面，他们的大脑构造是这样的。所以
it's not it can seem like we're making a
并非如此，看起来好像我们正在制造一个
choice but I it often doesn't feel like
选择，但我常常感觉不到。
that for me.
对我来说就是这样。
&gt;&gt; Doesn't feel like I'm making a choice.
感觉自己好像没有做出选择。
It feels like there is no other choice.
感觉好像别无选择。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; In the same way that one might make a
就像人们可能会做出……
choice to get a 9 toive job.
选择获得一份9到9岁的工作。
&gt;&gt; I have I I I think for me that would be
我有，我想对我来说那会是
a terrible thing.
一件糟糕的事。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And vice versa probably.
反之亦然。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, what you just said just
是的。嗯，你刚才说的那些话……
brought up a memory. I don't know if
勾起了一段回忆。我不知道是否
it's relevant to this or not, but you
这跟这件事有关也好，无关也罢，但你
said ADHD. When I was in undergrad, I
患有注意力缺陷多动症。我读本科的时候，
got tested for ADHD. And the
接受了多动症测试。以及
psychiatrist said, um, it was a big
精神科医生说，嗯，这很严重
report. I'm summarizing it to the only
报告。我只概括到最基本的部分。
sentence that I remember, but she said
我记得她说过一句话，但她说
that I just had delusions of grandeur,
我当时只是妄自尊大罢了。
right? Uh, it wasn't like an official
正确的？呃，这不像是一个官方的
diagnosis. It was one line in like an
诊断。那就像一行字
eight-page document, but I saw that just
一份八页的文件，但我只看到了这一点
like bounce off the page and I was like,
就像从纸上弹开一样，我当时就想，
how do you know that's a delusion?
你怎么知道那是妄想？
Right? Like it's only a delusion if
正确的？如果这只是一种错觉的话
enough time has passed so we could look
时间已经过去足够长了，我们可以看看
back and say, "Yeah, he was wrong. He
回去说：“是啊，他错了。”
was way off base."
完全错误。
&gt;&gt; By delusions of grandeur, what does she
她妄自尊大，究竟做了什么？
mean?
意思是？
&gt;&gt; She means like I had unrealist
她的意思是，就像我曾经那么不切实际
unrealistic expectations about how my
对我的期望不切实际
life would turn out. Um, and that that
生活总会好起来的。嗯，还有那个
was causing strife in my personal
这给我的个人生活带来了纷争。
relationships.
人际关系。
And I thought it was wrong. I still
我觉得这样做不对。我仍然
think it was wrong. But it it put a chip
我认为这样做是错误的。但它却植入了芯片
on my shoulder. It planted a seed that I
在我的肩膀上。它在我心中埋下了一颗种子。
never forgot. I have that printed. It's
永生难忘。我已经打印出来了。它是
in my my drawer at work. Um,
在我办公室的抽屉里。嗯，
&gt;&gt; what does he say?
他说了什么？
&gt;&gt; Just I just have like literally the
我简直就是……
report that she gave me back in 2009.
她在 2009 年给我的报告。
Uh, it's like highlighted and drawn up
呃，就像是高亮显示并绘制出来一样。
in in my in my drawer at work and I just
在我的抽屉里，我在上班的时候就放在抽屉里。
look at it sometimes for motivation
偶尔看看它，从中汲取动力。
because what what is a delusion of
因为什么是妄想？
grandeur? Like I have plans of grandeur.
宏伟？我仿佛胸怀宏伟的计划。
This is a plan. Um, and so I think about
这是一个计划。嗯，所以我在想……
her sometimes. She probably has no idea
她有时。她可能完全不知道
who I am. She probably forgot all about
我是谁。她可能完全忘记了这件事。
me. Uh
我。呃
&gt;&gt; if people want to learn more, where's
如果人们想了解更多，应该去哪里找？
the best place they should go to to
他们应该去的最佳地点
check your work out? You've got your
检查一下你的作品？你已经拥有了你的
podcast on YouTube.
在 YouTube 上发布播客。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Um it's not necessarily a podcast in the
嗯，它不一定是播客。
same way that this is a podcast. It's
就像这是一个播客一样。它是
much more sort of practical and specific
更实用、更具体
around specific subject matter. So I
围绕特定主题。所以，我
highly recommend people go check that
强烈建议大家去看看。
out. I'm going to link it below and put
出去。我会在下方附上链接并添加
it on the screen. But where else?
屏幕上会显示出来。还能去哪儿呢？
Where's a good place to get in touch
哪里可以联系到他们
with you or to consume your work?
和你一起还是来欣赏你的作品？
&gt;&gt; Probably tkopod.com
可能是 tkopod.com
as in
如
&gt;&gt; tkopod.com. The kerner office. It's just
tkopod.com。科纳办公室。只是
like my main website.
就像我的主网站一样。
&gt;&gt; And people can sign up here for your
人们可以在这里注册参加你的活动。
newsletter.
通讯。
&gt;&gt; A newsletter. Yep.
简报。是的。
&gt;&gt; One email per week.
每周一封邮件。
&gt;&gt; What do you send out?
你们寄送什么？
&gt;&gt; Like a very tactical guide on how to
就像一份非常实用的战术指南，教你如何……
start X, Y, or Z business. And I ask my
创办 X、Y 或 Z 企业。我问我
audience like what they want to learn
观众喜欢他们想学的东西
about. So they tell me and then I dive
关于。他们告诉我之后，我就潜入水中。
deep and then break it all down for
深入挖掘，然后将其全部分解。
them. I'll link that as well below for
他们。我也会在下面附上链接。
anyone that's interested. What is the
任何感兴趣的人。什么是
most popular, most frequent request you
最受欢迎、最频繁的请求
get through that website
浏览那个网站
&gt;&gt; on business ideas to talk about? Yeah,
有什么商业想法可以讨论吗？是的，
&gt;&gt; probably the AI agency, the AI
可能是人工智能机构，人工智能
implementation agency idea that I talked
我之前谈到的执行机构的想法。
about.
关于。
&gt;&gt; And what is the most viral video you've
你最火的视频是什么？
ever made?
曾经制作过吗？
&gt;&gt; Oh man, that was about a um just this
哦，天哪，那大概就是……
Chinese street vendor that sold ice
卖冰块的中国街头小贩
cream. She had this little uh
奶油。她有个小小的呃
contraption. It was like a frozen
装置。就像冰冻的
cylinder that she poured cream over and
她把奶油倒在圆柱体上，
it would scrape off ice cream in this
它会把冰淇淋刮下来。
really visually appealing way. And so I
非常赏心悦目的方式。所以，我
I basically broke down in 30 seconds
我基本上在30秒内崩溃了。
like you could pay $200 for this, you
就像你可以花200美元买这个一样，你
could post it at any given street corner
可以把它张贴在任何一个街角。
and you could make $1,000 by the end of
这样到年底你就能赚到1000美元。
the day. So it's like A B C here's how
那天。所以就像ABC一样，方法如下
to get to this revenue. Um and like 30
达到这个收入目标。嗯，还有30
or 40 million people saw it.
或者说有4000万人看过。
&gt;&gt; I'll put the uh the video on the screen
我会把视频放到屏幕上。
for anyone that's interested in that as
对于任何对此感兴趣的人来说
well, just so you know what this ice
嗯，只是想让你知道这冰是什么。
cream contraption is.
乳霜装置是。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Chris, thank you so much.
克里斯，非常感谢你。
&gt;&gt; Thank you so much for for being yourself
非常感谢你做你自己。
in every respect. You teach me that
各方面都是如此。你教我这个
there's many ways to skin a cat. As the
条条大路通罗马。作为
saying goes, there's many ways to become
俗话说，成名之路有很多条。
successful, to be happy, to be motivated
成功、快乐、有动力
in your life. There's many ways to
在你的生活中。有很多方法
become a millionaire. Some of it bucks
成为百万富翁。其中一些是叛逆的
sort of conventional wisdom of how to
某种关于如何做的传统智慧
grow a business. I think that is
发展业务。我认为那是
actually liberating to know that your
实际上，知道这一点会让你感到解脱。
own unique wiring and your own unique
您独有的布线和您独有的
perspective and a guy can drive you to
视角和一个人可以带你走向
the same outcome of financial freedom if
如果结果相同，也能实现财务自由。
you do have the self-awareness, if
你的确具备自我意识，如果
you're willing to work hard and if you
你愿意努力工作，如果你
can cope with the opinions of others.
能够接受他人的意见。
Um, and also if you're willing to
嗯，还有，如果你愿意的话
sacrifice tremendously, because you have
做出巨大的牺牲，因为你有
sacrificed tremendously, and especially
做出了巨大的牺牲，尤其
as someone as a man that has a young man
作为一个拥有年轻伴侣的男人
that has four kids, you've taken on your
你已经承担起照顾四个孩子的责任了。
shoulders a huge amount of risk. And I
承担着巨大的风险。我
applaud you for both simplifying and
赞赏你简化和
demystifying the pursuit of side hustles
揭开副业的神秘面纱
and business and entrepreneurship for so
以及商业和创业
many people because I think um, in the
很多人，因为我觉得，嗯，在
world we live in, it's probably going to
我们生活的世界，很可能会……
become more and more important that
变得越来越重要
people have more options. Agreed. um in
人们有了更多选择。同意。嗯，在
a world of AI and if Elon Musk is to be
人工智能的世界，以及埃隆·马斯克如果要成为人工智能时代的代表，
successful in creating the age of
成功创造了时代
abundance that he's describing, then uh
他所描述的那种富足，然后……
maybe we're all going to end up as
或许我们最终都会变成这样
entrepreneurs. Who knows? Who knows?
企业家。谁知道呢？谁知道呢？
Thanks. Thank you. Thank you as well.
谢谢。谢谢。也谢谢你。
[music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Make sure you keep what I'm about to say
请务必记住我接下来要说的话。
to yourself. I'm inviting 10,000 of you
对自己说。我邀请你们中的10000人。
to come even deeper into the D of a CEO.
更深入地了解CEO的D。
Welcome to my inner circle. This is a
欢迎来到我的核心圈子。这是
brand new private community that I'm
我所在的这个全新的私人社区
launching to the world. We have so many
面向全球发布。我们有太多了
incredible things that happen that you
发生的那些不可思议的事情
are never shown. We have the briefs that
从未展示过。我们有以下简报：
are on my iPad when I'm recording the
录音时，我的iPad上都有这些内容。
conversation. We have clips we've never
对话。我们有一些从未播放过的片段
released. We have behind the scenes
已发布。我们有幕后花絮
conversations with the guest and also
与客人的对话以及
the episodes that we've never ever
我们从未见过的那些剧集
released. And so much more. In the
已发布。还有更多。在
circle, you'll have direct access to me.
圈内人可以直接联系到我。
You can tell us what you want this show
你可以告诉我们你希望这个节目呈现什么内容
to be, who you want us to interview, and
你想让我们采访谁？
the types of conversations you would
你会进行的对话类型
love us to have. But remember, for now,
爱我们拥有。但请记住，就目前而言，
we're only inviting the first 10,000
我们只邀请前10000名。
people that join before it closes. So,
在截止日期前加入的人。所以，
if you want to join our private closed
如果你想加入我们的私人封闭式组织
community, head to the link in the
社区中，请点击链接。
description below or go to
下方有详细说明，或前往
daccircle.com.
daccircle.com。
I will speak to you then.
到时候我再跟你谈。
[music]
[音乐]
Heat. Heat.
热。热。
[singing]
[歌唱]